<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io/</link>
		<id>M2VOGh7iVhJRnKD2dXq2K</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun Jun 21 2020 10:38:17 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Watched George Floyd Protests in 15 Cities Using Aerial Surveillance</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From Minneapolis to Buffalo, Homeland Security officials dispatched drones, helicopters and airplanes to monitor Black Lives Matter protests.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/19/us/politics/george-floyd-protests-surveillance.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air Force Investigates Military Planes That Monitored Protesters</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Air Force inspector general is examining whether secretive National Guard surveillance aircraft improperly monitored demonstrators in Washington and Minneapolis.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/18/us/politics/investigation-military-surveillance-planes-george-floyd-protests.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Arctic Records Its Hottest Temperature Ever</title>
			<source>CBS News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Reaching 100 degrees in or near the Arctic is almost unheard of.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/arctic-records-its-hottest-temperature-ever-2020-06-20/?utm_source=digg</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'America Is Not the Greatest Country in the World Anymore' - The Newsroom</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Aug 18, 2018</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From the series 'the newsroom', the beginning scene. America is not the greatest country in the world anymore.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bIpKfw17-yY</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ten Percent of U.S. High School Students Graduating Without Basic Object Permanence Skills</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 31, 2013</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new study finds that many American students do not realize that objects continue to exist even when they cannot be seen or heard.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ssjokgx0pUQ</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Believed to Be Behind Major Cyber Attack on Australian Governments and Businesses</title>
			<source>ABC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Federal Government agencies believe China is the nation behind ongoing cyber attacks on Australian institutions, including hospitals, in recent months.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-06-19/foreign-cyber-hack-targets-australian-government-and-business/12372470</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Combining Therapy With the Psychedelic Drug Psilocybin Results in Large Reductions in Anxiety and Depression</title>
			<source>PsyPost</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Psilocybin is a hallucinogenic compound found in so-called 'magic mushrooms'. A recent meta-analysis published in Psychiatry Research provides tentative ...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.psypost.org/2020/06/combining-therapy-with-the-psychedelic-drug-psilocybin-results-in-large-reductions-in-anxiety-and-depression-57092</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Ranked Worst for Workers' Rights Among Major Economies</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. has the worst record among major developed countries when it comes to workers' rights, according to a survey of labor unions.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-06-18/u-s-ranked-worst-for-workers-rights-among-major-economies</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Millions of Abandoned Oil Wells Are Leaking Methane, a Climate Menace</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[(This June 16 story corrects comparison in paragraph eight of climate damage from methane leaks to that from U.S. oil consumption. The leaks cause climate damage roughly equivalent to typical U.S. oil consumption in one day, not two days.)]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drilling-abandoned-specialreport/special-report-millions-of-abandoned-oil-wells-are-leaking-methane-a-climate-menace-idUSKBN23N1NL</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PG&E Pleads Guilty to Manslaughter: 'Our Equipment Started the fire.'</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[PG&E's 'gross negligence' led to massive 2018 Camp Fire, district attorney said.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/utility-pleads-guilty-to-84-counts-of-manslaughter-in-california-fire/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Massive Spying on Users of Google's Chrome Shows New Security Weakness</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A newly discovered spyware effort attacked users through 32 million downloads of extensions to Google's market-leading Chrome web browser, researchers at Awake Security told Reuters, highlighting the tech industry's failure to protect browsers as they are used more for email, payroll and other sensi…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-chrome-exclusive/exclusive-massive-spying-on-users-of-googles-chrome-shows-new-security-weakness-idUSKBN23P0JO</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Spot Police Surveillance Tools</title>
			<source>Popular Mechanics</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officers are likely tracking your every move at protests. But if you know what to look for, it's easy to protect yourself.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.popularmechanics.com/technology/security/a32851975/police-surveillance-tools-protest-guide/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A $1.1m Hospital Bill After Surviving the Coronavirus? That's America for You</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It shouldn't take a once-in-a-century pandemic to make policymakers understand the tragic absurdity of healthcare in the United States of America]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/16/coronavirus-hospital-bill-healthcare-america</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Auto Industry Is Wrecked—Let's Rebuild It With Electric</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's the perfect time for a transportation revolution: the Green-Car New Deal.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-auto-industry-is-wrecked-lets-rebuild-it-with-electric/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Universities Step Up the Fight for Open-Access Research</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Today's deal between the University of California and publisher Springer Nature is a big milestone on the path to dismantling paywalls around academic journals.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/universities-step-up-the-fight-for-open-access-research/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Russian Disinfo Operation You Never Heard About</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The campaign known as Secondary Infektion appears to be a distinct effort from the meddling of the IRA and GRU—and it went undetected for years.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/russia-secondary-infektion-disinformation/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You Can Now Buy Spot the Robot Dog—if You've Got $74,500</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Boston Dynamics is finally making its mechanical canine available for businesses and developers. But know that this puppy ain't for everyone.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-now-buy-spot-the-robot-dog/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers Uncover Six-Year Russian Misinformation Campaign Across Facebook and Reddit</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[More than 2500 posts across 300 platforms]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21292982/russian-troll-campaign-facebook-reddit-twitter-misinformation</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Multiple 'CIA Failures' Led to Theft of Agency's Top-Secret Hacking Tools</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Vault 7, the worst data theft in CIA history, could have been avoided, report finds.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/06/theft-of-top-secret-cia-hacking-tools-was-result-of-woefully-lax-security/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Political Groups Use 'Deeply Spooky' Protester Location Data, Report Finds</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Activists want demonstrators to stay active—but privacy implications abound.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/political-groups-use-deeply-spooky-protester-location-data-report-finds/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Fighting Poverty Accidentally Stopped Deforestation</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Evidence from Indonesia shows that development goals don’t have to come at a cost to the climate.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-06-15/how-fighting-poverty-accidentally-stopped-deforestation</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Zoom Shut Down US-Based Activists at China's Request</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hackers for hire, a particularly ignominious phishing campaign, and more of the week's top security news.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/zoom-china-facebook-fbi-security-news/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Three People With Inherited Diseases Successfully Treated With CRISPR</title>
			<source>New Scientist</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two people with beta thalassaemia and one with sickle cell disease no longer need blood transfusions after their blood stem cells were gene edited and put back in their bodies]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2246020-three-people-with-inherited-diseases-successfully-treated-with-crispr/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CEO Worked Way Up From Son of CEO</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 23, 2013</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[No description provided.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_67JbvXLrmw&feature=youtu.be</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pandemic Is Propelling a New Wave of Automation</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Software programs adopted during the Covid-19 crisis make it easier to complete forms and track requests. It saves work, but could cost jobs.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-propelling-new-wave-automation/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Powerful Petrochemical Lobbying Group Advanced Anti-Protest Legislation Amid Pandemic</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[West Virginia is one of several states that have taken advantage of the pandemic to ease the construction of controversial oil and gas projects.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/07/pipeline-petrochemical-lobbying-group-anti-protest-law/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thousands of Tons of Microplastics Are Falling From the Sky</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research helps unravel how vast amounts of plastic particles travel&mdash;both regionally and globally&mdash;on the wind]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/thousands-of-tons-of-microplastics-are-falling-from-the-sky/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Plastic Dust Is Blowing Into U.S. National Parks—More Than 1000 Tons Each Year</title>
			<source>Science</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New study begins to trace a global 'plastic cycle']]></description>
			<link>https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/06/plastic-dust-blowing-us-national-parks-more-1000-tons-each-year</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Attacks on Protesters With 'Less Than Lethal' Weapons Result in Life-Threatening Injuries</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[People demonstrating on the streets, or following along online, don't need studies to know that less-lethal weaponry isn't safe — particularly in crowds.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/11/police-less-than-lethal-weapons-protests/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. States Accuse 26 Drugmakers of Generic Drug Price Fixing in Sweeping Lawsuit</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Twenty-six drug manufacturers were sued on Wednesday by the attorneys general of most U.S. states and several territories, which accused them of conspiring to reduce competition and drive up generic drug prices.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drugs-antitrust-lawsuit/u-s-states-accuse-26-drugmakers-of-generic-drug-price-fixing-in-sweeping-lawsuit-idUSKBN23H2TR</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2 Million Cases and Counting: US COVID-19 Outbreak Charges on Amid Reopening</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Despite testing boosts, experts say increases are real; fear of second wave looms.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/06/us-reaches-2-million-cases-as-states-continue-to-ease-restrictions/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Facebook Tool Allows Employers to Suppress 'Unionize' in Workplace Chat</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook Workplace is used by employers as large as Walmart. The new tool would allow 'content control' to prevent certain topics from trending internally.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/11/facebook-workplace-unionize/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Siberian Officials Say Huge Diesel Spill Has Reached a Sensitive Arctic Lake</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A major diesel spill from a power plant in Siberia has reached a fragile freshwater lake that leads to the Arctic Ocean, according to regional officials. That could create an ecological catastrophe.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/siberian-officials-say-huge-diesel-spill-has-reached-a-1843979303</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MIT, Guided by Open Access Principles, Ends Elsevier Negotiations</title>
			<source>MIT News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Institute ends negotiations for a new journals contract in the absence of a proposal aligning with the MIT Framework for Publisher Contracts.]]></description>
			<link>https://news.mit.edu/2020/guided-by-open-access-principles-mit-ends-elsevier-negotiations-0611</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Coronavirus Pandemic Isn't Ending — It's Surging</title>
			<source>The Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Good news from some nations and diverted attention in others doesn't stop the fact the overall picture is very grim.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2020/06/11/coronavirus-pandemic-isnt-ending-its-surging/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Protesters Across US Attacked by Cars Driven Into Crowds and Men With Guns</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Protesters confronted by armed men – including members of the so-called 'boogaloo movement' – in different parts of America]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/jun/09/protests-us-america-cars-weapons</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Britain Goes Coal Free as Fossil Fuels Edged Out</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, Britain will mark two months without burning any coal to generate power.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-52973089</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Louisville Police Release the Breonna Taylor Incident Report. It's Nearly Blank</title>
			<source>USA Today</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Nearly three months after police fatally shot Breonna Taylor, the department released the incident report. It is almost entirely blank.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2020/06/10/breonna-taylor-case-louisville-police-nearly-blank-incident-report/5335929002/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers Detail Huge Hack-for-Hire Campaigns Against Environmentalists</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['The extensive targeting of American nonprofits exercising their first amendment rights is exceptionally troubling.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/10/21286486/dark-basin-hackers-for-hire-phishing-emails-environmental-nonprofit-groups-exxon-mobil</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Best Raspberry Pi Alternatives</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 09, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you're working on a project that a Pi can't tackle, here are five single-board computers that power any DIY demand.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/gallery/best-raspberry-pi-alternatives/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coronavirus Hospitalizations Rise Sharply in Several States Following Memorial Day</title>
			<source>The Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Since Memorial Day, covid-19 hospitalizations in at least nine states have been on the rise.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/06/09/coronavirus-hospitalizations-rising/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Mapped Where Customs and Border Protection Drones Are Flying in the U.S. and Beyond</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In 2011, Rodney Brossart, a cattle rancher from Lakota, North Dakota was accused of stealing six cows. The cows, he said, simply wandered on to his 3,000-acre farm, and by his estimation, they, therefore, belonged to him. When the cops came, he and his family were prepared. Armed with high power rif…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/we-mapped-where-customs-and-border-protection-drones-ar-1843928454</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Officers Slashed Car Tires During Minneapolis Protests, Police Agencies Say</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Dozens of cars in a Kmart parking lot had all their tires slashed after public anger over George Floyd's death sparked large protests in Minneapolis.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/live-updates-protests-for-racial-justice/2020/06/09/873110812/police-officers-slashed-car-tires-during-minneapolis-protests-police-agencies-sa</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hospitals Got Bailouts and Furloughed Thousands While Paying C.E.O.s Millions</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Dozens of top recipients of government aid have laid off, furloughed or cut the pay of tens of thousands of employees.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/08/business/hospitals-bailouts-ceo-pay.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>To Save the Climate, Look to the Oceans</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[They can be a source of clean, renewable energy, sustainable food,&nbsp;and more]]></description>
			<link>https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/observations/to-save-the-climate-look-to-the-oceans/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You Have a First Amendment Right to Record the Police</title>
			<source>Electronic Frontier Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Like the rest of the world, we are horrified by the videos of George Floyd's murder. Once again, police brutality was documented by brave bystanders exercising their First Amendment rights. Their videos forcefully tell a painful truth that has further fueled a movement to demand an end to racism...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/06/you-have-first-amendment-right-record-police</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yes, American Police Act Like Occupying Armies. They Literally Studied Their Tactics</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The founders of modern policing quelled foreign uprisings. 'Demilitarizing' police will be harder than taking away their tanks]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/yes-american-police-act-like-occupying-armies-they-literally-studied-their-tactics</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Can No Longer Ignore the Potential of Psychedelic Drugs to Treat Depression</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At Imperial College we've been comparing psilocybin to conventional antidepressants – and the results are likely to be game-changing, says Robin Carhart-Harris]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/jun/08/psychedelic-drugs-treat-depression</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New CDC Survey Finds That Some Americans Are Misusing Disinfectants</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new survey by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has found that some Americans are misusing cleaning and disinfectant products to prevent coronavirus. Some practices include misting their bodies with disinfectant and gargling bleach.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/cdc-americans-are-misting-their-bodies-with-disinfecta-1843944408</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's Official: U.S. Economy Is in a Recession</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The committee tasked with marking U.S. business cycles says the economy peaked in February and has since been in a recession triggered by the pandemic. But it says the recession could be short-lived.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/06/08/872336272/its-official-scorekeepers-say-u-s-economy-is-in-a-recession</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Protests About Police Brutality Are Met With Wave of Police Brutality Across US</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Use of teargas, batons, pepper spray, fists, feet and vehicles against protesters sparks lawsuits and international condemnation]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/jun/06/police-violence-protests-us-george-floyd</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Tactics Could Turn Protests Into Covid-19 Hot Spots</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sure, large crowds already carry a risk of transmission. It's just worse when you teargas people, make them cough on each other, and bus them to jail.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/police-tactics-could-turn-protests-into-covid-19-hot-spots/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Unluckiest Generation in U.S. History</title>
			<source>The Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Millennials have faced the worst economic odds, and many will never recover.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/05/27/millennial-recession-covid/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Misconduct Records Are Secret. Protests May Finally Change That.</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A decades-old New York State law that has kept police behavior from public scrutiny may finally be overturned.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/05/nyregion/police-misconduct-records-are-secret-protests-may-finally-change-that.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Signs Order Removing Environmental Review of Major Projects</title>
			<source>The Hill</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[President Trump signed an executive order Thursday evening that would waive requirements under a suite of environmental laws, a move the administration says will boost the economy amid the coronavirus pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://thehill.com/policy/energy-environment/501258-trump-signs-order-removing-environmental-review-for-major-projects</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amid Pandemic and Protests, Trump Fast-Tracks Dangerous Fossil Fuel Infrastructure</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Amid nationwide protests against racist police brutality and a pandemic that's disproportionately affecting Black people, on Thursday night, Trump signed an executive order directing federal agencies to fast track the construction of projects that will put communities of color at risk.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/amid-pandemic-and-protests-trump-fast-tracks-dangerous-1843922269</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Americans Are Drinking Bleach and Dunking Food in It to Prevent COVID-19</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thirty-nine percent of surveyed people admitted to at least one risky practice.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/06/americans-are-drinking-bleach-and-dunking-food-in-it-to-prevent-covid-19/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pentagon War Game Includes Scenario for Military Response to Domestic Gen Z Rebellion</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The 2018 war game envisioned a 'Zbellion' by a tech-savvy generation that no longer believed in the American dream.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/05/pentagon-war-game-gen-z/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Buffalo Police Said Protester With Head Wound 'Tripped and Fell.' Video Shows They Lied.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Police officers in Buffalo, New York were caught on camera shoving a 75-year-old protester to the ground, injuring him at a protest against police brutality.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/05/buffalo-police-said-protester-head-wound-tripped-fell-video-shows-lied/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID Vaccine Execs Hyped Vague Data to Cash in $90M in Stock, Watchdog Says</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Executives allegedly 'exploited widespread fears' of pandemic to make millions.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/06/covid-vaccine-execs-hyped-vague-data-to-cash-in-90m-in-stock-watchdog-says/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Massive Oil Spill in the Arctic Has Turned a River Red</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Russia declared a state of emergency after a power plant spilled 20,000 metric tons of oil and diesel fuel into a river in the Arctic Circle. The possible cause: melting permafrost due to climate change.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ep4x54/a-massive-oil-spill-in-the-arctic-has-turned-a-river-red</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>All This Chaos Might Be Giving You 'Crisis Fatigue'</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Your body is well adapted to handle temporary stresses, but it's overwhelmed by the constant, unrelenting pressures of this horrible year.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/crisis-fatigue/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Harvard Shrank Its Insect-Inspired Microrobot to the Size of a Penny</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Harvard researchers have made the tiny Harvard Ambulatory Microrobot (HAMR) even tinier. The next-gen HAMR-JR is one of the smallest and fastest microrobots to date.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/harvard-hamr-jr-penny-sized-microrobot-160529162.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth's Carbon Dioxide Levels Hit Record High, Despite Coronavirus-Related Emissions Drop</title>
			<source>The Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Carbon dioxide levels are now the highest they've been in human history, and likely the highest in 3 million years.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2020/06/04/carbon-dioxide-record-2020/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tear Gas Is Way More Dangerous Than Police Let on — Especially During the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the middle of a respiratory pandemic, law enforcement agencies have used tear gas in especially dangerous ways. The chemical agent also seeps into homes, contaminates food, furniture, skin and surfaces, and can cause long-term lung damage.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/tear-gas-is-way-more-dangerous-than-police-let-on-especially-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How US Police Used Military Tactics to Turn Peaceful Protests Violent</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What would have happened had police taken a calmer approach at the beginning of the protests? Well, look at what happened in Baltimore]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.co.uk/article/police-brutality-minneapolis-floyd-blm-trump</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Crunched the Numbers: Police — Not Protesters — Are Overwhelmingly Responsible for Attacking Journalists</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Protests over the killing of George Floyd have seen attacks on the press spike. Our data shows police are responsible for more than 80 percent of them.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/04/journalists-attacked-police-george-floyd-protests/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New PFAS Chemical Contamination Discovered in New Jersey</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Eight variations of a newly identified group of PFAS compounds were found near a Solvay plant in West Deptford, New Jersey.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/04/pfas-chemicals-new-jersey-solvay/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Buffalo Police Officers Suspended After Shoving 75-Year-Old Protester</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A video showed the protester motionless on the ground and bleeding. Fifty-seven officers resigned from the department's Emergency Response Team in solidarity with the two who were suspended.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/05/us/buffalo-police-shove-protester-unrest.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NYPD Officers at George Floyd Protests Are Covering Their Badge Numbers in Violation of Own Policy</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The National Lawyers Guild threatened to sue the city if NYPD officers did not end the widespread practice of covering their badge numbers.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/03/nypd-badge-black-band/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Minneapolis Cops Sued for Shooting, Beating, and Gassing Over a Dozen Journalists</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ACLU has filed a class-action lawsuit against Minnesota authorities on behalf of journalists whom state and local police were filmed beating, shooting, gassing, and arresting during protests against the police killing of George Floyd.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/minneapolis-cops-sued-for-shooting-beating-and-gassin-1843887290</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Let's Start a Riot': Denver Cop Fired for Inflammatory Instagram Post</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Post was 'inconsistent with the values of the Department,' investigation found.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/denver-cop-fired-for-writing-lets-start-a-riot-on-instagram/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Launches 60 More Starlink Satellites and Achieves a Reusability Record for a Falcon 9 Booster</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX launched its second Falcon 9 rocket in the span of just four days on Wednesday at 9:25 PM EDT (6:25 PM PDT). This one was carrying 60 more satellites for its Starlink constellation, which will bring the total currently in operation on orbit to 480. The launch took off from Florida, where Spa…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-and-records-a-reusability-record-for-a-falcon-9-booster/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Than 70 Children Killed in Just 10 Airstrikes in Afghanistan, Report Finds</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Bureau of Investigative Journalism analyzed 10 strikes by the U.S. military and the U.S.-backed Afghan air force and found 115 civilians were killed.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/03/children-killed-airstrikes-afghanistan-tbij-report/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Cop Hits Australian Cameraman Live on National Television</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['You heard us yelling that we were media, but they don't care,' reporter said.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/us-cop-hits-australian-cameraman-live-on-national-television/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Millions of Americans Skip Payments as Tidal Wave of Defaults and Evictions Looms</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hardship programs appear to be helping many people pause payments and survive the economic shutdown so far. But not everybody is getting the help, and advocates see big potential trouble ahead.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/2020/06/03/867856602/millions-of-americans-skipping-payments-as-tidal-wave-of-defaults-and-evictions-</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CIA Veterans Who Monitored Crackdowns Abroad See Troubling Parallels in Trump's Handling of Protests</title>
			<source>The Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For former U.S. intelligence officials, scenes of armed clashes and strongman poses are familiar signs of a fraying country.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/cia-veterans-who-monitored-crackdowns-abroad-see-troubling-parallels-in-trump-handling-of-protests/2020/06/02/7ab210b8-a4f6-11ea-bb20-ebf0921f3bbd_story.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What the Future of the Space Station Looks Like After SpaceX's Historic Launch</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The paradigm of human spaceflight for the last nine years is about to change]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/21276881/nasa-spacex-iss-international-space-station-future-commercial</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Pharma Attacks Efforts to Guard Against Coronavirus Price Gouging</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A coalition of conservative groups, many funded by the pharmaceutical industry, have attacked proposals aiming to ensure Covid-19 treatments are affordable.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/02/big-pharma-coronavirus-treatment-price-gouging/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Influencers Reemerge, Worse Than Ever</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Santa Monica area influencer was caught borrowing a worker's drill to stage a photo-op outside a boarded-up shop damaged by the previous night's looting. Toting a photographer/boyfriend, the woman hands the drill back to a worker and climbs into a Mercedes-Benz and scurries away, pronouncing 'Good…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/influencers-reemerge-worse-than-ever-1843866512</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Nonlethal' Anti-Protest Weapons Can Cause Serious Harm</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Rubber bullets and tear gas are billed as relatively safe. They're anything but.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/tear-gas-rubber-bullets-nonlethal-harm-protests/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Short History of U.S. Law Enforcement Infiltrating Protests</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For decades, local police and FBI have sent undercover officials to participate in — and escalate — protests.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/02/history-united-states-government-infiltration-protests/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The NYPD Knows It Can Get Away With Attacking Protesters</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The NYPD has long been shielded from accountability. This week's violent response to protesters exposed the extent of the department's culture of impunity.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/06/02/new-york-police-protesters-george-floyd/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth Is Accelerating Towards Sixth Mass Extinction That Could See 'End of Civilisation'</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Stop The Wildlife Trade: 'Extinction breeds extinction', says grim new study revealing more than 500 species are on course to go extinct in next two decades - around the same figure for the whole of the twentieth century]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/sixth-mass-extinction-endangered-animals-wildlife-markets-biodiversity-crisis-standford-study-a9544856.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Demands Journalists Correct Stories on the Use of Tear Gas. According to the CDC, It Was Tear Gas.</title>
			<source>Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The truth about what was deployed on Lafayette Square protesters to make way for the president's photo op boils down to an exercise in semantics.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/media/trump-demands-journalists-correct-stories-on-the-use-of-tear-gas-according-to-the-cdc-it-was-tear-gas/2020/06/02/bf68726c-a544-11ea-bb20-ebf0921f3bbd_story.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Is Talking About Using Tanks to Quell the George Floyd Protests, but the Pentagon Is Getting Cold Feet</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Pentagon officials said Defense Secretary Mark Esper's urgings that states 'dominate the battlespace' was more a show of loyalty.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/pentagon-didnt-expect-trump-deploy-more-troops-after-esper-call-2020-6</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google Faces $5 Billion Lawsuit in U.S. for Tracking 'Private' Internet Use</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Google was sued on Tuesday in a proposed class action accusing the internet search company of illegally invading the privacy of millions of users by pervasively tracking their internet use through browsers set in 'private' mode.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-privacy-lawsuit/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-in-us-for-tracking-private-internet-use-idUSKBN23933H</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pentagon's Hand-Me-Downs Helped Militarize Police. Here's How</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over several decades, the 1033 program has shipped over $7.4 billion of Defense Department property to more than 8,000 law enforcement agencies.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/pentagon-hand-me-downs-militarize-police-1033-program/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tear Gas Is Dangerous and Should Be Illegal</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Tear gas is a chemical weapon that is banned for use in warfare, yet U.S. police have repeatedly deployed it against people protesting police brutality and anti-black violence this week. Though it's considered a non-lethal weapon, tear gas is actually far more dangerous than advertised—especially i…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/tear-gas-is-dangerous-and-should-be-illegal-1843858956</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>California Supreme Court Rules Cops Can't Bury Public Record Requests With Redaction Fees</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A recent California Supreme Court decision has ruled that government agencies in the state can't pass on the costs of privacy redactions in the course of fulfilling records requests. According to the ruling, the cost of redacting records that citizens file under the California Public Records Act (CP…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/california-supreme-court-rules-cops-cant-bury-public-re-1843857674</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Your Phone Is a Goldmine of Hidden Data for Cops. Here's How to Fight Back</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For the thousands of people protesting and reporting on George Floyd's death at the hands of the Minneapolis Police Department—or even for bystanders caught up in the demonstrations—arrests, injuries, and even death are becoming commonplace in this moment. And just like protests we've experienced wi…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/your-phone-is-a-goldmine-of-hidden-data-for-cops-heres-1843817740</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mass Extinctions Are Accelerating, Scientists Report</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Five hundred species are likely to become extinct over the next two decades, according to a new study.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/science/mass-extinctions-are-accelerating-scientists-report.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>British Photographer Arrested at George Floyd Protests in 'Affront to Press Freedom'</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['One big cop came at me and pushed me to the ground with his truncheon to my chest,' says Adam Gray – hit with unlawful assembly charge after taking photos of protesters]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/george-floyd-protests-uk-photographer-arrested-charged-new-york-city-a9542631.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Major Breakthrough Allows Robot Hand to 'See and Feel' Objects as Fragile as a Crisp</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['We wish to enable seeing the world by feeling the world,' researchers say]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/robots-soft-robotics-hand-mit-csail-a9538301.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An Onslaught of Crises Has Created a Modern Paradox</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Never before have humans lived more comfortably. And yet today we're overwhelmed by crises, be it inequality or economic collapse or Covid, all exacerbating one another.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/covid-crisis-modern-paradox/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Just Threatened to Use the U.S. Military Against Americans</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trump's plan involves invoking a two-century-old law known as the Insurrection Act, which allows the president to deploy troops inside the country.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/k7q84n/trump-just-threatened-to-use-the-us-military-against-americans</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After Dragon's Historic Docking, America Has More New Spaceships on the Way</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['It flew really well, very crisp. We couldn't be happier.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/06/after-dragons-historic-docking-america-has-more-new-spaceships-on-the-way/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Police Have Attacked Journalists More Than 130 Times Since May 28</title>
			<source>Nieman Lab</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['Although in some incidents it is possible the journalists were hit or affected accidentally, in the majority of the cases we have recorded the journalists are clearly identifiable as press, and it is clear that they are being deliberately targeted.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/well-try-to-help-you-follow-the-police-attacks-on-journalists-across-the-country</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Than 500 Vertebrate Species Are on the Brink of 'Biological Annihilation'</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new study finds further evidence that humans are driving the world's sixth mass extinction. Published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences Monday, this research focuses on terrestrial vertebrates—amphibians, birds, mammals, and reptiles—and found that more than 500 species are 'o…]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/more-than-500-vertebrate-species-are-on-the-brink-of-b-1843828308</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Army's New Drone Swarm May Be a Weapon of Mass Destruction</title>
			<source>Forbes</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Cluster Swarm project is developing a warhead to dispense a swarm of drones that fan out to automatically locate and destroy vehicles with explosively formed penetrators. It seems likely to be able to inflict an immense amount of harm but inable to distinguish civilians from military targets.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidhambling/2020/06/01/why-new-us-armys-tank-killing-drone-swarm-may-be-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/#522261b1ece8</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Animal Rights Activists Uncover the Locations of Thousands of Factory Farms</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The animal agriculture industry has spent decades fighting to avoid the disclosure of information about facilities where animals are raised for food.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/31/animal-rights-map-farms-coronavirus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>George Floyd Protests: Reporters Targeted by Police and Crowds</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Journalists report and record being shot at, teargassed, arrested and intimidated]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/31/george-floyd-protests-reporters-targeted-by-police-and-crowds</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Protest Safely in the Age of Surveillance</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Law enforcement has more tools than ever to track your movements and access your communications. Here's how to protect your privacy if you plan to protest.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-protest-safely-surveillance-digital-privacy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Launched Two Astronauts—Changing Spaceflight Forever</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The test mission will clear the way for regular crewed launches from the United States for the first time in nearly a decade.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launched-two-astronauts-changing-spaceflight-forever/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The George Floyd Killing Exposes the Failures of Police Reform</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As protests engulf Minneapolis after yet another police killing, advocates across the country say the time for police reform is over.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/29/george-floyd-minneapolis-police-reform/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Border Patrol Flies Anti-Terrorism Drone Over Minneapolis Protestors</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Predator B drone from near-by Airforce bases makes six passes over protestors.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/border-patrol-drone-used-in-anti-terror-ops-flies-over-minneapolis-protestors/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>135-Year-Long Streak Is Over: US Renewable Sources Topped Coal in 2019</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Including wood and biofuels across all sectors, coal fell short last year.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/2019-was-first-year-since-1880s-that-us-coal-lost-to-renewable-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facial Recognition and License Plate Readers: Here Are the Surveillance Tools Used by the Minneapolis Police Department</title>
			<source>BuzzFeed News</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As protesters demonstrate in Minneapolis in response to George Floyd's death, law enforcement agencies have access to a host of surveillance tools that could make it easier to target and find them.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolinehaskins1/george-floyd-protests-surveillance-technology</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Twitter Hides Trump Tweet for 'Glorifying Violence'</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For the first time, Twitter has hidden a tweet on the president's profile behind a warning.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52846679</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN Journalists Arrested Live on Air While Covering George Floyd Protests</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[CNN has reported that its correspondent Omar Jimenez, producer Bill Kirkos and photojournalist Leonel Mendez have been released from police custody after they were arrested in Minneapolis live on air.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/media/video/2020/may/29/cnn-journalists-omar-jimenez-minneapolis-arrested-live-on-air-while-covering-george-floyd-protests-video</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A.C.L.U. Accuses Clearview AI of Privacy 'Nightmare Scenario'</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>May 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The facial recognition start-up violated the privacy of Illinois residents by collecting their images without their consent, the civil liberties group says in a new lawsuit.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/28/technology/clearview-ai-privacy-lawsuit.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The CDC Released New Death Rate Estimates for the Coronavirus. Many Scientists Say They're Too Low.</title>
			<source>BuzzFeed News</source>
			<pubDate>May 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Public health experts are accusing the CDC of bending under political pressure to say the coronavirus is less deadly.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/stephaniemlee/coronavirus-cdc-infection-fatality-rate</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NSA Warns of Ongoing Russian Hacking Campaign Against U.S. Systems</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. National Security Agency on Thursday warned government partners and private companies about a Russian hacking operation that uses a special intrusion technique to target operating systems often used by industrial firms to manage computer infrastructure.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-usa-russia-idUSKBN2342RE</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mining Company Blows Up 46,000-Year-Old Aboriginal Site, Expresses No Regrets</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 28 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A culturally important archaeological site in Western Australia was destroyed this past weekend during the expansion of an iron ore mine. Upsettingly, the mining company responsible for the incident did so with state permission, exposing Australia's weak and bigoted heritage conservation laws.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/mining-company-blows-up-46-000-year-old-aboriginal-site-1843729409</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ACLU Sues Clearview AI Over Alleged Privacy Violations</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 28 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ACLU has sued Clearview AI for allegedly violating Illinois privacy law through its face recognition-based surveillance technology.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/aclu-sues-clearview-ai-164518487.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Leaked Draft Details Trump's Likely Attack on Technology Giants</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 28 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Draft executive order claims that technology giants have 'dangerous power.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/leaked-trump-order-is-a-wide-ranging-attack-on-facebook-and-twitter/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bad State Data Hides Coronavirus Threat as Trump Pushes Reopening</title>
			<source>Politico</source>
			<pubDate>May 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Test counts inflated, death tolls deflated, metrics shifted.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.politico.com/news/2020/05/27/bad-state-coronavirus-data-trump-reopening-286143</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After Twitter Fact-Check, Trump Threatens to Regulate or Close Down Social Media Platforms</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Once again, Donald Trump has doubled down. Following the addition of a fact-checking warning label added to his tweet about mail-in ballots, Trump took to the platform yet again to denounce it. In what may be his strongest words to date against a service that has largely given him free rein to this…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/after-twitter-fact-check-trump-threatens-to-regulate-or-close-down-social-media-platforms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FBI Investigates Death of Black Man After Footage Shows Officer Kneeling on His Neck</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Four officers fired in wake of death of George Floyd, who told Minneapolis police: 'I cannot breathe']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/26/george-floyd-killing-police-video-fbi-investigation</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>100,000 Americans Dead—and Counting—as COVID-19 Ravages US</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[US leads the world in cases and deaths—and the pandemic is far from over.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/100000-dead-us-tops-grim-milestone-in-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Whistleblowers Say Facebook Has Not Warned Investors About Illegal Activity, in New SEC Complaint</title>
			<source>Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The whistleblower's complaint claims the social media giant is aware of illegal activity on its platform, such as the sale of opioids, and has failed to properly police it.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/05/27/facebook-sec-whistleblower/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Revealed: Conservative Group Fighting to Restrict Voting Tied to Powerful Dark Money Network</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Honest Elections Project, part of network that pushed supreme court pick Brett Kavanaugh, is now focusing on voting restrictions]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/27/honest-elections-project-conservative-voting-restrictions</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Material Releases Hydrogen From Water at Near-Perfect Efficiency</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Only works at UV wavelengths, but it might point the way toward general approach.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/new-material-releases-hydrogen-from-water-at-near-perfect-efficiency/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How the Fed Bailed Out the Investor Class Without Spending a Cent</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 27 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Just announcing $4.5 trillion in future spending to support securities markets was enough to keep investors protected from the downsides of the pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/27/federal-reserve-corporate-debt-coronavirus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>YouTube Says That an Error Caused Comments Critical of China's Government to Auto-Delete</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[YouTube responded to reports that it is automatically deleting comments criticizing the Chinese government, explaining that the seeming censorship is actually an error in its automated moderation systems. As the Verge reported, comments on the platform using the Chinese phrases for 'communist…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/youtube-china-comments-wumao-dang/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>House Leaders Strike Deal to Protect U.S. Web Browsing Data From Warrantless Surveillance</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[After three days of negotiations, House lawmakers have struck a deal on an amendment aimed at protecting innocent Americans from being spied on by their own government online.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/house-leaders-strike-deal-to-protect-u-s-web-browsing-1843678595</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FBI Investigating Ahmaud Arbery Shooting as Possible Hate Crime, Lawyer Says</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Attorney for family of black jogger shot by white men says federal authorities are looking into prosecutors and police in case]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/25/ahmaud-arbery-shooting-hate-crime-fbi</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Local News Stations Run Propaganda Segment Scripted and Produced by Amazon</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least 11 TV stations aired an identical segment written and produced by Amazon's PR team.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/4ayvwb/local-news-stations-run-propaganda-segments-scripted-and-produced-by-amazon</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Twitter's First Fact-Check on President Trump Calls Out 'False Claims' [Updated]</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Twitter: 'Get the facts.' Trump: 'Twitter is completely stifling FREE SPEECH.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/twitters-first-fact-check-on-president-trump-calls-out-false-claims/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA and SpaceX Confirm SpaceX's First Ever Astronaut Launch Is a 'Go'</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 25 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[NASA and SpaceX are closer than ever to a moment both have been preparing for since the beginning of the Commercial Crew program in 2010. SpaceX's Falcon 9 and Crew Dragon spacecraft are now set to fly with NASA astronauts Doug Hurley and Bob Behnken onboard, making a trip to the Internationa…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/nasa-and-spacex-confirm-spacexs-first-ever-astronaut-launch-is-a-go/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hong Kong's Government Is Now Calling Pro-Democracy Protesters 'Terrorists'</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 25 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hong Kong's protesters are back, and the Beijing-backed government says their return only underscores the need for new treason and sedition laws.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/889n4x/hong-kongs-government-is-now-calling-pro-democracy-protesters-terrorists</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Third of Americans Now Show Signs of Clinical Anxiety or Depression, Census Bureau Finds Amid Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 25 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Symptoms of anxiety and depression are widespread during the pandemic, according to the Census Bureau's new Household Pulse Survey.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/05/26/americans-with-depression-anxiety-pandemic/?arc404=true</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Beaches, Parks Full on Memorial Day Weekend Despite Pandemic</title>
			<source>Al Jazeera</source>
			<pubDate>May 24 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Health officials issue warnings after some revellers did not follow precautions while marking the beginning of summer.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/05/beaches-parks-full-memorial-day-weekend-pandemic-200524183947394.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Massive Database of 8 Billion Thai Internet Records Leaks</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 24 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The unprotected database contained DNS queries on millions of Thail internet users.]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/24/thai-billions-internet-records-leak/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Inside the NSA's Secret Tool for Mapping Your Social Network</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 24 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Edward Snowden revealed the agency's phone-record tracking program. But thanks to 'precomputed contact chaining,' that database was much more powerful than anyone knew.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-nsas-secret-tool-for-mapping-your-social-network/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coronavirus in the U.S.: Latest Map and Case Count</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>May 23 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A detailed county map shows the extent of the coronavirus outbreak, with tables of the number of cases by county.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/us/coronavirus-us-cases.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Story of Cheaper Batteries, From Smartphones to Teslas</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The economics of cheaper batteries—and why they're good news for the planet.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/features/2020/05/the-story-of-cheaper-batteries-from-smartphones-to-teslas/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No Masks Allowed: Stores Turn Customers Away in US Culture War</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Shops around the US make headlines for denying entry to those wearing masks as protesters argue against preventative measures in the name of freedom]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/22/us-stores-against-face-masks</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers Squeeze 44.2 Tbps Through Existing Fiber Optic Cables</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers in Australia used a device called a microcomb to break the record for the fastest internet connection.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/44-tbps-internet-connection-154034760.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yes, the Patriot Act Amendment to Track Us Online Is Real</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Looks like more bad news with the renewal of the Patriot Act/USA Freedom Act — and its terrible provision to allow government collection of Americans' internet browsing and search histories without a warrant.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/yes-the-patriot-act-amendment-to-track-us-online-is-real-173055117.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Drops Word 'Peaceful' in Latest Push for Taiwan 'Reunification'</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Chinese Premier Li Keqiang left out the word 'peaceful' on Friday in referring to Beijing's desire to 'reunify' with Chinese-claimed Taiwan, an apparent policy shift that comes as ties with Taipei continue on a downward spiral.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-parliament-taiwan/china-drops-word-peaceful-in-latest-push-for-taiwan-reunification-idUSKBN22Y06S</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It Hit 80 Degrees in the Arctic This Week</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This story will provide important context for the headline, and I encourage you to read it—but really, the headline tells you what you need to know: It was 80 degrees Fahrenheit above the Arctic Circle this week.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/it-hit-80-degrees-in-the-arctic-this-week-1843606717</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The U.S. Brags About Health Aid to Africa While Bombing Some of Its Most Vulnerable Nations</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 22 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Libya and Somalia, where U.S. forces have spent hundreds of millions on airstrikes, have fared especially poorly when it comes to direct U.S. health assistance.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/22/us-africa-aid-coronavirus-somalia-libya/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Just Turning Your Phone on Qualifies as Searching It, Court Rules</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Location data requires a warrant since 2018; lock screen may now, too.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/just-turning-your-phone-on-qualifies-as-searching-it-court-rules/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Every Pharmaceutical Commercial Is REALLY Saying</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Consume. www.trustourbrand.com]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlWXhBw4TwU</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Congress Has No Idea How Much Web Browsing Data the FBI Collects</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Patriot Act is about to be reauthorized, but we still don't know basic facts about how our web browsing habits are being collected.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ep4d97/congress-has-no-idea-how-much-web-browsing-data-the-fbi-collects</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nearly Half of Twitter Accounts Pushing to Reopen America May Be Bots</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Kathleen M. Carley and her team at Carnegie Mellon University's Center for Informed Democracy & Social Cybersecurity have been tracking bots and influence campaigns for a long time. Across US and foreign elections, natural disasters, and other politicized events, the level of bot involvement is norm…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/05/21/1002105/covid-bot-twitter-accounts-push-to-reopen-america/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>California: 1,200 Pastors Say They Will Defy State Order and Resume Services</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[State allowing some businesses to reopen, but churches still banned. As many as 3,000 churches could hold services on 31 May]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/21/california-pastors-services-stay-home-order</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The CIA's Murderous Practices, Disinformation Campaigns, and Interference in Other Countries Still Shape the World Order and U.S. Politics</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 21 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[No understanding of international or domestic politics is possible without a factual grasp of the CIA's purpose.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/21/the-cias-murderous-practices-disinformation-campaigns-and-interference-in-other-countries-still-shapes-the-world-order-and-u-s-politics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'We've Been Muzzled': CDC Sources Say White House Putting Politics Ahead of Science</title>
			<source>CNN</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the early weeks of the US coronavirus outbreak, staff members in the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention had tracked a growing number of transmissions in Europe and elsewhere, and proposed a global advisory that would alert flyers to the dangers of air travel.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/20/politics/coronavirus-travel-alert-cdc-white-house-tensions-invs/index.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Acting U.S. Spy Chief Questioned Over Warrantless Capture of Americans' Web Browsing History</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. Senator Ron Wyden, the sponsor of a recent amendment to stop the FBI from capturing Americans' search and web browsing histories without a warrant, is now asking the nation's top spy (acting) to disclose whether his office has accurately reported on such activities, which the law seemingly requ…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/acting-u-s-spy-chief-questioned-over-warrantless-captu-1843572200</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EasyJet Admits Data of Nine Million Hacked</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The attack was 'sophisticated' the airline said, adding that some credit card details had been accessed.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52722626</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maryland Reopens—and Quickly Sees Its Largest COVID-19 Spike</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Health officials worry reopening amid continued spread could spark second wave.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/maryland-reopens-and-quickly-sees-its-largest-covid-19-spike/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ousted Scientist Says She Was Asked to Manipulate Florida COVID-19 Data</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Jones said she was ordered 'to manually change data' to support reopening.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/ousted-scientist-says-she-was-asked-to-manipulate-florida-covid-19-data/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'People Are Sick All Around Me': Inside the Coronavirus Catastrophe in California Prisons</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Prisoners and advocates told the Guardian that some infected inmates are in isolation without medical care or adequate food, cut off from family and attorneys]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/20/california-prisons-covid-19-outbreak-deaths</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Announces Executive Order 'Suspending' Regulations Impeding the Economy</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[President hands his Cabinet secretaries broad say to nix more regulations]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/trump-press-conference-today-executive-order-economy-regulations-coronavirus-a9523126.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>He Opposed Public Lands and Wildlife Protections. Trump Gave Him a Top Environment Job</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Under the leadership of William Perry Pendley, the Bureau of Land Management is failing to fulfill its most basic duties of safeguarding America's public lands, his critics say]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/may/20/william-perry-pendley-trump-pick-top-environmental-post-endangered-species</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Let's Rebuild the Broken Meat Industry—Without Animals</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Covid-19 has laid bare many flaws of industrialized animal agriculture. Plant- and cell-based alternatives offer a more resilient solution.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-lets-rebuild-the-broken-meat-industry-without-animals/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change Is Turning Antarctica's Snow Green</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the planet warms, parts of the planet are going green—and not in the environmentally friendly way. Snow in coastal Antarctica is literally turning the color green.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/climate-change-is-turning-antarcticas-snow-green-1843549489</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Not a Mask in Sight': Thousands Flock to Yellowstone as Park Reopens</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[With support of the Trump administration, Yellowstone and Grand Teton national parks have partially reopened after Covid-19 closures]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/may/19/yellowstone-coronavirus-reopening-grand-teton-covid-19</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FBI Power to Warrantlessly Seize Your Web Browsing History May Hinge on a Single Democrat</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Republicans and Democrats engrossed in a fight over the future of privacy in America say the public support of a specific influential Democrat is likely critical to secure a vote next week on an amendment that would prohibit FBI agents from demanding Americans' web browsing data without a warrant.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/fbi-power-to-warrantlessly-seize-your-web-browsing-hist-1843552385</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Covid-19's Toll on Prison Labor Doesn't Just Hurt Inmates</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Work stoppages impact the incarcerated workforce as well. The financial losses extend beyond the walls.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-prison-labor/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>America Just Made a Huge Investment in Next-Gen Nuclear Power</title>
			<source>Popular Mechanics</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[That means tinier, better reactors in the near future.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.popularmechanics.com/science/a32598099/advanced-nuclear-power-tiny-reactors/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Your Equifax Settlement $125 Isn't Coming, but Banks Get Their $5.5M</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sure, you might only get a few cents at this point, but where is it?]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/banks-get-their-slice-of-equifax-settlement-individuals-still-waiting/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Trump Administration Gave a Drug-Making Contract Worth Up to $812 Million to a Small Virginia Firm Founded Less Than 6 Months Ago</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Trump administration is plowing hundreds of millions into boosting US medicine manufacturing, fearing an overreliance on foreign companies.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/coronavirus-trump-admin-gives-812m-contract-to-small-virginia-firm-2020-5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ukraine Catches Hacker Who Tried to Sell 773 Million Stolen Email Addresses</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Ukrainian officials detained the hacker, known as Sanix, who tried to sell a database with 773 million email addresses and 21 million unique passwords.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/ukraine-officials-arrest-hacker-sanix-stolen-emails-194657808.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Honest Political Ads - Gil Fulbright for Senate</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 08 2014</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Join the movement to end political corruption: www.represent.us What would an honest politician actually sound like? America's biggest problems are going uns...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wz_V4lRdtjo</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hollow Point Bullets Recalled That Don't Explode in Targets</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 16 2009</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Steel Hawk Inc. is offering a full refund to customers who bought the non-flesh-shredding bullets.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f8XcVc_0ykU</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>First Female Dictator Hailed as Step Forward for Women</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 16 2009</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Amivi Gama's violent rise to power in East Timor has proved that women are just as capable as men when it comes to brutality and oppression.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iEtw3XJoJrE</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Memorial Honors Victims of Imminent Dam Disaster</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 16 2008</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officials in California dedicated the Folsom Dam Memorial, which will honor the nearby residents that will die when the faulty dam fails.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yjfrJzdx7DA</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's Called Artificial Intelligence — But What Is Intelligence?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We've built machines that are capable of incredible feats, yet still they have nothing on a baby.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/its-called-artificial-intelligence-but-what-is-intelligence/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Is the Brain a Useful Model for Artificial Intelligence?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thinking machines think just like us—but only up to a point.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/brain-model-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Are AI-Powered Killer Robots Inevitable?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Military scholars warn of a 'battlefield singularity,' a point at which humans can no longer keep up with the pace of conflict.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-military-robots/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'First Ever' Near Real-Time Analysis of Global Carbon Emissions Reveals Coronavirus Impacts</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Lockdowns around the world are having a measurable effect on global greenhouse gas emissions. A new study out Tuesday found that daily emissions dropped by 17 percent in April 2020 compared to last year's average levels. This is a sizable dip, but the findings offer a sobering reality check: Individ…]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/first-ever-near-real-time-analysis-of-global-carbon-e-1843542294</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's Time to Dismantle Factory Farms and Get Used to Eating Less Meat</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We should envision a more resilient and sustainable food system, one that doesn't commodify sentient life]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/may/19/its-time-to-get-used-to-eating-less-meat</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Carbon Dioxide Emissions Have Dropped 17 Percent During the Pandemic</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Some regions, like the US and the UK, have seen their outputs fall by a third, due in large part to people driving less.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/carbon-dioxide-emissions-pandemic/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>As Machines Get Smarter, How Will We Relate to Them?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Millennia of evolution have left us ill prepared to crack open the black box of AI and peer inside.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/as-machines-get-smarter-how-will-we-relate-to-them/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Alarm and Confusion at Fox News as Trump Says He Takes Hydroxychloroquine</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Fox News viewers were warned not to take medical advice from the president, following Donald Trump's announcement that he takes the drug hydroxychloroquine.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/19/alarm-confusion-fox-news-trump-says-takes-hydroxychloroquine/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Watch a Boston Dynamics Robot Herd Sheep in New Zealand</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 19 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New Zealand-based robotics company Rocos shared a video of Boston Dynamics' Spot herding sheep across grassy pastures.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/boston-dynamics-spot-robots-herd-sheep-135533533.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Arctic Is Unraveling as a Massive Heat Wave Grips the Region</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 18 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It wouldn't be spring in the climate change era without a massive heat wave in the Arctic.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/the-arctic-is-unraveling-as-a-massive-heat-wave-grips-t-1843519435</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Lockdown Protests May Have Spread Virus Widely, Cellphone Data Suggests</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 18 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Devices associated with protesters travelled up to hundreds of miles after rallies where few precautions were taken]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/may/18/lockdown-protests-spread-coronavirus-cellphone-data</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CDC Sued Over 'Pattern' of Mishandling Freedom of Information Requests During Pandemic</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 18 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is facing a lawsuit over its alleged mishandling of records requests under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). Plaintiffs accuse the agency of 'systematically obstruct[ing]' attempts by the public to acquire details about the government's handl…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/cdc-sued-over-pattern-of-mishandling-freedom-of-informa-1843527205</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's Air Pollution Is Now Worse Than Pre-Coronavirus Levels</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 18 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last month, China finally ended its coronavirus lockdown. While air quality improved dramatically during The Quiet Time, new data shows it was short-lived. What's more, air pollution is coming back at higher levels than during the same period last year.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/chinas-air-pollution-is-already-worse-than-pre-coronavi-1843520326</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cell-Tower Attacks by Idiots Who Claim 5G Spreads COVID-19 Reportedly Hit US</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 18 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[US warns carriers to boost security, citing reports of attacks in several states.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/prepare-for-cell-tower-attacks-by-5g-covid-19-conspiracy-theorists-us-warns/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Federal Government Buys Riot Gear, Increases Security Funding, Citing Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 17 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The orders are for disposable cuffs, gas masks, ballistic helmets, riot gloves, and equipment for federal police assigned to Veterans Affairs facilities.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/17/veterans-affairs-coronavirus-security-police/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Huge, Mysterious List Appears Online of Where People Met, Personal Information and More of Tens of Millions</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>May 15 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['There's nothing you nor I can do about it,' notes security expert]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/data-dump-personal-information-breach-crm-a9515931.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Stealth Bailout' Shovels Millions of Dollars to Oil Companies</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>May 15 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As it headed toward bankruptcy, Diamond Offshore Drilling Inc. took advantage of a little-noticed provision in the stimulus bill Congress passed in March to get a $9.7 million tax refund. Then, it asked a bankruptcy judge to authorize the same amount as bonuses to nine executives.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-05-15/-stealth-bailout-shovels-millions-of-dollars-to-oil-companies</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Government Proposed Manipulating CDC Guidelines to Avoid Mask Shortages: Whistleblower</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 15 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. government proposed manipulating information about whether N95 masks worked to fight the spread of coronavirus in the general public, according to Dr. Richard Bright, a whistleblower who testified publicly for the first time on Thursday. The deception was an effort to avoid shortages and ke…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-government-proposed-manipulating-cdc-guidelines-to-1843474820</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Whistleblower: Wall Street Has Engaged in Widespread Manipulation of Mortgage Funds</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>May 15 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Securities that contain loans for properties like hotels and office buildings have inflated profits, the whistleblower claims. As the pandemic hammers the economy, that could increase the chances of another mortgage collapse.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/whistleblower-wall-street-has-engaged-in-widespread-manipulation-of-mortgage-funds</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Senate Votes to Reauthorize FBI Surveillance Powers, With a Few Worthwhile Tweaks</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 14 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In an 80-16 vote on Thursday, the U.S. Senate passed a bill to restore controversial surveillance tools used by the FBI in terrorism and espionage investigations. But the bill has at least one more hurdle to jump thanks to a series of changes implemented yesterday.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/senate-votes-to-reauthorize-fbi-surveillance-powers-wi-1843466933</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Struggling Oil Companies Are Taking Advantage of US Coronavirus Aid</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 14 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Recent review finds at least $113m in taxpayer-backed loans meant for small businesses have gone to fossil fuel industry]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/may/14/us-oil-gas-companies-coronavirus-relief-loan-ppp</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Senate Passes Spying Bill Without Search and Browsing History Protections</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 14 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An amendment protecting search and browsing histories failed in a 59-37 vote.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/05/limits-on-fbi-access-to-search-histories-fails-by-one-senate-vote/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In a First, Renewable Energy Is Poised to Eclipse Coal in U.S.</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The coronavirus has pushed the coal industry to once-unthinkable lows, and the consequences for climate change are big.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/13/climate/coronavirus-coal-electricity-renewables.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Shot and Killed a 26-Year-Old EMT in Her Apartment While Looking for Someone Else Entirely</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Breonna Taylor had no criminal record, and police found no drugs in her home.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/qj44wv/what-we-know-about-breonna-taylor-lousiville-kentucky-emt-police-shooting-death</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FBI Accuses China of Attempting to Steal US COVID-19 Research</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The FBI warns that China-backed hackers are attempting to steal COVID-19 research from organizations in the US.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/fbi-cisa-accuse-china-covid-19-research-hacking-194610071.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Here's Who Just Voted to Let the FBI Seize Your Online Search History Without a Warrant</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A bipartisan amendment that would have prohibited law enforcement agencies, such as the FBI, from obtaining the web browsing and internet search histories of Americans without a warrant failed to pass in the U.S. Senate on Wednesday by a single vote.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/heres-who-just-voted-to-let-the-f-b-i-seize-your-searc-1843445032</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Alzheimer's–Air Pollution Link</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Toxic airborne particles can travel from lungs and nose to the brain, and exposure is linked to memory loss]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-new-alzheimers-air-pollution-link/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Warns That Chinese Hackers Are Targeting Virus Research</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hackers working for the Chinese government are trying to steal valuable research on coronavirus vaccines and treatments from U.S. health care, pharmaceutical and research organizations, the FBI and the Department of Homeland Security warned Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-05-13/u-s-warns-of-chinese-hackers-targeting-virus-research-groups</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Your Boss Is Watching You: Work-From-Home Boom Leads to More Surveillance</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>May 13 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[With more people now working from home, employers are increasingly relying on tracking software to monitor what employees do when they're on the clock.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/2020/05/13/854014403/your-boss-is-watching-you-work-from-home-boom-leads-to-more-surveillance</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Oil's Climate Plans Don't Come Close to Meeting the Paris Agreement</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Climate action plans are all the rage for polluting companies. Last month, Shell pledged to reach net-zero carbon emissions by 2050. It's just the latest example: Other oil giants have recently made similar pledges as well. These pronouncements use pseudo-inspirational marketing speak, promising to …]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/big-oils-climate-plans-dont-come-close-to-meeting-the-p-1843418530</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID-19 Resurges in Reopened Countries; Wuhan Sees First Cluster in a Month</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[China ordered all Wuhan residents get tested for COVID-19—that's ~11 million people.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/covid-19-resurges-in-reopened-countries-wuhan-sees-first-cluster-in-a-month/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Federal Whistleblower Says Boss Pushed Him to Buy Drugs That Hadn't Been Tested in Humans</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Rick Bright's complaint points to the influence of industry over the Trump administration's coronavirus response.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/12/richard-bright-barda-coronavirus-whistleblower/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>That Fresh Sea Breeze You Breathe May Be Laced With Microplastic</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers have discovered that the ocean is burping tiny plastic particles, which then blow onto land—and potentially into your lungs.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/sea-breeze-microplastic/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Online Voting Has Worked So Far. That Doesn't Mean It's Safe</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Proponents of mobile and internet voting point to its uneventful track record. That's not good enough.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/online-voting-worked-so-far-doesnt-mean-safe/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Large Chunks of a Chinese Rocket Missed New York City by About 15 Minutes</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[China's Long March 5B rocket launched without a second stage.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/large-chunks-of-a-chinese-rocket-missed-new-york-city-by-about-15-minutes/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Much Is a Human Life Actually Worth?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 11 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the US economy reopens amid a deadly pandemic, a dire question looms. Let's weigh the risks—and do the math.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-is-human-life-worth-in-dollars/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Bailout Is Working — for the Rich</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>May 10 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The economy is in free fall but Wall Street is thriving, and stocks of big private equity firms are soaring dramatically higher. That tells you who investors think is the real beneficiary of the federal government's massive rescue efforts.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/the-bailout-is-working-for-the-rich</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pandemic Is Bringing Back Single-Use Plastics in a Huge Way</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 09 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[States are rolling back their plastic bag bans and restaurants are turning to single-use utensils to reopen in the face of the coronavirus pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/n7wja8/the-pandemic-is-bringing-back-single-use-plastics-in-a-huge-way</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>At Least $72 Million in Coronavirus Bailout Loans Went to Big Oil and Gas Companies</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least 16 drillers, fuel transporters, oil technology firms and service providers tapped the Small Business Association's Paycheck Protection Program.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/v7g4w3/millions-in-small-business-coronavirus-bailout-loans-are-going-to-oil-and-gas-companies</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With a Distracted Public, the Pentagon Tries to Get Away With Killing Innocent Civilians</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Pentagon's annual report to Congress covering civilian casualties appears to be yet another case of woefully underreporting innocent deaths.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/08/civilian-casualties-us-airstrikes-pentagon/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Marshals Says Prisoners' Personal Information Taken in Data Breach</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Current and former prisoners were notified of the breach on May 1.]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/08/us-marshals-prisoner-data-breach/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Unemployment Just Hit Its Highest Level Since the Great Depression</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The American job market is in full-on meltdown.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/n7wjpd/us-unemployment-just-hit-its-highest-level-since-the-great-depression-15-percent-coronavirus</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>For Cops Who Kill, Special Supreme Court Protection</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. high court's continual refinement of an obscure doctrine called qualified immunity has made it harder to hold police liable for excessive force.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-police-immunity-scotus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An Oil Spill and the Coronavirus Are Creating a Crisis in Ecuador's Amazon</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 08 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Imagine being told to shelter at home due to a global pandemic, only to have your home, drinking water, and food stores destroyed. It would be a nightmare, but that is exactly what happened for indigenous people in the Ecuadorian Amazon after a massive oil spill polluted two major rivers.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/an-oil-spill-and-the-coronavirus-are-creating-a-crisis-1843338899</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CDC Guide to Reopening Was Trashed by the Trump Admin. It Just Leaked</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 07 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trump admin allegedly told CDC its reopening guide would 'never see the light of day.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/cdc-guide-to-reopening-was-trashed-by-the-trump-admin-it-just-leaked/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Are Tenants on Our Own Devices</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 20 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's time to assert our sovereignty over our own stuff.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/right-to-repair-tenants-on-our-own-devices/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Whistleblower Details How HHS Officials Refused to Secure N95 Masks as Pandemic Loomed</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 07 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The report from Richard Bright reveals a new villain in the tragic saga of the administration's mismanagement of the coronavirus crisis: Robert Kadlec.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/07/coronavirus-whistleblower-hhs-n95-ppe/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Farmers Are Destroying Mountains of Food. Here's What to Do About It</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 07 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Covid-19 pandemic has revealed the cracks in a corporate-focused system supported by polices that favor profits at any cost]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/may/07/farmers-food-covid-19</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prisons Will Worsen Coronavirus Crisis in Rural America</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 07 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The prison economy has been a lifeline for rural communities for decades, but that lifeline has transformed into a vector for coronavirus.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/07/coronavirus-america-rural-prisons/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We've Known How to Make Healthier Buildings for Decades</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>May 07 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[During the pandemic, people are now demanding them.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/7/21249496/building-ventilation-design-health-humidity-cost</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nearly 20,000 Teens in Georgia Have Received Their Driver's Licenses Without a Road Test</title>
			<source>CNN</source>
			<pubDate>May 06 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Georgia isn't the only state that is waiving road tests. Wisconsin announced this week that it will start doing the same for 16- and 17-year-olds, starting Monday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/06/us/driver-license-road-test-wisconsin-georgia-trnd/index.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Here Are the Companies Getting Rich From the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 06 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scott Disick, of 'Keeping Up With the Kardashians' fame, pushed out a line of T-shirts and hoodies emblazoned with the timely message 'Wash Your Hands.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/akzw7p/here-are-the-companies-getting-rich-from-the-coronavirus-pandemic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mass Incarceration Poses a Uniquely American Risk in the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 06 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The virus has exposed just how deadly prisons and jails are for incarcerated people, and for society at large.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/06/coronavirus-prison-jail-mass-incarceration/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Companies Cut Thousands of Workers While Continuing to Reward Shareholders During Pandemic</title>
			<source>Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the pandemic squeezes big companies, executives are making decisions about who will bear the brunt of the sacrifices, and in at least some cases, workers have been the first to lose, even as shareholders continue to collect.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/05/05/dividends-layoffs-coronavirus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Speaker Pelosi Supports Push for Taxpayer Bailout of Corporate Lobbyists</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trade groups have stepped up a campaign for $25 billion and PPP eligibility in the next phase of coronavirus relief.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/05/lobbyists-trade-groups-bailout/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>America's Renewable Energy Sources Have Produced More Electricity Than Coal Every Day for 40 Days Straight</title>
			<source>Newsweek</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The transition away from coal for electricity generation in the U.S. accelerated in 2020 due to lower gas prices, warmer weather and the economic conditions resulting from COVID-19, analysis found.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newsweek.com/america-renewable-energy-electricity-generation-tops-coal-plants-april-2020-40-days-1501967</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An AI Can Simulate an Economy Millions of Times to Create Fairer Tax Policy</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Deep reinforcement learning has trained AIs to beat humans at complex games like Go and StarCraft. Could it also do a better job at running the economy?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/05/05/1001142/ai-reinforcement-learning-simulate-economy-fairer-tax-policy-income-inequality-recession-pandemic/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.K. Reports Highest Coronavirus Death Toll in Europe</title>
			<source>Axios</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It surpassed Italy.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-united-kingdom-most-deaths-europe-50220ebe-12df-487b-bb9d-699eb03c4c50.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jared Kushner's Shadow Coronavirus Task Force Used a Spreadsheet Called 'VIP Update' to Procure PPE From Inexperienced Trump Allies Over Legitimate Vendors</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>May 05 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In theory, the group was supposed to find the most promising leads on protective gear and funnel them to FEMA. Instead, it prioritized Trump allies.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/jared-kushner-coronavirus-task-force-prioritized-ppe-trump-associates-nyt-2020-5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Projects 200,000 New COVID-19 Cases per Day, 3,000 Daily Deaths by June</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Leaked gov't document predicts rise in deaths as Trump aims to 'open up America.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/05/us-projects-200000-new-covid-19-cases-per-day-3000-daily-deaths-by-june/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Three Russian Doctors Fall From Hospital Windows, Raising Questions Amid Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
			<source>CNN</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three frontline health care workers have mysteriously fallen out of hospital windows in Russia over the past two weeks, heightening public attention to the working conditions for doctors and medical professionals amid the coronavirus pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/04/europe/russia-medical-workers-windows-intl/index.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World Came Together for a Virtual Vaccine Summit. The U.S. Was Conspicuously Absent.</title>
			<source>Washington Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[International donors are on track to raise $8.2 billion to mass-produce drugs, vaccines and testing kits. The Trump administration says the U.S. remains the world's largest health and humanitarian donor.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/the-world-comes-together-for-a-virtual-vaccine-summit-the-us-is-conspicuously-absent/2020/05/04/ac5b6754-8a5c-11ea-80df-d24b35a568ae_story.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Many Jobs Do Robots Really Replace?</title>
			<source>MIT News</source>
			<pubDate>May 03 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[MIT economist Daron Acemoglu's new research puts a number on the job costs of automation.]]></description>
			<link>http://news.mit.edu/2020/how-many-jobs-robots-replace-0504</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hostile States Trying to Steal Coronavirus Research, Says UK Agency</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 03 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Experts say Russia, Iran and China likely to be behind cyber-attacks on universities]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/may/03/hostile-states-trying-to-steal-coronavirus-research-says-uk-agency</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Store Guard Killed After Mask Row With Customer</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>May 02 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Michigan store guard is shot in the back of the head after confronting a customer who had no mask.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52540266</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Thinks Backlash to Its Coronavirus Response Could Lead to All-Out War With the U.S.</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A State Security report warned that anti-China sentiment, led by the U.S., has not been this high since the 1989 Tiananmen Square crackdown.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/wxeww4/china-thinks-backlash-to-its-coronavirus-response-could-lead-to-all-out-war-with-the-us</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Which States Are Reopening, Which Remain on Lockdown, and Why</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There's not a national plan to restart US businesses. That's led to inconsistencies among governors' orders, and some confusion among residents.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/which-states-reopening-lockdown/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Medical Expert: Federal Jail Intentionally Destroying Medical Records and Hiding Extent of Coronavirus Behind Bars</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['Several current practices in MDC actually promote a more rapid spread of COVID-19 inside the facility.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/01/mdc-brooklyn-jail-coronavirus-medical-records/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Donald Trump's Four-Step Plan to Reopen the US Economy – and Why It Will Be Lethal</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 03 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The president and his allies are hiding the facts and pretending 'freedom' conquers all. As a result, more Americans will die]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/may/03/donald-trump-reopen-us-economy-lethal-robert-reich</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White House Blocks Fauci From Testifying to Congress on Coronavirus Response</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 02 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Top U.S. health official Anthony Fauci will not testify next week to a congressional committee examining the Trump administration's response to the coronavirus pandemic, the White House said on Friday, calling it 'counterproductive' to have individuals involved in the response testify.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-usa-fauci/white-house-blocks-fauci-from-testifying-to-congress-on-coronavirus-response-idUSKBN22E03O</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World Is Still Producing More Oil Than It Needs. Why?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Today, petroleum producers around the world will start shutting down wells after the Covid-19 pandemic caused demand to plummet. What took them so long?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-is-still-producing-more-oil-than-it-needs-why/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Judge Orders FCC to Hand Over IP Addresses Linked to Fake Net Neutrality Comments</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Manhattan federal judge has ruled the Federal Communications Commission must provide two reporters access to server logs that may provide new insight into the allegations of fraud stemming from agency's 2017 net neutrality rollback.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/judge-orders-fcc-to-hand-over-ip-addresses-linked-to-fa-1843202071</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Congress Is Investigating Cruise Ship Company Carnival Over COVID-19 Outbreaks</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Carnival is accused of failing to take action when it knew the risks of the novel coronavirus.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/1/21244432/carnival-princess-cruises-congress-investigation-covid-19-coronavirus-outbreak</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Warns Australia It Could Face Boycotts Over Call for an Independent Inquiry Into Coronavirus</title>
			<source>Time</source>
			<pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[China has accused Australia of parroting the United States in its call for an inquiry independent of the WHO to determine the origins of COVID-19.]]></description>
			<link>https://time.com/5830675/china-australia-coronavirus-inquiry/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jobs Collapse Is Deeper Than the Government Says</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Economists' workforce surveys are more current than the government's. And more terrifying.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2020-04-30/jobs-collapse-is-deeper-than-the-government-says</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>People With Guns (And No Masks) Swarmed the Michigan State Capitol to Protest the Coronavirus Lockdown</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Some state legislators, anticipating the possibility of violence, had even come to work that day wearing bulletproof vests.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/y3makv/protestors-with-guns-and-no-masks-swarmed-the-michigan-state-capitol-to-protest-the-coronavirus-lockdown</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Microplastic Hot Spots' Are Tainting Deep-Sea Ecosystems</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists found 2 million microplastic particles in a square meter of sediment, as currents drag debris into seafloor versions of the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-hotspots/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pence Threatened to Punish the Reporter Who Proved His Office Ignored the Rule That He Needed a Mask to Visit the Mayo Clinic</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Steve Herman undermined Pence's wife's claim that the vice president didn't know he was supposed to wear a mask during the much-criticized visit.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/pence-threatened-reporter-proved-knew-mayo-clinic-mask-rule-2020-5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It Could Take Decades for the Ocean Floor to Recover From Deep Sea Mining</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new study has found that the impacts of deep sea mining are still felt a quarter of a century later.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/it-could-take-decades-for-the-ocean-floor-to-recover-fr-1843162892</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Stocks Are Recovering While the Economy Collapses. That Makes More Sense Than You'd Think.</title>
			<source>Time</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[While the economy is contracting, the market is soaring. If you look closely at what's up and down, it actually makes sense--for now.]]></description>
			<link>https://time.com/5828898/stocks-recovering-economy-collapses-makes-sense/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google Play Has Been Spreading Advanced Android Malware for Years</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Advanced hacker group seeded market with at least 8 apps likely since 2016.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/04/sophisticated-android-backdoors-have-been-populating-google-play-for-years/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pandemic Is Accelerating Coal's Demise</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Electricity in Europe, India, China, and parts of the U.S. is less and less reliant on coal.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-28/the-coronavirus-pandemic-is-accelerating-coal-s-demise</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Inside the Race to Build the Best Quantum Computer on Earth</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 26 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Google's most advanced computer isn't at the company's headquarters in Mountain View, California, nor anywhere in the febrile sprawl of Silicon Valley. It's a few hours' drive south in Santa Barbara, in a flat, soulless office park inhabited mostly by technology firms you've never heard of. An open-…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/02/26/916744/quantum-computer-race-ibm-google/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
