<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>2Axoh_6fu1NXfcZdMxSZX</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon Mar 08 2021 11:49:24 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>The Accellion Breach Keeps Getting Worse — and More Expensive</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What started as a few vulnerabilities in firewall equipment has snowballed into a global extortion spree.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/accellion-breach-victims-extortion/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>For Our Own Good, We All Need a Glimpse of the Evil Queen</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I had a client many years ago who was a real-life version of Sleeping Beauty. She was tall, blonde-haired, razor thin (as the saying goes), and profoundly unhappy. She was enrolled in a local junio…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/03/07/for-our-own-good-we-all-need-a-glimpse-of-the-evil-queen/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chinese, Russian Hackers Reportedly Stole European Vaccine Data</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Both China and Russia were reportedly behind two cyberattacks last year at the European Medicines Agency that compromised documents related to covid-19 vaccines and treatments.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/chinese-and-russian-hackers-reportedly-stole-vaccine-da-1846426656</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Tell Which Emails Quietly Track You</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Your emails know more about you than you might think, like when you open them or when you forward them to others. But you can reclaim your privacy.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-tell-which-emails-track-you/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This Rapid 3D-Printing Method Could Be the Secret to Developing 3D-Printed Organs</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We may not have flying cars yet, but 3D-printed organs? That sci-fi fantasy just got one step closer to reality thanks to a rapid 3D-printing method developed by University of Buffalo engineers.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/this-rapid-3d-printing-method-could-be-the-secret-to-de-1846424035</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A North Carolina Pipeline Caused the Biggest Gas Spill in Decades</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A slowly-unfolding, little-reported-on saga in North Carolina involves a company controlled by the Koch brothers and Shell, and a pipeline that has been transporting dirty energy for decades. And it has implications for pipelines everywhere across the U.S.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/one-of-the-nation-s-largest-pipelines-caused-the-bigges-1846406684</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's and Russia's Spying Sprees Will Take Years to Unpack</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Full extent of SolarWinds hack, Hafnium's attack on Exchange Server may never be known.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/03/chinas-and-russias-spying-spree-will-take-years-to-unpack/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World Wastes 1 Billion Tons of Food a Year, and It's Frying the Planet</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you've ever overstuffed your fridge and let some leftovers go bad in the back of it, you're not alone. People toss more than 1 billion tons of food in the trash every year, according to a new United Nations report. But it doesn't have to be this way.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/our-wasted-food-is-fueling-climate-change-1846414880</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Under Intense Pressure, WHO Skips Summary Report on Coronavirus Origin</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The full report, however, is expected the week of March 15.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/under-intense-pressure-who-skips-summary-report-on-coronavirus-origin/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chinese Hacking Spree Hit an 'Astronomical' Number of Victims</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A single group appears to have infiltrated tens of thousands of Microsoft Exchange servers in an ongoing onslaught.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/china-microsoft-exchange-server-hack-victims/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Just Looted Passenger Data From Some of the Biggest Airlines</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The breach may have not exposed incredibly personal details, but it reveals the data third parties collect.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/hackers-just-looted-passenger-data-from-some-of-the-wor-1846417692</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>At Least 30,000 U.S. Organizations Newly Hacked via Holes in Microsoft's Email Software</title>
			<source>Krebs on Security</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least 30,000 organizations across the United States -- including a significant number of small businesses, towns, cities and local governments -- have over the past few days been hacked by an unusually aggressive Chinese cyber espionage unit that's focused on stealing email from victim organizati…]]></description>
			<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/03/at-least-30000-u-s-organizations-newly-hacked-via-holes-in-microsofts-email-software/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Poison the Data That Big Tech Uses to Surveil You</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Algorithms are meaningless without good data. The public can exploit that to demand change.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/03/05/1020376/resist-big-tech-surveillance-data/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>As the Insurrection Narrative Crumbles, Democrats Cling to It More Desperately Than Ever</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If the threat of 'armed insurrectionists' and 'domestic terrorists' is as great as some claim, why do they have to keep lying and peddling crude media fictions about it?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/as-the-insurrection-narrative-crumbles</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dr. Seuss Books Deemed Offensive Will Be Delisted From eBay</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[EBay is working to prevent the resale of six Dr. Seuss books pulled this week by the company in charge of the late author's works because they contain offensive imagery.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/dr-seuss-books-deemed-offensive-will-be-delisted-from-ebay-11614884201</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Cephalopod Has Passed a Cognitive Test Designed for Human Children</title>
			<source>ScienceAlert</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new test of cephalopod smarts has reinforced how important it is for us humans to not underestimate animal intelligence.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.sciencealert.com/cuttlefish-can-pass-a-cognitive-test-designed-for-children</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ancient Memorization Trick Boosts Long-Term Memory, Changes the Brain</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A mnemonic, called the 'method of loci,' has been around for centuries, and it's surprisingly effective for memorizing things. New research published in Science Advances on Wednesday suggests it is good for both short-term memory and also long-term recall.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/ancient-memorization-trick-boosts-long-term-memory-and-1846398066</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mars: NASA's Perseverance Rover Sends Stunning Images</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Amazing images as Nasa's Perseverance rover lands on Mars and seeks signs of past microbial life.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/in-pictures-56238018</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's 'Sharp Eyes' Program Aims to Surveil 100% of Public Space</title>
			<source>Medium</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The program turns neighbors into agents of the surveillance state]]></description>
			<link>https://onezero.medium.com/chinas-sharp-eyes-program-aims-to-surveil-100-of-public-space-ddc22d63e015</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Gets 'C-,' Faces $2.59 Trillion in Infrastructure Needs Over 10 Years: Report</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States faces a $2.59 trillion shortfall in infrastructure needs that requires a massive jump in government spending to address crumbling roads, bridges and other programs, according to an assessment by an engineers group issued on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-infrastructure-idUSKBN2AV0DD</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kids Are Being Exposed to a Lot of Concerning Chemicals Through Plastic Toys</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Children's toys contain many potentially toxic chemicals, recent research suggests. The study highlights over 120 concerning chemicals commonly found in plastic toys that could possibly raise a person's risk of health problems, including cancer.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/kids-are-being-exposed-to-a-lot-of-concerning-chemicals-1846383124</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Food Prices Are Soaring Faster Than Inflation and Incomes</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the Covid-19 pandemic wreaks havoc on economic growth, concerns about hunger and malnutrition are rising around the world.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-01/inflation-2021-malnutrition-and-hunger-fears-rise-as-food-prices-soar-globally</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Atlantic Currents Seem to Have Started Fading Last Century</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Another predicted impact of climate change may be here.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/02/atlantic-currents-seem-to-have-started-fading-last-century/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Evolutionary Advantages of Playing Victim</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Victimhood is defined in negative terms: 'the condition of having been hurt, damaged, or made to suffer.' Yet humans have evolved to empathize with the suffering of others, and to provide assistanc…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/27/the-evolutionary-advantages-of-playing-victim/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Tied to Russia's GRU Targeted the US Grid for Years</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sandworm-aligned group has breached US critical infrastructure a handful of times.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/02/hackers-tied-to-russias-gru-targeted-the-us-grid-for-years/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saudi De Facto Ruler Approved Operation That Led to Khashoggi's Death: U.S.</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[FILE PHOTO: The Committee to Protect Journalists and other press freedom activists hold a candlelight vigil in front of the Saudi Embassy to mark the anniversary of the killing of journalist Jamal Kha]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/news/picture/saudi-crown-prince-approved-khashoggi-mu-idUSKBN2AQ2OC</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Erik Prince and the Failed Plot to Arm a CIA Asset-Turned-Warlord in Libya</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sources and exclusive documents reveal new details about Prince's long campaign to back Libyan strongman Khalifa Hifter.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/26/erik-prince-jordan-libya-weapons-opus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sen. John Thune, Opposing $15 Min Wage, Says He Earned $6 as a Kid — That's $24 With Inflation</title>
			<source>Newsweek</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I started working by bussing tables at the Star Family Restaurant for $1/hour & slowly moved up to cook—the big leagues for a kid like me—to earn $6/hour,' Thune wrote.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newsweek.com/sen-john-thune-opposing-15-min-wage-says-he-earned-6-kidthats-24-inflation-1571915</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazon Rainforest Plots Sold via Facebook Marketplace Ads</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Protected land reserved for Brazil's indigenous communities is being traded on the social network.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56168844</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Is the Woke Mob So Scared?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The no-platforming of yet another academic raises uncomfortable questions about free speech]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/02/why-is-the-woke-mob-so-scared/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Problem With 'Indigenizing the University'</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The idea that academics need to 'Indigenize' the Canadian education system has become popular in recent years. The Congress of the Humanities and Social Sciences, the Canadian Association of Univer…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/24/the-problem-with-indigenizing-the-university/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Quantum Computer Just Solved a Decades-Old Problem Three Million Times Faster Than a Classical Computer</title>
			<source>ZDNet</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Using a method called quantum annealing, D-Wave's researchers demonstrated that a quantum computational advantage could be achieved over classical means.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/a-quantum-computer-just-solved-a-decades-old-problem-three-million-times-faster-than-a-classical-computer/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Musk: Starlink Will Hit 300Mbps and Expand to 'Most of Earth' This Year</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX CEO teases higher speeds, lower latency, and near-global coverage.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/02/musk-starlink-will-hit-300mbps-and-expand-to-most-of-earth-this-year/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Major Ocean Current May Be Hurtling Towards Collapse</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ocean may have less time than we thought before massive, irreversible shifts take place. A new study finds that a crucial ocean system may reach its 'tipping point' sooner than predicted if the rate of climate change continues at a breakneck pace.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/a-major-ocean-current-may-be-hurtling-towards-collapse-1846337333</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fossil Fuel Executives Gloat About Profits, PR From Texas Winter Storm Crisis</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Comstock Resources, a shale drilling company, apologized for describing gas prices from the Texas storm as a 'jackpot.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/23/texas-winter-storm-gas-prices-executives/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>House Democrats, Targeting Right-Wing Cable Outlets, Are Assaulting Core Press Freedoms</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Democrats' justification for silencing their adversaries online and in media -- 'they are spreading fake news and inciting extremism' -- is what despots everywhere say.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/house-democrats-targeting-right-wing</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Even by Democratic Party Standards, Censoring Fox News Is an Insanely Stupid Idea</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How will the latest campaign against 'misinformation' backfire for the country? Let's count the ways]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/i-cant-stand-fox-news-but-censoring-94b</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Garden-Variety Germs May Explode in COVID's Wake, Study Suggests</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In coronavirus's wake, garden-variety germs may come roaring back.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/02/covid-precautions-no-match-for-the-common-cold-and-its-ready-for-a-comeback/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Also Went After NASA and the FAA</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Apparently not content with having penetrated the networks of such piddling federal agencies as the U.S. State Department, the Department of Homeland Security, and that agency that maintains our nuclear stockpile, the hackers of the 'SolarWinds' affair also went after NASA and the Federal Aviatio…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/solarwinds-hackers-also-went-after-nasa-and-the-faa-1846340394</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Student Surveillance Vendor Proctorio Files SLAPP Lawsuit to Silence a Critic</title>
			<source>Electronic Frontier Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[During the pandemic, a dangerous business has prospered: invading students' privacy with proctoring software and apps. In the last year, we've seen universities compel students to download apps that collect their face images, driver's license data, and network information. Students who want to move.…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/02/student-surveillance-vendor-proctorio-files-slapp-lawsuit-silence-critic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Humans Had Never Seen a Spacecraft Land on Another Planet—Until Now</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I can, and have, watched those videos for hours.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/02/humans-had-never-seen-a-spacecraft-land-on-another-planet-until-now/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unreal Video of Perseverance Landing on Mars Will Take Your Breath Away</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[NASA has released stunning footage of the Perseverance rover landing on Mars, in what is a seminal achievement for the space agency.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/unreal-video-of-perseverance-landing-on-mars-will-take-1846328878</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazon Rainforest Fires Got Even Worse Last Year</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[NASA spotted more severe fires from space.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295437/amazon-rainforest-fires-worse-2020</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>500,000 Lives Lost</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The scale of the COVID-19 death toll in the United States]]></description>
			<link>https://graphics.reuters.com/HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS/USA-CASUALTIES-CHRONOLOGY/xklpyomnrpg/index.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Hijacked an NSA Hacking Tool — and Used It for Years</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The hackers used the agency's EpMe exploit to attack Windows devices years before the Shadow Brokers leaked the agency's zero-day arsenal online.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/china-nsa-hacking-tool-epme-hijack/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thinking Critically About Critical Thinking</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Michael J. Fox, the third president of the United States, was responsible for establishing Presbyterianism as the state religion of the new federation after its peaceful secession from the English …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/20/thinking-critically-about-critical-thinking/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Ripple Effect of Loss: U.S. Covid Deaths Approach 500,000</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Twice as many Americans have died as early worst-case projections.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/21/us/coronavirus-deaths-us-half-a-million.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Are Sperm Telling Us?</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists are concerned by falling sperm counts and declining egg quality. Endocrine-disrupting chemicals may be the problem.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/20/opinion/sunday/endocrine-disruptors-sperm.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists Find a Way to Communicate With Dreaming People</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The veil between dreamworld and reality may be thinner than we thought. In a new study released Thursday, scientists in four countries say they've shown it's possible to communicate with people while they're lucid dreaming. At least some of the time, the dreamers were reportedly able to respond to y…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/scientists-find-a-way-to-communicate-with-dreaming-peop-1846292025</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White House Now Says 100 Companies Hit by SolarWinds Hack, but More May Be Impacted</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The attack is 'likely of Russian origin']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288961/solarwinds-hack-100-companies-9-federal-agencies</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Data Breach Warning After California DMV Contractor Hit by File-Stealing Ransomware</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A file-stealing ransomware group claimed responsibility for the hack, and said it will sell the stolen data.]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/california-motor-vehicles-afts-ransomware/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Charges Three North Koreans in $1.3 Billion Hacking Spree</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States has charged three North Korean computer programmers with a massive hacking spree aimed at stealing more than $1.3 billion in money and cryptocurrency, affecting companies from banks to Hollywood movie studios, the Department of Justice said on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-northkorea-cyber-idUSKBN2AH2B5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prisons Are Skimming Big Chunks of CARES Act Stimulus Checks</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A September court ruling promised incarcerated people their slice of the federal stimulus. Some prisons still took a cut.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/17/stimulus-checks-cares-prisons-skimming-irs/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Haven't Seen a Quarter of Known Bee Species Since the 1990s</title>
			<source>National Geographic</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A sweeping analysis shows an overall downward trend in bee diversity worldwide, raising concerns about these crucial pollinators.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/we-havent-seen-quarter-of-known-bee-species-since-1990s</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Congress Escalates Pressure on Tech Giants to Censor More, Threatening the First Amendment</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In their zeal for control over online speech, House Democrats are getting closer and closer to the constitutional line, if they have not already crossed it.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/congress-escalates-pressure-on-tech</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Stay Calm Everyone, There's Prozac in the Drinking Water</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 2, 2017</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It should make us happy, but environmentalists are deeply alarmed: Prozac, the anti-depression drug, is being taken in such large quantities that it can now be found in Britain's drinking water.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2004/aug/08/health.mentalhealth</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Protection of Murderous Saudi Despots Shows the Hidden Reality of U.S. Foreign Policy</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 2, 2001</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[That the U.S. opposes tyranny is a glaring myth. Yet it is not only believed but often used to justify wars, bombing campaigns, sanctions, and protracted conflict.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/bidens-protection-of-murderous-saudi</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After Pork Giant Was Exposed for Cruel Killings, the FBI Pursued Its Critics</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The agency, seeking information on an animal rights group, attempted to recruit a former truck driver as an informant, the truck driver says.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/17/fbi-iowa-select-pigs-whistleblower/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Targets Rare Earth Export Curbs to Hobble US Defense Industry</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Beijing asks industry executives if proposed restrictions will harm western contractors.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/02/china-targets-rare-earth-export-curbs-to-hobble-us-defense-industry/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'New Car Smell' Is the Scent of Carcinogens, and Even Short Trips May Overexpose Us</title>
			<source>ScienceAlert</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The average American spends almost one hour each day commuting to work, a number that adds up quickly.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.sciencealert.com/a-20-minute-commute-puts-you-at-risk-of-unacceptably-high-levels-of-carcinogens</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What the New York Times' Hit Piece on Slate Star Codex Says About Media Gatekeeping</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['Silicon Valley's Safe Space' has misinformed readers.]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/02/15/what-the-new-york-times-hit-piece-on-slate-star-codex-says-about-media-gatekeeping/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fake Amazon Reviews 'Being Sold in Bulk' Online</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Which? investigation found 10 sites offering fake Amazon Marketplace reviews from as little as £5 each.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-56069472</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With a Star Science Reporter's Purging, Mob Culture at the New York Times Enters a Strange New Phase</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Speaking recently at a Quillette Free Thought Lives event, Columbia University professor John McWhorter expounded on his thesis that social justice comprises an ersatz religion, complete with rites…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/09/with-a-star-science-reporters-purging-mob-culture-at-the-new-york-times-enters-a-strange-new-phase/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Untold History of America's Zero-Day Market</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The lucrative business of dealing in code vulnerabilities is central to espionage and war planning, which is why brokers never spoke about it—until now.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/untold-history-americas-zero-day-market/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White House Cites 'Deep Concerns' About WHO COVID Report, Demands Early Data From China</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The White House on Saturday called on China to make available data from the earliest days of the COVID-19 outbreak, saying it has 'deep concerns' about the way the findings of the World Health Organization's COVID-19 report were communicated.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-usa-idUSKBN2AD0FX</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Billions in Pandemic Aid Was Swindled by Con Artists and Crime Syndicates</title>
			<source>NBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A senior federal law enforcement source said the fraud is so complex and multilayered that it will take months to develop a full accounting.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/how-billions-pandemic-aid-was-swindled-con-artists-crime-syndicates-n1257766</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers, Mason Jars, and the Psychedelic Science of DIY Shrooms</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The history of home cultivation methods of Psilocybe is more connected to early internet culture than you'd think.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/hackers-mason-jars-psychedelic-science-diy-shrooms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>LA Cops Tried Using Instagram's Copyright Filter to Stop Someone From Filming Them</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over the last several weeks, police in Beverly Hills have been caught on video seemingly trying to weaponize Instagram's copyright detection algorithms to get a prominent LA activist banned from the platform.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/beverly-hills-police-instagram-copyright-232013882.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Making the Profane Sacred</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['By making a statute and by defining blasphemy, the church sought to prevent discussion—sought to prevent argument—sought to prevent a man giving his honest opinion. Certainly a tenet, a dogma, a d…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/11/making-the-profane-sacred/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Long Hack: How China Exploited a U.S. Tech Supplier</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For years, U.S. investigators found tampering in products made by Super Micro Computer Inc. The company says it was never told. Neither was the public.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2021-supermicro/#</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Refuses to Give WHO Raw Data on Early Covid-19 Cases</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[WHO investigators said Chinese authorities wouldn't give them personalized data that could help them determine how and when the coronavirus first began to spread in China.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/china-refuses-to-give-who-raw-data-on-early-covid-19-cases-11613150580</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unspeakable Truths About Racial Inequality in America</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This is the text of a lecture delivered by the author as part of the Benson Center Lecture Series at the University of Colorado, Boulder, on February 8th, 2021. I am a black American intellectual l…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/10/unspeakable-truths-about-racial-inequality-in-america/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MIT Researchers Created a System That Prints Functional Drones and Robots</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[LaserFactory cuts out a shape, then adds circuitry and components.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/mit-laserfactory-system-drones-robots-electronics-150215803.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mediocrity Is Now Mandatory</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From stimulus to school admissions, leaders act as if ease is the only worthy goal.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/mediocrity-is-now-mandatory-11612724198</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beating Back Cancel Culture: A Case Study From the Field of Artificial Intelligence</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's easy to decry cancel culture, but hard to turn it back. Thankfully, recent developments in my area of academic specialty—artificial intelligence (AI)—show that fighting cancel culture isn't im…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/27/beating-back-cancel-culture-a-case-study-from-the-field-of-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Journalistic Tattletale and Censorship Industry Suffers Several Well-Deserved Blows</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The NYT's Taylor Lorenz falsely accuses a tech investor of using a slur after spending months trying to infiltrate and monitor a new app that allows free conversation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-journalistic-tattletale-and-censorship</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Uighurs: 'Credible Case' China Carrying Out Genocide</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A legal opinion concludes the Chinese government has shown an intent to destroy the Uighur minority.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-55973215</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wuhan Residents Remember Coronavirus 'Whistleblower' Doctor a Year After His Death</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A year after his death from COVID-19, residents in the Chinese city of Wuhan say they remain grateful to the 'whistleblower' doctor who first sounded the alarm about the outbreak before it received official recognition.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/reutersComService_2_MOLT/idUSKBN2A60AK</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Plans Starlink Phone Service, Emergency Backup, and Low-Income Access</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX's latest petition to the FCC details some of its Starlink plans.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/02/spacex-plans-starlink-phone-service-emergency-backup-and-low-income-access/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Leading Baby Food Manufacturers Knowingly Sold Products With High Levels of Toxic Metals, a Congressional Investigation Found</title>
			<source>CNN</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Internal documents from major baby food manufacturers show they tested and used ingredients with high levels of arsenic, lead, cadmium and mercury in the baby food they sold to parents, according to a congressional investigation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/04/health/baby-food-heavy-metal-toxins-wellness/index.html?utm_term=link&amp;utm_medium=social&utm_content=2021-02-04T19%3A00%3A14</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'More Weight': An Academic's Guide to Surviving Campus Witch Hunts</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the fall of 2020, I became the target of a cancellation campaign after I'd suggested that the best policy for a university seeking to support underrepresented groups, while staying true to its m…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/05/more-weight-an-academics-guide-to-surviving-campus-witch-hunts/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>American Cities Are Way Underreporting Their Carbon Footprints</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A modeling system called Vulcan shows that on average, cities across the country pollute 18.3 percent more than they've estimated.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/american-cities-underreporting-their-carbon-footprints/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mysterious California Sea Lion Deaths Linked to Toxic Synthetic Chemicals</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists say animals with higher levels of DDT, PCBs and others in their blubber are more prone to cancer triggered by herpes]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/01/california-sea-lion-deaths-cancer-toxic-chemicals</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electric Cars Would Save America Huge Amounts of Energy</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Electrifying the vehicle fleet would save more energy than we get from the entire power grid today.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2021-opinion-renewables-will-power-future-of-us-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Did the BLM Protests Against the Police Lead to the 2020 Spike in Homicides?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Serious crime, particularly murder, soared while everyone was supposed to be locked indoors. Between 2019—by no means a famously peaceful year—and 2020, homicides alone surged by 42 percent during …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/27/did-the-blm-protests-against-the-police-lead-to-the-2020-spike-in-homicides/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apple CEO Sounds Warning of Algorithms Pushing Society Towards Catastrophe</title>
			<source>ZDNet</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Tim Cook says there will be consequences to having 'rampant disinformation and conspiracy theories juiced by algorithms'.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/apple-ceo-sounds-warning-of-algorithms-pushing-society-towards-catastrophe/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Intelligence Claims China Wants to Steal Your DNA</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[China has been accused of stealing a lot of things from America: intellectual property, 'jobs and wealth,' even our role as the world's biggest jerk. Now, US national security officials warn that America's greatest adversary wants to steal our genetic makeup.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-intelligence-claims-china-wants-to-steal-your-dna-1846156502</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Suck It, Wall Street</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In a blowout comedy for the ages, finance pirates take it up the clacker]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/suck-it-wall-street</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social Media Damages Teenagers' Mental Health, Report Says</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Heavy social media use had a negative impact on wellbeing, the study found.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55826238</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Live Streamers</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Silicon Valley is shutting down speech loopholes. The latest target: live content]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-live-streamers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Status Coup</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Silicon Valley is shutting down speech loopholes. The latest target: live content]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-status-coup</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Worrisome New Coronavirus Mutations Are Emerging. Why Now?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Across the globe, SARS-CoV-2 is evolving ways to evade the immune system and become more infectious. Blown pandemic response plans are to blame.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/worrisome-new-coronavirus-strains-are-emerging-why-now/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air Pollution Linked to Higher Risk of Irreversible Sight Loss</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Large UK study found small pollution rise associated with more cases of age-related macular degeneration]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/26/air-pollution-linked-to-higher-risk-of-irreversible-sight-loss</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reflecting the Authoritarian Climate, Washington Will Remain Militarized Until at Least March</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The idea of troops in U.S. streets for an extended period of time -- an extreme measure even when temporary -- has now become close to a sacred consensus.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/reflecting-the-authoritarian-climate</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth Has Lost 28 Trillion Tons of Ice Since the Mid-1990s</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Melt has accelerated over recent decades, contributing to sea level rise]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earth-has-lost-28-trillion-tons-of-ice-since-the-mid-1990s/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No Qualified Immunity for Cops Who Made Stuff Up to Justify Seizing a Man's Phone for Twelve Days</title>
			<source>Techdirt.</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Here's an interesting decision [PDF] by the Eighth Circuit Court of Appeals. On one hand, it says cops can possibly hassle people for filming them if they can find almost any reason at all to justify it. On the other hand, it says they definitely...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20210106/18521446009/no-qualified-immunity-cops-who-made-stuff-up-to-justify-seizing-mans-phone-twelve-days.shtml</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The War on Privacy</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 8, 2001</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Five years ago, official abuses of secrecy were the scandal. Today, the scandal is you]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-war-on-privacy</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Sets New Record for Most Satellites on a Single Launch With Latest Falcon 9 Mission</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has set a new all-time record for the most satellites launched and deployed on a single mission, with its Transporter-1 flight on Sunday. The launch was the first of SpaceX's dedicated rideshare missions, in which it splits up the payload capacity of its rocket among multiple customers…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spacex-sets-new-record-for-most-satellites-on-a-single-launch-with-latest-falcon-9-mission</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Glenn Greenwald: 'Journalists Are Authoritarians'</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What went wrong at the outlet he co-founded, what's wrong with the ACLU, and what might go wrong in the Biden administration]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/01/23/journalists-are-authoritarians/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electric Vehicles Close to 'Tipping Point' of Mass Adoption</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sales increase 43% globally in 2020 as plunging battery costs mean the cars will soon be the cheapest vehicles to buy]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/22/electric-vehicles-close-to-tipping-point-of-mass-adoption</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
