<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
    <channel>
        <title>cata-list</title>
        <link>https://cata-list.github.io/</link>
        <id>dNqdPT5H_fMopmkrIGUwU</id>
        <description>Lists of some of the best information, media, tools, and wisdom which can help to inform, empower, and act as catalysts for positive change in this perilous yet promising time.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon May 04 2020 17:25:33 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2020 Matthew McCutcheon. All rights reserved</copyright>
        <item>
            <title>China Thinks Backlash to Its Coronavirus Response Could Lead to All-Out War With the U.S.</title>
            <source>Vice</source>
            <pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[A State Security report warned that anti-China sentiment, led by the U.S., has not been this high since the 1989 Tiananmen Square crackdown.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/wxeww4/china-thinks-backlash-to-its-coronavirus-response-could-lead-to-all-out-war-with-the-us</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Which States Are Reopening, Which Remain on Lockdown, and Why</title>
            <source>Wired</source>
            <pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[There's not a national plan to restart US businesses. That's led to inconsistencies among governors' orders, and some confusion among residents.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/which-states-reopening-lockdown/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Medical Expert: Federal Jail Intentionally Destroying Medical Records and Hiding Extent of Coronavirus Behind Bars</title>
            <source>The Intercept</source>
            <pubDate>May 04 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA['Several current practices in MDC actually promote a more rapid spread of COVID-19 inside the facility.']]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theintercept.com/2020/05/01/mdc-brooklyn-jail-coronavirus-medical-records/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Donald Trump's Four-Step Plan to Reopen the US Economy – and Why It Will Be Lethal</title>
            <source>The Guardian</source>
            <pubDate>May 03 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[The president and his allies are hiding the facts and pretending 'freedom' conquers all. As a result, more Americans will die]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/may/03/donald-trump-reopen-us-economy-lethal-robert-reich</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>White House Blocks Fauci From Testifying to Congress on Coronavirus Response</title>
            <source>Reuters</source>
            <pubDate>May 02 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Top U.S. health official Anthony Fauci will not testify next week to a congressional committee examining the Trump administration's response to the coronavirus pandemic, the White House said on Friday, calling it 'counterproductive' to have individuals involved in the response testify.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-usa-fauci/white-house-blocks-fauci-from-testifying-to-congress-on-coronavirus-response-idUSKBN22E03O</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The World Is Still Producing More Oil Than It Needs. Why?</title>
            <source>Wired</source>
            <pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Today, petroleum producers around the world will start shutting down wells after the Covid-19 pandemic caused demand to plummet. What took them so long?]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-is-still-producing-more-oil-than-it-needs-why/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Judge Orders FCC to Hand Over IP Addresses Linked to Fake Net Neutrality Comments</title>
            <source>Gizmodo</source>
            <pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[A Manhattan federal judge has ruled the Federal Communications Commission must provide two reporters access to server logs that may provide new insight into the allegations of fraud stemming from agency's 2017 net neutrality rollback.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gizmodo.com/judge-orders-fcc-to-hand-over-ip-addresses-linked-to-fa-1843202071</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Congress Is Investigating Cruise Ship Company Carnival Over COVID-19 Outbreaks</title>
            <source>The Verge</source>
            <pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Carnival is accused of failing to take action when it knew the risks of the novel coronavirus.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/1/21244432/carnival-princess-cruises-congress-investigation-covid-19-coronavirus-outbreak</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>China Warns Australia It Could Face Boycotts Over Call for an Independent Inquiry Into Coronavirus</title>
            <source>Time</source>
            <pubDate>May 01 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[China has accused Australia of parroting the United States in its call for an inquiry independent of the WHO to determine the origins of COVID-19.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://time.com/5830675/china-australia-coronavirus-inquiry/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Jobs Collapse Is Deeper Than the Government Says</title>
            <source>Bloomberg</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Economists' workforce surveys are more current than the government's. And more terrifying.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2020-04-30/jobs-collapse-is-deeper-than-the-government-says</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People With Guns (And No Masks) Swarmed the Michigan State Capitol to Protest the Coronavirus Lockdown</title>
            <source>Vice</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Some state legislators, anticipating the possibility of violence, had even come to work that day wearing bulletproof vests.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/y3makv/protestors-with-guns-and-no-masks-swarmed-the-michigan-state-capitol-to-protest-the-coronavirus-lockdown</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>'Microplastic Hot Spots' Are Tainting Deep-Sea Ecosystems</title>
            <source>Wired</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Scientists found 2 million microplastic particles in a square meter of sediment, as currents drag debris into seafloor versions of the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-hotspots/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pence Threatened to Punish the Reporter Who Proved His Office Ignored the Rule That He Needed a Mask to Visit the Mayo Clinic</title>
            <source>Business Insider</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 30 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Steve Herman undermined Pence's wife's claim that the vice president didn't know he was supposed to wear a mask during the much-criticized visit.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/pence-threatened-reporter-proved-knew-mayo-clinic-mask-rule-2020-5</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>It Could Take Decades for the Ocean Floor to Recover From Deep Sea Mining</title>
            <source>Gizmodo</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[A new study has found that the impacts of deep sea mining are still felt a quarter of a century later.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/it-could-take-decades-for-the-ocean-floor-to-recover-fr-1843162892</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stocks Are Recovering While the Economy Collapses. That Makes More Sense Than You'd Think.</title>
            <source>Time</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[While the economy is contracting, the market is soaring. If you look closely at what's up and down, it actually makes sense--for now.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://time.com/5828898/stocks-recovering-economy-collapses-makes-sense/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Play Has Been Spreading Advanced Android Malware for Years</title>
            <source>Ars Technica</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 29 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Advanced hacker group seeded market with at least 8 apps likely since 2016.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/04/sophisticated-android-backdoors-have-been-populating-google-play-for-years/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Pandemic Is Accelerating Coal's Demise</title>
            <source>Bloomberg</source>
            <pubDate>Apr 28 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Electricity in Europe, India, China, and parts of the U.S. is less and less reliant on coal.]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-28/the-coronavirus-pandemic-is-accelerating-coal-s-demise</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Inside the Race to Build the Best Quantum Computer on Earth</title>
            <source>MIT Technology Review</source>
            <pubDate>Feb 26 2020</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Google's most advanced computer isn't at the company's headquarters in Mountain View, California, nor anywhere in the febrile sprawl of Silicon Valley. It's a few hours' drive south in Santa Barbara, in a flat, soulless office park inhabited mostly by technology firms you've never heard of. An open-…]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/02/26/916744/quantum-computer-race-ibm-google/</link>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>