<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>liII7-ipXkX_JSKoZg-JZ</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed Dec 02 2020 09:46:57 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>The Heretical Impulse: Zamyatin and Orwell</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I In a 1931 letter to Joseph Stalin, Russian novelist Yevgeny Zamyatin adopted a respectful tone by way of introduction: 'My name is probably known to you.' The author of We, the dystopian science fiction novel that influenced Aldous Huxley's Brave New World and George Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/01/the-heretical-impulse-zamyatin-and-orwell/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Race and Social Panic at Haverford: A Case Study in Educational Dysfunction</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['You have continued to stand as an individual that seems to turn a blind eye to the stuff that's going on, as a black woman that is in the [college] administration,' said the first-year Haverford College student. 'I came to this institution'—and here she pauses for a moment, apparently fighting back…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/01/race-and-social-panic-at-haverford-a-case-study-in-educational-dysfunction/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Elon Musk Says SpaceX Will Attempt Uncrewed Mars Flight in Two Years, Human Landing in Four to Six</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX founder and CEO Elon Musk was given an award from media giant Axel Springer on Tuesday, and he sat down to provide a wide-ranging interview that covered topics including space, Tesla, AI and even underpopulation. Musk addressed SpaceX's Mars ambitions first, providing current timelines…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/elon-musk-says-spacex-will-attempt-uncrewed-mars-flight-in-two-years-human-landing-in-four-to-six/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DeepMind's Superhuman Intelligence</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The solving of a 50-year scientific problem takes computers a step closer to 'true creativity']]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/how-deepmind-is-transforming-the-future/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aftermarket Truck Mods Pollute as Much as 9 Million Extra Pickups</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The EPA estimates 550,000 medium pickup trucks have disabled emissions controls.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/12/truck-emissions-mods-pollute-more-than-dieselgate-epa-says/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Tis the Season: Congress Looks to Sneak in Unconstitutional Copyright Reform Bill Into 'Must Pass' Spending Bill</title>
			<source>Techdirt</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you have to sneak your transformational copyright bill into a 'must pass' government spending bill, it seems fairly evident that you know the bill is bad. Earlier we talked about how the White House is trying to slip a Section 230 repeal...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20201201/10514145802/tis-season-congress-looks-to-sneak-unconstitutional-copyright-reform-bill-into-must-pass-spending-bill.shtml</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Public Defender Tales: Innocent, But Fined</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The state of Iowa collects millions of dollars in fines from people whose charges were dismissed. There's also a Catch-22: financially, you're better off guilty]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/public-defender-tales-innocent-but</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Appointee Neera Tanden Spread the Conspiracy That Russian Hackers Changed Hillary's 2016 Votes to Trump</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How can Democrats and allied media outlets credibly oppose unhinged conspiracy theories and attacks on U.S. election legitimacy while empowering its worst purveyors?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/biden-appointee-neera-tanden-spread</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Study Sheds Light on Why Women Tend to Have Greater Animosity Towards Political Opponents</title>
			<source>PsyPost</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research suggests there is a gender gap in affective polarization: Women in the United States tend to be more hostile than men towards their political ...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.psypost.org/2020/11/new-study-sheds-light-on-why-women-tend-to-have-greater-animosity-towards-political-opponents-58680</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Dangerous Logic of Anti-Racism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If racism is about prejudice and power, where does that leave high-achieving minorities?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/the-dangerous-logic-of-anti-racism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Assassination of a Top Iranian Nuclear Scientist, Briefly Explained</title>
			<source>Vox</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Iran has blamed Israel for the attack, and pledged retaliation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vox.com/2020/11/28/21723778/assassination-iran-nuclear-scientist-mohsen-fakhrizadeh</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Guns, Drugs and Viral Content: Welcome to Cartel TikTok</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Mexico is set to shatter another murder record, but that grim reality is nowhere to be seen on the TikTok videos that go viral by showcasing drug cartel culture.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/28/world/americas/mexico-drugs-cartel-tiktok.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Politics in Academia: A Case Study</title>
			<source>Psychology Today</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This is the story of our effort to publish a paper that threatens academia.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/darwins-subterranean-world/202011/politics-in-academia-case-study</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Most Americans Object to Government Tracking of Their Activities Through Cellphones</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new survey found widespread concern among Americans about government tracking of their whereabouts through their digital devices, with an overwhelming majority saying that a warrant should be required to obtain such data.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/most-americans-object-to-government-tracking-of-their-activities-through-cellphones-11606305601</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Long-Forgotten CIA Document From WikiLeaks Sheds Critical Light on Today's U.S. Politics and Wars</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Agency knew that their best asset for selling their wars was Barack Obama -- the same reason so many in the security state were eager to get rid of Donald Trump.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/a-long-forgotten-cia-document-from</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jordan Peterson v the Crybullies</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The reaction to the 12 Rules for Life sequel shows an infantile intolerance]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/jordan-peterson-v-the-crybullies/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>As Cities Curb Surveillance, Baltimore Police Took to the Air</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In a program that overcame three court challenges this year, planes with high-tech cameras circled the city up to 40 hours a week.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/cities-curb-surveillance-baltimore-police-took-air/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Microsoft's New 'Productivity Score' Gamifies Workplace Surveillance</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The company's newest feature is facing heavy criticism for allowing bosses to track how their employees use Microsoft's suite of tools, such as how frequently they send emails, collaborate in shared documents, or have their camera on during virtual meetings.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/microsofts-creepy-new-productivity-score-gamifies-workp-1845763063</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Ethics of Rebooting the Dead</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The notion of resurrecting people as digital entities is becoming less hypothetical. But just because something can be done, doesn't always mean it should.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/ethics-reviving-dead-with-tech/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How the Criminal Justice System Fails People With Mental Illness</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I found your baby,' Michelle Durden recalls the police officer saying after her son went missing. 'He's alive. And he's in jail.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/26/mental-illness-prison-jail-police/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contaminants in New Jersey Soil and Water Are Toxic, Documents Reveal</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Solvay had previously withheld information about the PFAS chemicals on the grounds that it was 'confidential business information.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/25/solvay-new-jersey-pfas-documents/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Illegal Tampering by Diesel Pickup Owners Is Worsening Pollution, E.P.A. Says</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An E.P.A. investigation has found that the owners of more than half a million diesel pickup trucks have installed devices to defeat emissions controls and boost pollution.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/25/climate/diesel-trucks-air-pollution.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interview With Edward Snowden on Silicon Valley Censorship, Biden, and Lurking Press Freedom Dangers</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How did we travel so far from the original vision of the internet as the one place humans could communicate and organize free of state and corporate control?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/video-interview-with-edward-snowden</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Demanding Silicon Valley Suppress 'Hyper-Partisan Sites' in Favor of 'Mainstream News' (The NYT) Is a Fraud</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The corporate news organizations masquerading as reliable and non-partisan are, in fact, as hyper-partisan as any sites on the internet, and spread as much misinformation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/demanding-silicon-valley-suppress</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Andre Damon</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Increased content moderation has been sold as a tool to control the far right, but the World Socialist Web Site was among the first to sound the alarm]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-andre-damon</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why I Had to Leave the Guardian</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you were bullied by 338 colleagues, what would you do?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/why-i-had-to-leave-the-guardian/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How America Came Apart</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A people with no shared history will find it very hard to keep a lid on disorder and violence]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/09/can-america-hold-apart/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Cultural Appropriation' Is American Cultural Imperialism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The US culture wars are intruding in places they don't belong]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/09/cultural-appropriation-is-american-cultural-imperialism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Has Trans Activism Gone Too Far?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's time we were allowed a properly nuanced discussion on gender issues]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/11/has-trans-activism-gone-too-far/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Will Maths Succumb to the Woke Wave?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 4, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Students are being imprisoned in the lies of our age]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/10/will-maths-succumb-to-the-woke-wave/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antifa's Attack on the Truth</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 5, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hostile actors are conspiring to create false narratives]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/07/antifas-attack-on-the-truth/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Titania Is Perfect for Our Times</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 8, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The avenging SJW angel, Titania McGrath, has disrupted a tired genre]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/03/why-titania-is-perfect-for-our-times/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Is Scientific Illiteracy So Acceptable?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the mid-1980s, when I taught a Physics for Poets class at Yale University, I was dumbstruck when I gave the students a quiz problem to estimate the total amount of water flushed in all the toilets in the US in one 24-hour period and I started to grade the quiz. In order to estimate this, you have…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/23/why-is-scientific-illiteracy-so-acceptable/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Retracting a Controversial Paper Won't Help Female Scientists</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Imagine yourself as a newly hired female assistant professor and the delight you feel when you learn that your article, examining over 222 million academic papers, has just been accepted at one of the top science journals. Now imagine your response when you discover that a fellow female academic is …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/23/retracting-a-controversial-paper-wont-help-female-scientists/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This Squishy 3D-Printed Human Heart Feels Like the Real Thing</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A clever technique allows scientists to scan a heart and reconstruct it in a soup of gelatin. It's like making jello, only way more useful for surgeons.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/3d-printed-human-heart-feels-like-the-real-thing/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psilocybin &amp; Migraine: First of Its Kind Trial Reports Promising Results</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A first-of-its-kind exploratory study, led by researchers from Yale School of Medicine, has found a single dose of the psychedelic psilocybin can reduce migraine frequency by 50 percent for a least two weeks. The preliminary trial was small, with follow-up work necessary to validate the results,…]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/psilocybin-migraine-psychedelic-clinical-trial-promising-results/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Fragility of Modern Education in the Time of COVID-19</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Modern education is arguably the most massive feat of social engineering ever attempted by humanity and one of the most important, when effective. Academic competencies at the end of schooling can have life-long influences on employability, wages, and the ability to advance in one's career.1,2,3,4 T…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/22/the-fragility-of-modern-education-in-the-time-of-covid/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kin, Tribes, and the Dark Side of Identity</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['We should poison their water holes!' This was the first thing my father said when I called him after planes hit the World Trade Center where I worked. My dad was a 1960s cultural liberal and pacifist, who had opposed every war our country had fought. The moment he felt that my life was in danger, h…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/22/kin-tribes-and-the-dark-side-of-identity/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Does Racism Explain Black Disadvantage?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A foundational tenet of the Black Lives Matter and similar racial justice movements is that gaps between blacks and whites on many socio-economic measures are produced primarily by racism. Racial inequalities in educational attainment, financial success, social status, crime, and health are thereby …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/15/does-racism-explain-black-disadvantage/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Joe Biden's Silence on Ending the Drone Wars</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[With scant comments about U.S. assassination programs, there are indications that Biden would keep the drone wars around.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/22/biden-drones-endless-wars/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What if Instead of Calling People Out, We Called Them In?</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Prof. Loretta J. Ross is combating cancel culture with a popular class at Smith College.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/19/style/loretta-ross-smith-college-cancel-culture.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police in Mississippi to Pilot a Program to Live-Stream Amazon Ring Cameras</title>
			<source>Mozilla Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The police surveillance center in Jackson, Mississippi, will be conducting a 45-day pilot program to live stream the security cameras, including Amazon Ring cameras, of participating residents.]]></description>
			<link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/blog/police-mississippi-pilot-program-live-stream-amazon-ring-cameras/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Robots Invade the Construction Site</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Boosted by advances in sensors and artificial intelligence, a new generation of machines is automating a tech-averse industry.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/robots-invade-construction-site/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This 2-Acre Vertical Farm Out-Produces 720 Acre 'Flat Farms'</title>
			<source>Forbes</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[95% less water. 99% less land. 400X more yield.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/20/this-2-acre-vertical-farm-out-produces-750-acre-flat-farms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deep Frozen Arctic Microbes Are Waking Up</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thawing permafrost is releasing microorganisms, with consequences that are still largely unknown]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/deep-frozen-arctic-microbes-are-waking-up/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Extremely Aggressive' Internet Censorship Spreads in the World's Democracies</title>
			<source>University of Michigan News</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The largest collection of public internet censorship data ever compiled shows that even citizens of the world's freest countries are not safe from internet censorship. A University of Michigan team used Censored Planet, an automated censorship tracking...]]></description>
			<link>https://news.umich.edu/extremely-aggressive-internet-censorship-spreads-in-the-worlds-democracies/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Victimhood or Development?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On October 20th, Brown University professor of economics Glenn Loury and Columbia University professor of linguistics John McWhorter were joined on Loury's Bloggingheads podcast The Glenn Show by Shel]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/19/victimhood-or-development/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Ford Fischer</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The videographer is this week's entrant in a growing club of the digitally deleted]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-ford-fischer</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's Time for America to Reckon With the Staggering Death Toll of the Post-9/11 Wars</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least half a million people have been killed in the post-9/11 wars in Afghanistan, Iraq, and Pakistan, a new study by Brown University researchers finds.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/11/19/civilian-casualties-us-war-on-terror/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Ruling Coalition: Opposition to Afghanistan Withdrawal Shows Its Key Factions</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An unholy union of the National Security State and the neocon-backed and corporate-funded Democratic Party are about to assume power: with media-supported internet censorship a key weapon.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-new-ruling-coalition-opposition</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pandemic Villains: Allianz Global Investors</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How one of the world's biggest finance companies misread Covid-19 and cost pensioners billions]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/pandemic-villains-allianz-global</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Massive, China-State-Funded Hack Hits Companies Around the World, Report Says</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Attacks are linked to Cicada, a group believed to be funded by the Chinese state.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/11/massive-china-state-funded-hack-hits-companies-around-the-word-report-says/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Passes 250,000 Deaths From Coronavirus</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Bleak landmark comes as more than 11m have been infected, while Biden public health adviser warns of further hardship over winter]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/nov/18/us-passes-250000-deaths-from-coronavirus</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>1% of People Cause Half of Global Aviation Emissions – Study</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Exclusive: Researchers say Covid-19 hiatus is moment to tackle elite 'super emitters']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/nov/17/people-cause-global-aviation-emissions-study-covid-19</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Intellectual Freedom and the Culture Wars — A Review</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A review of Intellectual Freedom and the Culture Wars by Piers Benn. Palgrave MacMillan, 168 pages (October 2020)I attended a notably liberal state university in the early 2000s. Most politically-]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/16/intellectual-freedom-and-the-culture-wars-a-review/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How the U.S. Military Buys Location Data From Ordinary Apps</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Muslim prayer app with over 98 million downloads is one of the apps connected to a wide-ranging supply chain that sends ordinary people's personal data to brokers, contractors, and the military.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgqm5x/us-military-location-data-xmode-locate-x</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>South Dakota Nurse Says Many Dying Patients Still Insist COVID-19 'Not Real'</title>
			<source>The Hill</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A South Dakota emergency room nurse on Monday expressed frustration that many of her patients don't believe they are dying of COVID-19.]]></description>
			<link>https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/526204-south-dakota-nurse-says-many-dying-patients-still-insist-covid-19-not</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thanks to SpaceX, NASA Regains a Capability It Lost for a Decade</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has now launched as many astronauts into space as the Mercury program.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/11/nasas-big-bet-on-spacex-and-commercial-space-pays-off/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Three Greatest Dangers of Biden/Harris: Militarism, Corporatism and Censorship, All Fueled by Indifference</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[VIDEO: What we need to be vigilant against.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-three-greatest-dangers-of-bidenharris</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Ongoing Death of Free Speech: Prominent ACLU Lawyer Cheers Suppression of a New Book</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Free speech has always been more than a Constitutional guarantee: it's also a crucial societal value. And it's more imperiled than ever.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-ongoing-death-of-free-speech</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Sponsored by Russia and North Korea Are Targeting COVID-19 Researchers</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three nation-state-sponsored groups are targeting organizations throughout the world.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/11/hackers-sponsored-by-russia-and-north-korea-are-targeting-covid-19-researchers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden, the Media and CIA Labeled the Hunter Biden Emails 'Russian Disinformation.' There Is Still No Evidence.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The same factions that constantly claim to abhor Fake News and disinformation continue to be the most aggressive and shameless propagators of it -- especially the media.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/biden-the-media-and-cia-labeled-the</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Measles Surging as COVID-19 Curbs Disrupt Vaccinations</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Measles surged to infect almost 870,000 people across the world in 2019, the worst figures in almost a quarter of a century as vaccination levels fell below critical levels, a report said on Thursday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-measles-global/measles-surging-as-covid-19-curbs-disrupt-vaccinations-idUSKBN27S2TC</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Healthcare on Brink as COVID-19 Hospitalizations Hit All-Time High</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There's a 'very dark winter' ahead as hospitals struggle to cope and cases keep rising.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/11/us-healthcare-on-brink-as-covid-19-hospitalizations-hit-all-time-high/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The U.S. Inability to Count Votes Is a National Disgrace. And Dangerous.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Nations far poorer and less technologically advanced have no problem holding quick, efficient elections. Distrust in U.S. outcomes is dangerous but rational.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-us-inability-to-count-votes-is</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN Is Just the Latest News Outlet to Prove Deliberate Lying Is Not an Impediment to Employment</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Former Trump DHS official, now CNN analyst, Miles Taylor got caught blatantly lying on CNN's airwaves to host Anderson Cooper, but The Most Trusted Name In News™ doesn't mind at all.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/cnn-is-just-the-latest-news-outlet</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Article on Joe and Hunter Biden Censored by the Intercept</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An attempt to assess the importance of the known evidence, and a critique of media lies to protect their favored candidate, could not be published at The Intercept]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/article-on-joe-and-hunter-biden-censored</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Reports More Than 100,000 COVID-19 Cases for Seventh Day in a Row</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States reported a record number of new COVID-19 cases for the seventh day in a row on Tuesday, according to a Reuters tally, while the number of deaths surged to their highest daily count since August.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-usa-cases/u-s-reports-more-than-100000-covid-19-cases-for-seventh-day-in-a-row-idUSKBN27R09T</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>One in Five COVID-19 Patients Develop Mental Illness Within 90 Days - Study</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Many COVID-19 survivors are likely to be at greater risk of developing mental illness, psychiatrists said on Monday, after a large study found 20% of those infected with the coronavirus are diagnosed with a psychiatric disorder within 90 days.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-mental-illness-int-idUSKBN27P35N</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Latest Covid Vaccine Results, Deciphered</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Reporting on the big announcement from Pfizer and BioNTech has been a little off the mark. Here's what we really know right now.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-latest-covid-vaccine-results-deciphered/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Secular Modernity Under Theocratic Assault</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Professor Leszek Kołakowski, one of the great Polish intellectual dissidents from the Stalinist period, liked to say that when he debated with apologists for the system, he often found himself almost on the losing side. Kołakowski hastened to add that this fact did not owe to the superior arguments …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/11/secular-modernity-under-theocratic-assault/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Everything You Need to Know About Energy</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We'll talk about the different types—kinetic energy, electrical potential energy, etc.—and different sources, from fossil fuels to solar.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/everything-you-need-to-know-about-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Renewable Power Represents Almost 90% of Total Global Power Capacity Added in 2020</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Bucking the slowdown in most of the power sector caused by responses to the COVID-19 pandemic, renewable energy actually grew in 2020, and will represent about 90% of the total power capacity added for the year, according to the International Energy Agency. A surge in new projects from China and th…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/renewable-power-represents-almost-90-of-total-global-power-capacity-added-in-2020/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>America Has Serious Problems. It's Time to Stop Blaming Them on 'Trumpism'</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Donald Trump may have been defeated in his quest for re-election. But not so the shadowy ideology he supposedly champions. 'Even in defeat, the embers of Trumpism still burn in the Republican Party,' declares the Washington Post. 'Trumpism wasn't repudiated,' warns a New York Times columnist. 'Trump…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/09/america-has-serious-problems-its-time-to-stop-blaming-them-on-trumpism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Crosses 10 Million COVID-19 Cases as Third Wave of Infections Surges</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States became the first nation worldwide since the pandemic began to surpass 10 million coronavirus infections, according to a Reuters tally on Sunday, as the third wave of the COVID-19 virus surges across the nation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/BigStory12/idUSKBN27P00U</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Banks Are at the Front &amp; Center of Money Laundering of Over $2 Trillion</title>
			<source>Medium</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 21, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[International Consortium of Investigative Journalists (ICIJ) has exposed a multi-trillion dollar money laundering scandal]]></description>
			<link>https://medium.com/technicity/big-banks-are-at-the-front-center-of-money-laundering-of-over-2-trillion-299feea4c58e</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gender Activists Are Trying to Cancel My Book. Why Is Silicon Valley Helping Them?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The day after I tweeted about the ongoing attempts to block sales of my book, Irreversible Damage: The Transgender Craze Seducing Our Daughters, I was stuck on the phone with my parents' real estate agent. 'How's your book going?' she wanted to know. 'Is there a lot of controversy?' I know it's fash…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/07/gender-activists-are-trying-to-cancel-my-book-why-is-silicon-valley-helping-them/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Batteries of the Future Are Weightless and Invisible</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There's a renaissance underway in structural battery research, which aims to build energy storage into the very devices and vehicles they power.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-batteries-of-the-future-are-weightless-and-invisible/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>San Diego's Spying Streetlights Stuck Switched 'On,' Despite Directive</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sometimes, sharing a power supply is a little too efficient.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/11/san-diegos-spying-streetlights-stuck-switched-on-despite-directive/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Government Continues Encryption War</title>
			<source>PrivacyTools</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Wars can be fought in the real world but there is also a virtual battlefield - and it is just as harmful. The Lawful Access to Encrypted Data Act is the latest attempt to access people's encrypted data and it serves as another reinforcement. This type of 'warrant-proof' encryption adds]]></description>
			<link>https://blog.privacytools.io/us-government-continues-encryption-war/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Breaks Covid-19 Record Again With Over 110,000 New Cases on Thursday</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. has broken its own record for daily cases of covid-19, with 116,225 new cases on Thursday, according to the Covid Tracking Project, up from the previous record of 103,087 new cases on Wednesday. The country also identified 1,124 new deaths from coronavirus on Thursday, bringing the total to…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-breaks-covid-19-record-again-with-over-110-000-new-1845591670</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Voters Rejecting the War on Drugs Is a Win for Public Health</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, several states passed ballot measures to relax drug laws. That's not just a criminal justice victory.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/drug-reform-votes-public-health/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Breaks Record With Over 100,000 New Covid-19 Cases in Single Day</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. recorded over 100,000 new cases of covid-19 on Wednesday, according to the Covid Tracking Project. The shockingly high daily case count is a grim milestone that public health experts warn may be surpassed in the coming days and weeks.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-breaks-record-with-over-100-000-new-covid-19-cases-1845579609</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cannabis Legalization Measures Set to Pass in 5 States</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Cannabis legalization was on five state ballots yesterday and ran the table. Voters in Oregon, where cannabis is already legal, also approved a measure addressing street drugs and another that sought to legalize psychedelic mushrooms' therapeutic use. Of the five states that voted on cannabis…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/cannabis-legalization-measures-set-to-pass-in-5-states/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psilocybin Therapy 4 Times More Effective Than Antidepressants, Study Finds</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new study is presenting the first published data from preliminary human trials investigating the effect of psilocybin-assisted psychotherapy to treat major depressive disorder (MDD). The incredibly positive results have been described as just a 'taste of things to come' with larger a Phase 2…]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/psilocybin-therapy-major-depression-trial-results-johns-hopkins/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tesla Project to Install Another Giant Battery in Australia</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[France's Neoen SA will partner with Tesla Inc. to install one of the world's biggest lithium-ion batteries in Australia after reaching a grid connection deal with the power market operator.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-05/tesla-project-will-install-another-giant-battery-in-australia</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>23,600 Hacked Databases Have Leaked From a Defunct 'Data Breach Index' Site</title>
			<source>ZDNet</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Site archive of Cit0day.in has now leaked on two hacking forums after the service shut down in September.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/23600-hacked-databases-have-leaked-from-a-defunct-data-breach-index-site/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Treat Artificial Light Like Other Forms of Pollution, Say Scientists</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Impact of human illumination has grown to point of systemic disruption, researchers find]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/nov/02/treat-artificial-light-form-pollution-environment</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My Resignation From the Intercept</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The same trends of repression, censorship and ideological homogeneity plaguing the national press generally have engulfed the media outlet I co-founded, culminating in censorship of my own articles.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/my-resignation-from-the-intercept</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>For Five Months, BLM Protestors Trashed America's Cities. After the Election, Things May Only Get Worse</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This week marks the first time in living memory that widespread violence was widely viewed as a foreseeable, and even expected, outcome of an American national election. The votes are being counted just days after riots broke out in Philadelphia, causing the governor to deploy the National Guard in …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/03/for-five-months-blm-protestors-trashed-americas-cities-after-the-election-things-may-only-get-worse/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Exits Paris Climate Accord After Trump Stalls Global Warming Action for Four Years</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[State-level efforts and a growing renewables market have mitigated federal emissions policy rollbacks - but Trump's climate impact could be long-lasting]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/u-s-exits-paris-climate-accord-after-trump-stalls-global-warming-action-for-four-years/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deep Neural Networks Are Helping Decipher How Brains Work</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Neuroscientists are finding that deep-learning networks, often criticized as 'black boxes,' can be good models for the organization of living brains.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/deep-neural-networks-are-helping-decipher-how-brains-work/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Oregon Just Voted to Decriminalize All Drugs</title>
			<source>Vox</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Oregon voters have taken a big step toward ending the war on drugs.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vox.com/2020/11/3/21514828/oregon-drug-decriminalization-measure-110-results</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Failing Business Model of American Universities</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Put yourself in the shoes of the average college graduate today. It took you longer than expected to complete your 'four-year degree' and you are almost $30,000 in debt. You are desperately searching for a job in your field before your student loan payments run you into the ground, assuming your ren…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/03/the-failing-business-model-of-american-universities/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Raspberry Pi 400: The $70 Desktop PC</title>
			<source>Raspberry Pi</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 400 is your complete personal computer, built into a compact keyboard. It's our most powerful and easy-to-use computer yet.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-400-the-70-desktop-pc/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sex Differences in Occupational Attainment Are Here to Stay</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In many nations and for many people, the sex difference in occupational attainment is a social pathology that begs for corrective intervention. The ultimate societal goal for many is equal numbers of high-achieving men and women across high-status fields, including those that typically draw more of …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/02/sex-differences-in-occupational-attainment-are-here-to-stay/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Worst Choice Ever</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Donald Trump is a disaster, but Joe Biden's party is democratic in name only. Why this year's election is a vomit milkshake]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-worst-choice-ever</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Signed Up to Study Sexual Health. What I Got Was Gender Ideology, Fetishism, and Porn</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I am not a conspiracy theorist. And as recently as a year and a half ago, if someone had told me the things I am reporting here, I would have accused them of culture-war paranoia. That was before I enrolled in a professional training program that I'd hoped would expand my skills as a therapist, but …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/10/31/i-signed-up-to-study-sexual-health-what-i-got-was-gender-ideology-fetishism-and-porn/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jack Turban's Dangerous Campaign to Smear Ethical Psychotherapy as Anti-Trans 'Conversion Therapy'</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This essay is adapted from a letter published on October 21 by the listed authors in the Archives of Sexual Behavior. It has been abridged for a non-academic readership. A subset of the scholarly citations included in the original letter appear below in the form of web links. Readers who wish to rea…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/01/jack-turbans-dangerous-campaign-to-smear-ethical-psychotherapy-as-anti-trans-conversion-therapy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Is It Better to Plant Trees or Let Forests Regrow Naturally?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Nations are pledging to plant billions of trees. But a new study shows that we've underestimated the power of natural forest regrowth to fight climate change.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/is-it-better-to-plant-trees-or-let-forests-regrow-naturally/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
