<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>Mj8z3_z7Z31QMM7BjiGlk</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun Jan 24 2021 14:29:15 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Sets New Record for Most Satellites on a Single Launch With Latest Falcon 9 Mission</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has set a new all-time record for the most satellites launched and deployed on a single mission, with its Transporter-1 flight on Sunday. The launch was the first of SpaceX's dedicated rideshare missions, in which it splits up the payload capacity of its rocket among multiple customers…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spacex-sets-new-record-for-most-satellites-on-a-single-launch-with-latest-falcon-9-mission</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Glenn Greenwald: 'Journalists Are Authoritarians'</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What went wrong at the outlet he co-founded, what's wrong with the ACLU, and what might go wrong in the Biden administration]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/01/23/journalists-are-authoritarians/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electric Vehicles Close to 'Tipping Point' of Mass Adoption</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sales increase 43% globally in 2020 as plunging battery costs mean the cars will soon be the cheapest vehicles to buy]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/22/electric-vehicles-close-to-tipping-point-of-mass-adoption</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Intelligence Analysts Use U.S. Smartphone Location Data Without Warrants, Memo Says</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The disclosure comes amid growing legislative scrutiny of how the government uses commercially available location records.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/22/us/politics/dia-surveillance-data.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Moronic Firing of Will Wilkinson Illustrates Why Fear and Bad Faith Mob Demands Reign Supreme</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the prevailing climate, the rational choice is to avoid social scorn and ostracization no matter how baseless the grievances one must appease.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-moronic-firing-of-will-wilkinson</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Echo Chamber Era</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trust in media is down, but if journalists don't listen to critics anyway, why should they care?]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-echo-chamber-era</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Forever Chemicals Are Widespread in U.S. Drinking Water</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Experts hope that with the incoming Biden administration, the federal government will finally regulate a class of chemicals known as PFASs]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/forever-chemicals-are-widespread-in-u-s-drinking-water/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Vertical Farms Grow Veggies on Site at Restaurants and Grocery Stores</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last month we reported that a huge vertical farming operation near Copenhagen in Denmark recently completed its first harvest. That setup uses hydroponics, but the veggies grown in Vertical Field urban farming pods take root in real soil.]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/good-thinking/vertical-field-urban-farm-geoponics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Palantir's God's-Eye View of Afghanistan</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The company's software can sift through enormous amounts of data, and those metrics can be used to make life-or-death decisions.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/palantirs-gods-eye-view-of-afghanistan/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social Media Bans Are Really, Actually, Shockingly Common</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Booting Trump didn't set a precedent. From Yelp to Uber to Airbnb, platforms regularly ban users and content, but too often behind the scenes.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-social-media-bans-are-really-actually-shockingly-common/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Could Lab-Grown Plant Tissue Ease the Environmental Toll of Logging and Agriculture?</title>
			<source>MIT News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[MIT researchers have proposed a method for growing plant-based materials, like wood and fiber, in a lab. The technology is still in early development but might one day help reduce the environmental footprint of some types of agriculture.]]></description>
			<link>https://news.mit.edu/2021/lab-grown-plant-tissue-0120</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Ongoing Collapse of the World's Aquifers</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When humans over-exploit underground water supplies, the ground collapses like a huge empty water bottle. It's called subsidence, and it could affect 1.6 billion people by 2040.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-ongoing-collapse-of-the-worlds-aquifers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The SolarWinds Hackers Used Tactics Other Groups Will Copy</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The supply chain threat was just the beginning.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/solarwinds-hacker-methods-copycats/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New SolarWinds Malware Strain Is Discovered</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SolarWinds: it's the hack that keeps on growing. On Monday, researchers announced the discovery of yet another malware strain used by foreign hackers to infiltrate a wide milieu of American government agencies and companies.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/a-new-solarwinds-malware-strain-is-discovered-1846087775</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Domestic War on Terror Is Coming</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[No speculation is needed. Those who wield power are demanding it. The only question is how much opposition they will encounter.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-new-domestic-war-on-terror-is</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Behind a Secret Deal Between Google and Facebook</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook was going to compete with Google for some advertising sales but backed away from the plan after the companies cut a preferential deal, according to court documents.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/17/technology/google-facebook-ad-deal-antitrust.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2020 Was the One of the Hottest Years on Record</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officials from NASA and NOAA say the warming of both the planet's air and water are driving weather disasters.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/2020-was-the-one-of-the-hottest-years-on-record/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Left Stranded: US Military Sonar Linked to Whale Beachings in Pacific, Say Scientists</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Islands surrounded by US military study area, including Guam and Saipan, call for activity that harms the whales to stop]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/16/left-stranded-us-military-sonar-linked-to-whale-beachings-in-pacific-say-scientists</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beyond Platforms: Private Censorship, Parler, and the Stack</title>
			<source>EFF</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last week, following riots that saw supporters of President Trump breach and sack parts of the Capitol building, Facebook and Twitter made the decision to give the president the boot. That was notable enough, given that both companies had previously treated the president, like other political...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/01/beyond-platforms-private-censorship-parler-and-stack</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Billionaires Add $1tn to Net Worth During Pandemic as Their Workers Struggle</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Companies' attempts at hazard pay have been paltry and fleeting as employees are threatened for protesting working conditions]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/15/billionaires-net-worth-coronavirus-pandemic-jeff-bezos-elon-musk</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Everything We Know Now About Schools, Kids, and Covid-19</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers are finally getting good data on how severely SARS-CoV-2 affects children and how they transmit it. What does it mean for reopening classrooms?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/everything-we-know-now-about-schools-kids-and-covid-19/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Antifa Thugs Shame America</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Andy Ngo's family came to the US to escape Communist tyranny — now he's fleeing a political mob]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/01/the-antifa-thugs-shame-america/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cult Nation</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[National politics has robbed us of our selves.]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/cult-nation-935</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Law Enforcement Gets Around Your Smartphone's Encryption</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research has dug into the openings that iOS and Android security provide for anyone with the right tools.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/smartphone-encryption-law-enforcement-tools/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tech Companies Are Profiling Us From Before Birth</title>
			<source>The MIT Press Reader</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Children today are the very first generation of citizens to be datafied from before birth. The social and political consequences of this historical transformation have yet to be seen.]]></description>
			<link>https://thereader.mitpress.mit.edu/tech-companies-are-profiling-us-from-before-birth/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump's Twitter Ban Obscures the Real Problem: State-Backed Manipulation Is Rampant on Social Media</title>
			<source>The Conversation</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Social media censorship in the US fails to tackle the rising trend of 'disinformation-for-hire' cyber troops.]]></description>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/trumps-twitter-ban-obscures-the-real-problem-state-backed-manipulation-is-rampant-on-social-media-153136</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nasa's Curiosity Rover: 3,000 Days on Mars</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three thousand days and counting: Nasa's Curiosity rover continues its extraordinary exploration of Mars.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-55562150</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Arctic Ocean Is Teeming With Microfibers From Clothes</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists find an average of 40 microplastic particles per cubic meter of the northern water. The likely source? The synthetic clothing in our washing machines.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-arctic-ocean-is-teeming-with-microfibers-from-clothes/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Silicon Valley, in a Show of Monopolistic Force, Destroyed Parler</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the last three months, tech giants have censored political speech and journalism to manipulate U.S. politics, while liberals, with virtual unanimity, have cheered.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Mafia Is Thriving in Lockdown</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Chaos has always been an opportunity for organised crime — as Britain could soon find out]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/01/the-mafia-is-thriving-in-lockdown/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Plan to Build a Global Network of Floating Power Stations</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A lot of thermal energy is trapped in the ocean. An ex-NASA researcher has figured out how it might generate unlimited clean power for aquatic robots.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-build-a-global-network-of-floating-power-stations/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Shared Tricks With Known Russian Cyberspies</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Security researchers have found links between the attackers and Turla, a sophisticated team suspected of operating out of Moscow's FSB intelligence agency.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/solarwinds-russia-hackers-turla-malware/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Need a New Media System</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you sell culture war all day, don't be surprised by the real-world consequences]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/we-need-a-new-media-system</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social-Media Oligopolists Are the New Railroad Barons. It's Time for Washington to Treat Them Accordingly</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In 1964, an Ohio Ku Klux Klan leader named Clarence Brandenburg told a Cincinnati-based reporter that his hate group would soon be holding a rally in a rural area of Hamilton County. In the filmed por]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/11/social-media-oligopolists-are-the-new-railroad-barons-its-time-for-washington-to-treat-them-accordingly/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Would It Take to Run a City on 100 Percent Clean Energy?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 09, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Most claims of running on 'clean' electricity come with caveats, and many technologies required for round-the-clock renewable energy aren't quite ready yet.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-it-take-to-run-a-city-on-100-percent-clean-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Violence in the Capitol, Dangers in the Aftermath</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From the Cold War to the War on Terror: the harms from authoritarian 'solutions' are often greater than the threats they are ostensibly designed to combat.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/violence-in-the-capitol-dangers-in-bbe</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wednesday's Other Story</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On the case of Julian Assange, and fearing empire more than Trump]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/wednesdays-other-story</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EFF's Response to Social Media Companies' Decisions to Block President Trump's Accounts</title>
			<source>Electronic Frontier Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Like most people in the United States and around the world, EFF is shocked and disgusted by Wednesday's violent attack on the U.S. Capitol. We support all those who are working to defend the Constitution and the rule of law, and we are grateful for the service of policymakers, staffers, and other...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/01/eff-response-social-media-companies-decision-block-president-trumps-accounts</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change Is Turning Cities Into Ovens</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 07, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new model estimates that by 2100, cities across the world could warm as much as 4.4 degrees Celsius. It's a deadly consequence of the heat-island effect.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-turning-cities-into-ovens/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sealed U.S. Court Records Exposed in SolarWinds Breach</title>
			<source>Krebs on Security</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ongoing breach affecting thousands of organizations that relied on backdoored products by network software firm SolarWinds may have jeopardized the privacy of countless sealed court documents on file with the U.S. federal court system, according to a memo released Wednesday by the Administrative…]]></description>
			<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/01/sealed-u-s-court-records-exposed-in-solarwinds-breach/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Security Failures Enabled Trump Mob to Storm U.S. Capitol</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[By Joseph Tanfani, John Shiffman, Brad Heath, Andrea Januta and Mark Hosenball]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-election-capitol-security-insight/how-security-failures-enabled-trump-mob-to-storm-u-s-capitol-idUSKBN29C0R5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Accessed More Than 3,000 DOJ Email Accounts</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In yet another dastardly twist in the ongoing SolarWinds debacle, the U.S. Department of Justice announced Wednesday that hackers had accessed the inboxes of over 3,000 DOJ employee Microsoft email accounts.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/solarwinds-hackers-accessed-more-than-3-000-doj-email-a-1846001981</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Intelligence Agencies Say Russia Was Likely Behind the SolarWinds Hack</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 06, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The FBI, NSA and CISA say it'll take a lot of effort to fix the problem.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/us-intelligence-agencies-fbi-nsa-cisa-solarwinds-hack-russia-111518166.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Last Year Reusable Rockets Entered the Mainstream, and There's No Going Back</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 06, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['If Rocket Lab ever builds a new vehicle, it will fundamentally be reusable.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/01/last-year-reusable-rockets-entered-the-mainstream-and-theres-no-going-back/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gravity Energy Storage Will Show Its Potential in 2021</title>
			<source>IEEE Spectrum</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Gravitricity and Energy Vault are pioneering a radical new alternative to batteries for grid storage]]></description>
			<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/energy/batteries-storage/gravity-energy-storage-will-show-its-potential-in-2021</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers Find a Faster, More Efficient Way to 3D Print</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two researchers at Penn State have created a new system for five-axis additive 3D-printing that reduces the amount and density of support materials needed for making printed objects.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/researchers-find-a-faster-more-efficient-way-to-3d-pri-1845992030</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Blocks Entry to WHO Team Studying Covid's Origins</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officials say visas not yet approved for World Health Organization delegation due to visit Wuhan]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/05/china-blocks-entry-to-who-team-studying-covids-origins</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This Year, Autonomous Trucks Will Take to the Road With No One on Board</title>
			<source>IEEE Spectrum</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The startup TuSimple is deploying tractor-trailers that drive themselves from pickup to delivery]]></description>
			<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/transportation/self-driving/this-year-autonomous-trucks-will-take-to-the-road-with-no-one-on-board</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Lab-Leak Hypothesis</title>
			<source>New York Magazine</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For decades, scientists have been hot-wiring viruses in hopes of preventing a pandemic, not causing one. But what if …?]]></description>
			<link>https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/coronavirus-lab-escape-theory.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Wokest News Stories of 2020</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When editors in 2020 weren't being fired in bunches, they were taking aim at everything from Beethoven to mermaids to skyscrapers]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-wokest-news-stories-of-2020-d14</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Mark Crispin Miller</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The NYU Professor becomes the latest academic to fall afoul of idea police]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-mark-crispin-miller</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Kafkaesque Imprisonment of Julian Assange Exposes U.S. Myths About Freedom and Tyranny</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The real measure of how free is a society is not how its mainstream, well-behaved ruling class servants are treated, but the fate of its actual dissidents.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-kafkaesque-imprisonment-of-julian</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Woke Have No Vision of the Future</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Today's SJWs believe all that needs to be done to bring about a new world is to destroy the old one]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/the-woke-have-no-vision-of-the-future-2/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Approves Sale of $290m in Bombs to Saudi Arabia</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Arms deals with Middle East dictatorships are being rushed through by Trump, critics say, despite opposition over human rights records]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/30/us-approves-sale-of-290m-in-bombs-to-saudi-arabia</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Pardon of Blackwater Iraq Contractors Violates International Law - UN</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. President Donald Trump's pardon of four American men convicted of killing Iraqi civilians while working as contractors in 2007 violated U.S. obligations under international law, U.N. human rights experts said on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iraq-blackwater-un/trump-pardon-of-blackwater-iraq-contractors-violates-international-law-un-idUSKBN294108</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Coronavirus Variant Is in the U.S.—Now What?</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over the past 24 hours, health officials in Colorado have reported finding two suspected cases of covid-19 caused by a worrying new variant of the coronavirus.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/the-new-coronavirus-variant-is-in-the-u-s-now-what-1845967832</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nearly All Inmates in Alaska's Largest Prison Have Contracted Covid-19</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[About 1,115 prisoners of the the total 1,236 prisoners at the Goose Creek correctional center had tested positive]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/30/alaska-prison-inmates-contract-covid</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Liberals Rarely Defend Liberalism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Don't kid yourself, the woke crocodile is coming for you too]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/why-wont-liberals-defend-liberalism-2/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2020 Had Its Share of Memorable Hacks and Breaches. Here Are the Top 10</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The past 12 months teaches us that, yes, attacks do only get better.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/12/2020-had-its-share-of-merorable-hacks-and-breaches-here-are-the-top-10/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Your Digital Trails Wind Up in the Police's Hands</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Phone calls. Web searches. Location tracks. Smart speaker requests. They've become crucial tools for law enforcement, while users often are unaware.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/your-digital-trails-polices-hands/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'I Was Never More Hated Than When I Tried to Be Honest'</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Ralph Ellison, author of the timeless American classic Invisible Man, was among the most commanding black literary voices to emerge in the 20th century. It is a designation he would almost certainly have resented. Ellison didn't see his work through the prism of his racial identity but as a means of…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/28/i-was-never-more-hated-than-when-i-tried-to-be-honest/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Plastic Pipes Are Polluting Drinking Water Systems After Wildfires</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[And it's a risk in urban fires, too.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/12/plastic-pipes-are-polluting-drinking-water-systems-after-wildfires/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thousands of Birds Starved to Death This Fall in the U.S. South</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This past autumn, people all across the U.S. southwest were finding an astounding number of dead birds littered along roads, on golf courses, and in their own driveways. Some estimated that hundreds of thousands of the creatures perished. Months later, new findings are shedding a little more light o…]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/thousands-of-birds-starved-to-death-this-fall-in-the-u-1845956292</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Threat of Authoritarianism in the U.S. Is Very Real, and Has Nothing to Do With Trump</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The COVID-driven centralization of economic power and information control in the hands of a few corporate monopolies poses enduring threats to political freedom.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-threat-of-authoritarianism-in</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists Turn CO2 Into Jet Fuel</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists have turned CO2 into jet fuel, hinting at a future where aircraft could have net zero emissions without relying on electric motors.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/co2-converted-into-jet-fuel-224318943.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fusion Energy Device Sets a Record by Running for 20 Seconds</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Korean fusion device has set a record by running for 20 seconds at 180 million degrees.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/kstar-fusion-device-sets-record-210817623.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On Sex and Gender, the New England Journal of Medicine Has Abandoned Its Scientific Mission</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two years ago, 'Titania McGrath,' whose satirical Twitter account regularly skewers the ideological excesses of social-justice culture, suggested that 'we should remove biological sex from birth certificates altogether to prevent any more mistakes.' The joke (obvious to those who follow the culture …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/23/on-sex-and-gender-the-new-england-journal-of-medicine-has-abandoned-its-scientific-mission/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Even Homer Gets Mobbed</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Massachusetts school has banned 'The Odyssey.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/even-homer-gets-mobbed-11609095872</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>She Noticed $200 Million Missing, Then She Was Fired</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Alice Stebbins was hired to fix the finances of California's powerful utility regulator. She was fired after finding $200 million for the state's deaf, blind and poor residents was missing.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/she-noticed-200-million-missing-then-she-was-fired</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hack Infected Critical Infrastructure, Including Power Industry</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The companies involved used compromised software, but it's not clear if hackers entered their networks. Finding out could be difficult.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/24/solarwinds-hack-power-infrastructure/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Cyber Agency Says SolarWinds Hackers Are 'Impacting' State, Local Governments</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cybersecurity agency said on Wednesday that a sprawling cyber espionage campaign made public earlier this month is affecting state and local governments, although it released few additional details.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-global-cyber-usa/u-s-cyber-agency-says-solarwinds-hackers-are-impacting-state-local-governments-idUSKBN28Y09L</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Olivia Katbi-Smith</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An activist for the Democratic Socialists for America tells of a cycle of bans]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-olivia-katbi-smith</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Powerful Mobile Phone Surveillance Tool Operates in Obscurity Across the Country</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[CellHawk helps law enforcement visualize large quantities of information collected by cellular towers and providers.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/23/police-phone-surveillance-dragnet-cellhawk/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Sued Blackwater for the Massacre of Iraqi Civilians. Trump Just Pardoned Those Convicted Killers.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trump's pardon of the Blackwater mercenaries who murdered 14 Iraqi civilians at Nisour Square shows the world what justice means in the United States.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/23/blackwater-massacre-iraq-pardons/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Snowden and Assange Deserve Pardons. So Do the Whistleblowers Trump Imprisoned.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Press freedom advocates must be careful not to indulge Trump's conspiracy theories while they lobby for whistleblower pardons.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/23/assange-snowden-whistleblower-pardons-espionage/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With Biden's New Threats, the Russia Discourse Is More Reckless and Dangerous Than Ever</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. media demands inflammatory claims be accepted with no evidence, while hacking behavior routinely engaged in by the U.S. is depicted as aberrational.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/with-bidens-new-threats-the-russia</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Justice Dept. Accuses Walmart of Fueling Opioid Crisis</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The 160-page civil complaint alleges the retailer knew its system for detecting illegitimate prescriptions was inadequate.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/22/business/walmart-opioid-lawsuit.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Leaked Documents Show How China's Army of Paid Internet Trolls Helped Censor the Coronavirus</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the coronavirus spread in China, the government stage-managed what appeared on the domestic internet to make the virus look less severe and the authorities more capable, according to thousands of leaked directives and other files.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/leaked-documents-show-how-chinas-army-of-paid-internet-trolls-helped-censor-the-coronavirus</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Brief Global History of the War on Cannabis</title>
			<source>The MIT Press Reader</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Prohibitionists around the world have long used rhetoric to associate the plant with violence and depravity.]]></description>
			<link>https://thereader.mitpress.mit.edu/a-brief-global-history-of-the-war-on-cannabis/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Types of Dark Pattern</title>
			<source>Dark Patterns</source>
			<pubDate></pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Dark Patterns have been categorised into 12 main types, including 'bait and switch', 'roach motel' and 'privacy zuckering'. All of them are manipulative techniques that aim to trick the user into doing something they didn't intend.]]></description>
			<link>https://darkpatterns.org/types-of-dark-pattern.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Poison Found in Everyone, Even Unborn Babies – and Who Is Responsible for It</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Chemicals called PFAS and PFOS – known as forever chemicals – are in the blood of virtually every person on the planet. And they will only accumulate]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/dec/17/dark-waters-pfas-ticking-chemical-time-bomb-in-your-blood</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DuPont and the Chemistry of Deception</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Aug 11, 2015</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Internal documents reveal that DuPont long suspected C8 was harmful, yet continued to put the company's workers and the public at risk.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2015/08/11/dupont-chemistry-deception/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Forever Chemicals' Pollute Water From Alaska to Florida</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Whichever state you are in, there could be harmful PFAS chemicals in water near you]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/22/forever-chemicals-pollute-water-dozens-of-sites-in-every-us-state</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Microplastics Revealed in the Placentas of Unborn Babies</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Health impact is unknown but scientists say particles may cause long-term damage to foetuses]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/dec/22/microplastics-revealed-in-placentas-unborn-babies</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Had to Pass a Law to Stop Telecom Monopolies From Charging You 'Rental Fees' for Things You Already Own</title>
			<source>Techdirt</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For much of the last few years, broadband customers have been complaining that Frontier Communications, the nation's third-biggest telco, had been charging its customers a rental fee for modems they already owned. Normally, you're supposed...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20201221/07075845926/we-had-to-pass-law-to-stop-telecom-monopolies-charging-you-rental-fees-things-you-already-own.shtml</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Peculiar Kind of Racist Patriarchy</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 21, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We are frequently told by commentators and theorists on the progressive and liberal Left that we live in a systemically racist and patriarchal society. The belief that Western societies privilege white men and oppress people of color, women, and LGBT citizens is especially popular within academic in…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/22/a-peculiar-kind-of-racist-patriarchy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK Coronavirus Variant May Be More Able to Infect Children: Scientists</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 21, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new variant of the coronavirus spreading rapidly in Britain carries mutations that could mean children are as susceptible to becoming infected with it as adults - unlike previous strains, scientists said on Monday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-variant-children-idUSKBN28V2F5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hospital CEOs Have Gotten Rich Cutting Staff and Supplies. Now They're Not Ready for the Next Wave.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Years of understaffing nurses and health care workers have consequences, experts say.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/20/covid-hospital-ceos-nurses/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Second Hacking Team Was Targeting SolarWinds at Time of Big Breach</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A second hacking group, different from the suspected Russian team now associated with the major SolarWinds data breach, also targeted the company's products earlier this year, according to a security research blog by Microsoft.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-solarwinds/second-hacking-team-was-targeting-solarwinds-at-time-of-big-breach-idUSKBN28T0U1</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Russia's SolarWinds Hack Is a Historic Mess</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[All the most important stories about the biggest hack in years.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/russia-solarwinds-hack-roundup/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK Says New Coronavirus Variant Up to 70% More Transmissible</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Following are details of a new coronavirus variant that has been identified in the United Kingdom, given at a news conference on Saturday by Prime Minister Boris Johnson, Patrick Vallance, the UK's chief scientific adviser, and Chris Whitty, the chief medical adviser.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-britain-variant-detai-idUSL8N2IZ0H7</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Battery Prices Have Fallen 88 Percent Over the Last Decade</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Cheaper batteries are making it easier to fight climate change.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/12/battery-prices-have-fallen-88-percent-over-the-last-decade/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wildfire Smoke Is Loaded With Microbes. Is That Dangerous?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers are putting out a call to study the potential effects of bacteria- and fungi-filled haze on human health.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-smoke-is-loaded-with-microbes-is-that-dangerous/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Successful Experiment Gets Us One Step Closer to a Quantum Internet</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This week, a joint team of researchers made up of scientists from Caltech, the Department of Energy's Fermilab, AT&T, Harvard University, NASA's Jet Propulsion Lab and the University of Calgary announced that they successfully teleported qubits of photons across approximately 27 miles of fiber-optic…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/fermilab-quantum-teleportation-report-221002594.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Instagram Is Using False 'Fact-Checking' to Protect Joe Biden's Crime Record From Criticisms</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Facebook-owned platform's denunciation of a well-established view of Biden shows the dangers of internet censorship and the fraudulent use of 'fact-checking.']]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/instagram-is-using-false-fact-checking</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Tied to Russia Hit Nuclear Agency; Microsoft Is Exposed</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. nuclear weapons agency and at least three states were hacked as part of a suspected Russian cyber-attack that struck a number of federal government agencies, according to people with knowledge of the matter, indicating widening reach of one of the biggest cybersecurity breaches in recent memory.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-17/u-s-states-were-also-hacked-in-suspected-russian-attack</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'We Are Slowly Being poisoned.' How Toxic Fumes Seep Into the Air You Breathe on Planes</title>
			<source>Los Angeles Times</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Times investigation found that vapors from oil and other fluids seep into planes with alarming frequency across all airlines, at times creating chaos and confusion.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.latimes.com/projects/toxic-chemicals-planes-covid-19-travel-woes/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ella Adoo-Kissi-Debrah: Air Pollution a Factor in Girl's Death, Inquest Finds</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Ella Adoo-Kissi-Debrah was 'living on a knife edge' before her fatal asthma attack, the inquest heard.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-london-55330945</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On Activist Scholarship: An Interview With Helen Pluckrose</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In recent years, free speech and inquiry have come under attack on college campuses, ethical relativism has spread, and demands to decolonize syllabi and rid them of canonical white male texts and thinkers have become increasingly common. Hostility to reason, objectivity, and Enlightenment universal…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/16/on-activist-scholarship-an-interview-with-helen-pluckrose/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cops Are Getting a New Tool for Family-Tree Sleuthing</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Verogen's push into public crime labs with genetic genealogy may help solve more cold cases, but it raises concerns about DNA data collection.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/cops-are-getting-a-new-tool-for-family-tree-sleuthing/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
