<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>oy6MRda-c1YmG7pzfUb47</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu May 27 2021 08:52:08 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>How Many People Die When Polluters Exceed Their Limits?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new report tallies the death toll from excess emissions by looking at air pollution and spikes in local ozone levels.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-people-die-when-polluters-exceed-their-limits/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Clearview AI Hit With Sweeping Legal Complaints Over Controversial Face Scraping in Europe</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>May 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Photos of faces were collected without clear consent.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22455446/clearview-ai-legal-privacy-complaint-privacy-international-facial-recognition-eu</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What a Wuhan Lab Leak Would Really Mean</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists and the media eagerly denounced credible evidence as a conspiracy theory]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/what-if-there-was-a-lab-leak/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook Ends Ban on Posts Asserting Covid-19 Was Man-Made</title>
			<source>WSJ</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook has ended its ban on posts asserting Covid-19 was man-made or manufactured, reflecting a deepening debate over the origins of the pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-ends-ban-on-posts-asserting-covid-19-was-man-made-11622094890</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Riot Erupts in Portland on Anniversary of George Floyd's Murder</title>
			<source>New York Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[More than 200 rioters — most fully clad in black and many wearing gas masks — trashed Portland soon after a peaceful march ended late Tuesday, according to the Portland Police Bureau (P…]]></description>
			<link>https://nypost.com/2021/05/26/portland-riots-on-anniversary-of-george-floyds-murder/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lab Asks FDA to Recall 78 Sunscreens Over Carcinogen Concerns</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A lab company called Valisure is sounding the alarm over a carcinogen that they've detected in common sunscreens. This week, the lab sent a petition to the FDA warning that it's found potentially unsafe levels of benzene in dozens of sunscreen products.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/testing-lab-asks-fda-to-recall-78-sunscreens-over-carci-1846977439</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Gathering Resistance to the Stigmatisation of Masculinity</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On the face of it, Brilliant Bob is an unremarkable character for a children's book—a playful boy who loves football and embarks upon fun adventures with his friends Dazzling Dave, Genuine Ge…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/26/the-gathering-resistance-to-the-stigmatisation-of-masculinity/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Education and Masculinity — An Interview With Will Knowland</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['What's the one thing we're not talking about but we really should be?' Triggernometry's Francis Foster asked now-sacked Eton teacher Will Knowland. 'I think the crisis of masculinity, …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/26/education-and-masculinity-an-interview-with-will-knowland/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jeffrey Epstein's Jail Guards Avoid Prison as Judge Approves Pact With Prosecutors</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two jail guards who admitted to falsifying records on the night Jeffrey Epstein killed himself on their watch won a federal judge's approval on Tuesday for an agreement to end the criminal case against them and let them avoid prison.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/jeffrey-epsteins-jail-guards-avoid-prison-judge-approves-pact-with-prosecutors-2021-05-25/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Calls for Second 'Transparent' Probe Into COVID Origins</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States called on Tuesday for international experts to be allowed to evaluate the source of the coronavirus and the 'early days of the outbreak' in a second phase of an investigation into the origins of the coronavirus.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/video/watch/us-calls-for-second-transparent-probe-in-idOVEEGTEXR</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>GCHQ's Mass Data Interception Violated Right to Privacy, Court Rules</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Human rights judgment follows legal challenge begun in 2013 after Edward Snowden's whistleblowing revelations]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/25/gchqs-mass-data-sharing-violated-right-to-privacy-court-rules</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mass Surveillance Must Have Meaningful Safeguards, Says ECHR</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>May 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The highest chamber of the European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) has delivered a blow to anti-surveillance campaigners in Europe by failing to find that bulk interception of digital comms is inherently incompatible with human rights law — which enshrines individual rights to privacy and freed…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/mass-surveillance-must-have-meaningful-safeguards-says-echr</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Greenland's Ice Sheet Is Releasing Huge Amounts of Mercury Into Rivers</title>
			<source>New Scientist</source>
			<pubDate>May 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As Greenland's ice grinds up underlying rocks it frees up the toxic mercury they contain, potentially contaminating the aquatic life that Indigenous communities rely on for food]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2278370-greenlands-ice-sheet-is-releasing-huge-amounts-of-mercury-into-rivers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>America Has Given Up on Impartial Justice</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A year after George Floyd's death, the powerless have been abandoned]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/the-day-american-justice-died/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lived Experiences Aren't Special</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Some time ago I found myself in the middle of a discussion about race relations and minority experiences. When it was my chance to speak, I mentioned some statistical data that appeared to challeng…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/24/lived-experiences-arent-special/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Fact-Checking' Takes Another Beating</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Fact-checkers are great, but the media business keeps trying to solve its credibility problem by misrepresenting what they do]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/fact-checking-takes-another-beating</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Agency Ran 'Rogue' Police Force, Spied on Americans' Social Media</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Commerce used counterintelligence tools to gather information about U.S. citizens and foreign visitors to the U.S., unauthorized surveillance that included the monitoring of Americans' Twitter accounts.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-agency-ran-rogue-police-force-spied-on-americans-1846955664</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wuhan Lab Staff Sought Hospital Care Before COVID-19 Outbreak Disclosed - WSJ</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three researchers from China's Wuhan Institute of Virology (WIV) sought hospital care in November 2019, a month before China reported the first cases of COVID-19, the Wall Street Journal reported on Sunday, citing a U.S. intelligence report.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/wuhan-lab-staff-sought-hospital-care-before-covid-19-outbreak-disclosed-wsj-2021-05-23/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. CDC Looking Into Heart Inflammation in Some Young Vaccine Recipients</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>May 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Some teenagers and young adults who received COVID-19 vaccines experienced heart inflammation, a U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention advisory group said, recommending further study of the rare condition.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/us-cdc-investigating-heart-problem-few-young-vaccine-recipients-nyt-2021-05-22/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Tech Firms Are Trying to Run Away From Politics — and Failing</title>
			<source>The Economist</source>
			<pubDate>May 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As other firms become more political, some Silicon Valley companies are heading in the opposite direction | United States]]></description>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/united-states/2021/05/22/why-tech-firms-are-trying-to-run-away-from-politics-and-failing</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Science Has Become a Cartel</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There's a reason the medical establishment dismissed the lab leak theory]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/how-scientists-sacrificed-scepticism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Corporate Media's Double Standard: They Attack Whomever They Want, but You Cannot Criticize Them</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[My responses to The Washington Post's article and Daily Beast's questions about accusations from The Intercept that I have 'endangered' their writers.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/corporate-medias-double-standard</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trauma and the Psychedelic Renaissance</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Military veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and the wildly imaginative British writer and philosopher Aldous Huxley are increasingly finding common ground. In 1954, Huxley publishe…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/22/trauma-therapy-and-the-psychedelic-renaissance/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Liberal Elites Use Race to Keep Workers Divided—and Justify Class-Based Inequities</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Pulitzer Center allegedly 'raises awareness of underreported global issues through direct support of quality journalism across all media platforms and a unique program of education and public o…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/20/how-liberal-elites-use-race-to-keep-workers-divided-and-justify-class-based-inequities/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New Replication Crisis: Research That Is Less Likely to Be True Is Cited More</title>
			<source>UC San Diego</source>
			<pubDate>May 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Papers in leading psychology, economic and science journals that fail to replicate and therefore are less likely to be true are often the most cited papers in academic research, according to a new study by the University of California San Diego's Rady School of Management.]]></description>
			<link>https://ucsdnews.ucsd.edu/pressrelease/a-new-replication-crisis-research-that-is-less-likely-be-true-is-cited-more</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Squad Enables Pelosi's Massive Capitol Police Spending Bill While Cynically Feigning Opposition</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three Squad members -- all of whom recently chanted 'Defund the Police' -- had the power to kill a $1.9 billion increase in Capitol Police and security spending. Instead, they ensured its passage.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-squad-enables-pelosis-massive</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Twenty Firms Produce 55% of World's Plastic Waste, Report Reveals</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Plastic Waste Makers index identifies those driving climate crisis with virgin polymer production]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/twenty-firms-produce-55-of-worlds-plastic-waste-report-reveals</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Despite Social Pressure, Boys and Girls Still Prefer Gender-Typical Toys</title>
			<source>Big Think</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Fifty years of research on children's toy preferences shows that kids generally prefer toys oriented toward their own gender.]]></description>
			<link>https://bigthink.com/surprising-science/gender-stereotyped-toys</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The End of Woke Is Nigh</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The new political correctness hasn't the power to overwhelm our existing order]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/the-end-of-woke-is-nigh/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Did Covid Come From the Lab? Mike Pompeo Says Yes.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Listen now (60 min) | An interview with the former secretary of state about the virus, China's ambitions, Iran, Israel, and the future of America.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/did-covid-come-from-the-lab-mike</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazon's Ring Is the Largest Civilian Surveillance Network the US Has Ever Seen</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[One in 10 US police departments can now access videos from millions of privately owned home security cameras without a warrant]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/18/amazon-ring-largest-civilian-surveillance-network-us</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Case for Using MDMA to Help Heal Victims of Trauma</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A psychiatrist explores how a drug often associated with Burning Man could be a breakthrough in treating PTSD.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/opinon-using-mdma-to-help-heal-victims-of-trauma/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Pharma Executives Mocked 'Pillbillies' in Emails, West Virginia Opioid Trial Hears</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Attorney says AmerisourceBergen executive showed 'contempt' as three companies in dock over crisis which has killed 500,000]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/amerisourcebergen-pillbillies-emails-west-virginia-opioid-trial-</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cancelling Comedians While the World Burns — A Review</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Review of Cancelling Comedians While the World Burns: A Critique of the Contemporary Left by Ben Burgis. Zero Books, 136 pages (May 2021). In 2013, British philosopher and cultural critic Mark Fish…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/05/17/cancelling-comedians-while-the-world-burns-a-review/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Long Working Hours Killing 745,000 People a Year, Study Finds</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>May 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization says the trend may worsen due to the coronavirus pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-57139434</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Navy Pilots Describe Encounters With UFOs</title>
			<source>60 Minutes</source>
			<pubDate>May 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Bill Whitaker reports on the regular sightings of unidentified aerial phenomena, or UAP, that have spurred a report due to Congress next month.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZBtMbBPzqHY</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Police Dog Who Cried Drugs at Every Traffic Stop</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Cops laugh about 'probable cause on four legs' but the damage to innocent lives is real.]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/05/13/the-police-dog-who-cried-drugs-at-every-traffic-stop/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nuclear Reactions at Chernobyl Are Spiking in an Inaccessible Chamber</title>
			<source>New Scientist</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Subreactor room 305/2, which has been inaccessible since the Chernobyl meltdown 35 years ago, is emitting neutrons that point to a growing nuclear fission reaction]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2277195-nuclear-reactions-at-chernobyl-are-spiking-in-an-inaccessible-chamber/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Is Systemic Racism?</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[John McWhorter, Lara Bazelon, Glenn Loury, Kmele Foster, Chloé Valdary and Kenny Xu weigh in.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/what-is-systemic-racism</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>America's True Believers and Their Gutless Enablers</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Don't blame the children of Park Slope and Echo Park for the nonsense. Blame those adults with the power to stop it.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/americas-true-believers-and-their</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White People Don't Have a Monopoly on Hatred</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I know. I once held bigoted beliefs myself.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/white-people-dont-have-a-monopoly</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dissidents and Doublethinkers in Our Democracy</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Plus: a new organization picking up the flag the ACLU has put down.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/dissidents-and-doublethinkers-in</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>There Is No Such Thing as 'White' Math</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I naively believed that STEM would be spared from the ideological takeover. I was wrong, says Princeton professor Sergiu Klainerman.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/there-is-no-such-thing-as-white-math</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lincoln Isn't Evil. Neither Is the West. Stand Up to the Woke Lies.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[My front-page column in today's New York Post. Plus: Ayaan Hirsi Ali.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/lincoln-isnt-evil-neither-is-the</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Schools Must Resist Destructive Anti-Racist Demands</title>
			<source>The Atlantic</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Contrary to what activists seem to believe, campuses are not bastions of social injustice.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/01/when-antiracist-manifestos-become-antiracist-wrecking-balls/617841/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Divers Haul 200lb of Trash From Lake Tahoe in a Day</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scuba team launches six-month effort that has already turned up fishing rods, tires and cans]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/lake-tahoe-cleanup-trash-scuba-divers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Scientists' [Finally] Want a Serious Investigation Into the Origins of the Coronavirus</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists in several countries are calling for a serious investigation into the beginnings of SARS-CoV-2, the novel coronavirus that gave rise to the covid-19 pandemic. In an open letter released Thursday, the group says that there are still too many unanswered questions about how the pandemic star…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/scientists-want-a-serious-investigation-into-the-origin-1846899382</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pentagon Is Tracking US Citizens Without a Warrant, Senator Says</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Pentagon may be using commercial data to track Americans without due legal process, according to a letter from Senator Ron Wyden..]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/the-pentagon-is-doing-warrantless-us-surveillance-ron-wyden-101201315.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Study Finds Alarming Levels of 'Forever Chemicals' in US Mothers' Breast Milk</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Toxic chemicals known as PFAS found in all 50 samples tested at levels nearly 2,000 times what is considered safe in drinking water]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/13/pfas-forever-chemicals-breast-milk-us-study</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chemical Giants Hid Dangers of 'Forever Chemicals' in Food Packaging</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The chemicals, called 6:2 FTOH, are now linked to a range of serious health issues, and Americans are still being exposed to them]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/chemical-giants-hid-dangers-pfas-forever-chemicals-food-packaging-dupont</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Solar Pushback: How US Power Firms Try to Make People Pay for Going Green</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In states such as Kansas, energy companies are seeking to impose financial charges on people who install rooftop solar arrays]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/13/solar-power-us-utility-companies-kansas</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC's Attack on Yang's Meaningless Israel Statement Shows Her Role: Protect Dem Leaders</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Real power over U.S. policy toward Israel and Gaza rests with Biden, Harris, Pelosi, Schumer, Blinken -- not Yang. But AOC's function is to shield them from leftist anger.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/aocs-attack-on-yangs-meaningless</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Neural Implant Lets Paralyzed Person Type by Imagining Writing</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A paralyzed individual hit 90 characters per minute, 99% accuracy.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/neural-implant-lets-paralyzed-person-type-by-imagining-writing/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Better Than Holograms: 3D-Animated Starships Can Be Viewed From Any Angle</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unlike holograms, the optical trap display produces images viewable from all angles.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/scientists-created-tiny-animated-starships-light-sabers-with-lasers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Millionaire CEOs Saw 29% Pay Raise While Workers' Pay Fell, Report Finds</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Workers saw 2% decrease as companies gave leaders bonuses and forgiving performance benchmarks amid pandemic]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/us-millionaire-ceos-saw-29-pay-raises-while-workers-had-decreases-report-says</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Will Science Survive Politics?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Whether something is politically convenient or not doesn't affect its truth]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/will-science-survive-politics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reporters Once Challenged the Spy State. Now, They're Agents of It</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[News companies are pioneering a new brand of vigilante reporting, partnering with the spy agencies they once oversaw]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/reporters-once-challenged-the-spy-a32</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air Pollution Linked to Increased Mental Health Outpatient Visits</title>
			<source>Yale School of Medicine</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[More pollution in the air could be linked to higher rates of mental health service utilization, researchers at the Yale School of Public Health found in a new]]></description>
			<link>https://medicine.yale.edu/news-article/air-pollution-linked-to-increased-mental-health-outpatient-visits/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tribalism Has Come to the West</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hostile and polarised, today's America reminds me of my Somalian clan]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/tribalism-has-come-to-the-west/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pentagon Inches Toward Letting AI Control Weapons</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Drills involving swarms of drones raise questions about whether machines could outperform a human operator in complex scenarios.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/pentagon-inches-toward-letting-ai-control-weapons/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bombshell Dossier Indicates China Has Been 'Preparing' for Bio-Warfare</title>
			<source>Sky News Australia</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A recently uncovered bombshell dossier suggests Chinese scientists have been 'preparing' for a Third World War fought with 'biological and genetic weapons – including coronavirus,' according to Sky News host Alan Jones. 'The paper by Chinese scientists describes these biological weapons as the core…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.skynews.com.au/details/_6253473578001</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antony Blinken Continues to Lecture the World on Values His Administration Aggressively Violates</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How can you feign anger over others' attacks on a free press when you imprison Assange as punishment for his vital revelations about U.S. officials?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/antony-blinken-continues-to-lecture</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Portland Man Recovering From Beating After Armed Standoff Amid Protest</title>
			<source>New York Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Portland Police are trying to sort out exactly what happened that ended up sending Joseph Hall, 53, to the hospital.]]></description>
			<link>https://nypost.com/2021/05/08/portland-man-recovering-from-beating-after-standoff-amid-protest/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Publishing Is Now a Left-Wing Bubble</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A letter filled with hysterical analogies indicates an industry in crisis]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/publishing-is-now-a-leftist-bubble/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's Carbon Pollution Now Surpasses All Developed Countries Combined</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As China's coal-reliant economy has boomed, so, too, have its emissions.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/chinas-carbon-pollution-now-surpasses-all-developed-countries-combined/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biggest ISPs Paid for 8.5 Million Fake FCC Comments Opposing Net Neutrality</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[ISP-funded astroturfing used millions of real names and faked consent records.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/biggest-isps-paid-for-8-5-million-fake-fcc-comments-opposing-net-neutrality/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Natural Gas Is Now More Deadly Than Coal in 19 States</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unhealthy air pollution generally brings to mind coal-fired plants spewing black soot. But that image may quickly be outdated. A study published on Wednesday in found that natural gas air pollution caused more deaths in 19 states than burning coal.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/natural-gas-is-now-more-deadly-than-coal-in-19-states-1846831696</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Successfully Lands a Starship Test Flight</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Given that it's meant to be the basis for a lunar lander, landing it is good.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/spacex-successfully-lands-a-starship-test-flight/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Signal Said Facebook Shut Down Its Advertising Account After the Privacy-Focused Messaging App Tried to Buy Instagram Ads Showing How the Social Media Giant Collects Data</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[CEO Moxie Marlinspike tweeted an example that shows how occupation, location, dietary preferences, and fitness interests can be used to target ads.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-blocked-signal-ads-data-collecting-targeting-2021-5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Tactics Police Are Using to Prevent Bystander Video</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Kian Kelley-Chung was wearing a black T-shirt with the logo of his documentary and art collective on the day last summer when he found himself filming the Washington, DC, police during a protest. It was August 13, 2020, and Kelley-Chung had been recording Black Lives Matter demonstrations in the cit…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/04/30/1024325/police-video-filming-prevention-tactics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Be It Resolved: The Mainstream Media Is Dying, and That's OK. Matt Taibbi Debates Ben Bradlee, Jr.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In Canada's 'Munk Debates' series, a civil discussion about the future of media]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/be-it-resolved-the-mainstream-media</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Corporate News Outlets Again 'Confirm' the Same False Story, While Many Refuse to Correct It</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Journalists with major outlets know they spread a false, retracted story about the FBI and Giuliani but refuse to remove it, because their real job is spreading disinformation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/corporate-news-outlets-again-confirm</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EPA to Eliminate Climate 'Super Pollutants' From Refrigerators, Air Conditioners</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hydrofluorocarbons saved the ozone layer, but they're killing the climate.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/biden-epa-proposes-rule-to-slash-use-of-climate-super-pollutants/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Havana Syndrome: NSA Officer's Case Hints at Microwave Attacks Since 90s</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When Mike Beck developed a rare form of Parkinson's US intelligence concluded he was the victim of a hi-tech weapon]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/02/havana-syndrome-nsa-officer-microwave-attacks-since-90s</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>When Will Activists (And the Media) Get Honest About Police Shootings?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Minutes before Derek Chauvin was convicted on all three counts of murder and manslaughter, Ma'Khia Bryant, a black teenage girl in Columbus, Ohio, was shot dead by police. Almost immediately, enrag…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/30/when-will-activists-and-the-media-get-honest-about-police-shootings/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Left Continues to Destroy Itself and Others With Evidence-Free Destruction of Reputations</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Equating accusations with proven fact is reckless and repressive. It is also standard behavior in liberal politics, whereby they ruin lives without a second thought.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-left-continues-to-destroy-itself</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Erased Decades of Historic Crimes in His Speech to Congress</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Biden's claim that the Capitol Riot was the 'worst attack on our democracy since the Civil War' is ahistorical garbage.]]></description>
			<link>https://outsidevoices.substack.com/p/biden-erased-decades-of-historic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Journal of Controversial Ideas Is Here</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The long-awaited first issue of Journal of Controversial Ideas (JCI), which allows academics of all disciplines to publish peer-reviewed research anonymously, has just been released. In an editoria…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/28/the-journal-of-controversial-ideas-is-here/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Court Rules That EPA's Delay 'Exposed a Generation of American Children' to Brain-Damaging Pesticide Chlorpyrifos</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ruling represents a stark repudiation of the Trump EPA's refusal to ban chlorpyrifos.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/29/chlorpyrifos-epa-brain-damage-children/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Satellites Show World's Glaciers Melting Faster Than Ever</title>
			<source>Associated Press</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Glaciers are melting faster, losing 31% more snow and ice per year than they did 15 years earlier, according to three-dimensional satellite measurements of all the world's mountain glaciers. Scientists blame human-caused climate change. Using 20 years of recently declassified satellite data, scienti…]]></description>
			<link>https://apnews.com/article/mountains-climate-climate-change-oceans-glaciers-64abe6a2ebb9793d8d695735128284ef</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Empire Politician: A Half-Century of Joe Biden's Stances on War, Militarism, and the CIA</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The new president's paper trail reveals a man who has often betrayed his own bedrock principles.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/28/empire-politician-a-half-century-of-joe-bidens-stances-on-war-militarism-and-the-cia/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Experian API Exposed Credit Scores of Most Americans</title>
			<source>Krebs on Security</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Big-three consumer credit bureau Experian just fixed a weakness with a partner website that let anyone look up the credit score of tens of millions of Americans just by supplying their name and mailing address, KrebsOnSecurity has learned. Experian says…]]></description>
			<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/04/experian-api-exposed-credit-scores-of-most-americans/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nestlé Threatened With Cease-and-Desist Over Alleged Illegal Water Use</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Company's claims hinge on how much water early-1900s rail cars carried.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/04/nestle-threatened-with-cease-and-desist-over-alleged-illegal-water-use/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High-Bandwidth Wireless BCI Demonstrated in Humans for First Time</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[BrainGate device complements Neuralink's successful test of wireless BCI in monkey.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/04/new-high-bandwidth-wireless-bci-helps-tetraplegics-use-tablet-computers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You Can't Cure Racism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Efforts to medicalise a social problem could be fatal]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/04/you-cant-cure-racism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN's New 'Reporter,' Natasha Bertrand, Is a Deranged Conspiracy Theorist and Scandal-Plagued CIA Propagandist</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the U.S. corporate media, the surest way to advance is to loyally spread lies and deceit from the U.S. security state. Bertrand is just the latest example.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/cnns-new-reporter-natasha-bertrand</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>25,000 Barrels of Suspected DDT Found Off the California Coast</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A known DDT dump site off the coast of Southern California is considerably larger than suspected, in a discovery that's sounding the alarm bells. Research by the Scripps Institution of Oceanography shows thousands of potentially toxic barrels on the seafloor.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/around-25-000-barrels-of-suspected-ddt-has-been-found-o-1846775004</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ACLU Again Cowardly Abstains From an Online Censorship Controversy: This Time Over BLM</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The once-principled group issues P.R.-scripted excuses or engages in obfuscation to avoid taking stances that would offend its liberal donor base.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/aclu-again-cowardly-abstains-from</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interview: Glenn Greenwald, on 'Securing Democracy,' Twitter, and the Media Business</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I tend to have a pretty polarizing effect on the discourse,' says the author, in a free-ranging talk about Bolsonaro's Brazil, his time at The Intercept, and critics who accuse him of being pro-Trump]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/interview-glenn-greenwald-on-securing-1bb</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grade Inflation Is Ruining Education</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['When people lose the connection between their actions and their consequences, they lose their hold on reality and the further this goes the more it looks like madness.' ~ Robert Greene A recent st…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/24/grade-inflation-is-ruining-education/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Slander Industry</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Who makes money from destroying reputations online?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/04/24/technology/online-slander-websites.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Crisis Has Shifted the Earth's Axis, Study Shows</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Massive melting of glaciers has tilted the planet's rotation, showing the impact of human activities]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/climate-crisis-has-shifted-the-earths-axis-study-shows</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pharmaceutical Industry Dispatches Army of Lobbyists to Block Generic Covid-19 Vaccines</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New lobbying disclosures show over 100 drug lobbyists working to defeat the IP waiver request at the WTO.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/23/covid-vaccine-ip-waiver-lobbying/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Heroic Congressional Fight to Save the Rich</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A handful of Democrats want to hold up a $2 trillion infrastructure bill to save a choice tax deduction for the wealthy, not that you'll hear it described that way]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-heroic-congressional-fight-to</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA Generates Oxygen on Mars, Setting Stage for Crewed Missions</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A device on the Perseverance rover produced roughly 5 grams of oxygen, a potentially huge leap for humanity and our aspirations on Mars.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/nasa-generates-oxygen-on-mars-setting-stage-for-crewed-1846739185</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Space Junk Is Our New Tragedy of the Commons</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unless countries overcome their differences and regulate the use of satellites, we’re all headed for trouble.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-04-17/space-junk-like-overfishing-and-pollution-is-a-global-tragedy-of-the-commons</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fukushima: Japan Announces It Will Dump Contaminated Water Into Sea</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Environmental groups and neighbours condemn plan to release more than 1m tonnes of contaminated water in two years' time]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/13/fukushima-japan-to-start-dumping-contaminated-water-pacific-ocean</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wall Street's Cooked Books Fueled the Financial Crisis in 2008. It's Happening Again.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This time, the issue is not a bubble in the housing market, but apparent widespread inflation of the value of commercial businesses, on which loans are based.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/20/wall-street-cmbs-dollar-general-ladder-capital/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psychedelics Are Transforming the Way We Understand Depression and Its Treatment</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Psychiatry has long failed to explain depression. Our research into psilocybin suggests a new approach, says researcher Robin Carhart-Harris]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/apr/20/psychedelics-depression-treatment-psychiatry-psilocybin</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Media Lied Repeatedly About Officer Brian Sicknick's Death. and They Just Got Caught.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Just as with the Russia Bounty debacle, they will never acknowledge what they did. Their audience wants to be lied to for partisan gain and emotional pleasure.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-media-lied-repeatedly-about-officer</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
