<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>SbEfa378LpaFl9V4sam-Q</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed Jul 14 2021 11:39:15 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>This Is How Democracy Dies</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If machines make all our decisions, who's in charge?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/07/this-is-how-democracy-dies/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Twitter Sees Jump in Govt Demands to Remove Content of Reporters, News Outlets</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Twitter Inc (TWTR.N) saw a surge in government demands worldwide in 2020 to take down content posted by journalists and news outlets, according to data released by the social media platform.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-twitter-sees-jump-govt-demands-remove-content-journalists-news-outlets-2021-07-14/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Health Official Says COVID-19 Boosters Could Risk More Serious Side Effects</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States is reviewing the need for a third COVID-19 booster shot among residents who have already been vaccinated but needs to see more data to know if additional shots could raise people's risk of serious side effects, a U.S. health official said Tuesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/us-health-official-says-covid-19-boosters-could-risk-more-serious-side-effects-2021-07-13/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Almost Four Decades After Its Birth, the Diversity Industry Thrives on Its Own Failures</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Campus diversity advocates have pulled off their greatest coup to date: They have declared 'diversity' to be a freestanding academic discipline, thus injecting their bureaucracy-heavy apparatus int…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/07/12/almost-four-decades-after-its-birth-the-diversity-industry-thrives-on-its-own-failures/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>E.P.A. Approved Toxic Chemicals for Fracking a Decade Ago, New Files Show</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The compounds can form PFAS, also known as 'forever chemicals,' which have been linked to cancer and birth defects. The E.P.A. approvals came despite the agency's own concerns about toxicity.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/12/climate/epa-pfas-fracking-forever-chemicals.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Strange Rehabilitation of the Black Panther Party</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Isn't it a little late for the rehabilitation of the Black Panther Party (BPP)? After all, the organization that first caught the public's attention in 1969 was already in its death thr…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/07/13/the-strange-rehabilitation-of-the-black-panther-party/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Puts New Warning on J&amp;J Coronavirus Vaccine for Autoimmune Disorder</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Food and Drug Administration on Monday added a warning to the fact sheet for Johnson & Johnson's (JNJ.N) COVID-19 vaccine saying that data suggests there is an increased risk of a rare neurological disorder in the six weeks after inoculation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-johnson-johnson/u-s-to-announce-new-warning-on-jj-coronavirus-vaccine-for-autoimmune-disorder-washington-post-idINKBN2EI1YP</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Witch Trial at the Legal Aid Society</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Maud Maron was a model public defender. Then she was forced out of her job because of her political views and her race.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/a-witch-trial-at-the-legal-aid-society</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Study Projects a Surge in Coastal Flooding, Starting in 2030s</title>
			<source>NASA Sea Level Change Portal</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the mid-2030s, every U.S. coast will experience rapidly increasing high-tide floods, when a lunar cycle will amplify rising sea levels caused by climate change.]]></description>
			<link>https://sealevel.nasa.gov/news/222/study-projects-a-surge-in-coastal-flooding-starting-in-2030s/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Solar Is Dirt-Cheap and About to Get Even More Powerful</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[After focusing for decades on cutting costs, the solar industry is shifting attention to making new advances in technology.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-05/solar-power-is-dirt-cheap-and-about-to-get-even-more-powerful</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Is 'Critical Race Theory' the Wrong Term?</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Are Republicans tilting at the wrong windmill? New Substack author Wesley Yang, who coined the term 'Successor Ideology,' describes a movement that goes far beyond race]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/is-critical-race-theory-the-wrong</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Could You Resist a Cult?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Many of us yearn to be told what to do]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/07/could-you-resist-a-cult/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Heat Dome' Probably Killed 1bn Marine Animals on Canada Coast, Experts Say</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[British Columbia scientist says heat essentially cooked mussels: 'The shore doesn't usually crunch when you walk']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/08/heat-dome-canada-pacific-northwest-animal-deaths</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global Wind and Solar Power Capacity Grew at Record Rate in 2020</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[BP's annual report reveals renewable energy boom in pandemic coincided with slump in demand for oil]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/08/bp-global-wind-and-solar-power-capacity-grew-at-record-rate-in-2020</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Capitol Police, Armed With $2 Billion in New Funding, Expanding Operations Outside of D.C.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[AOC and two other Squad members -- who spent months chanting 'Defund the Police' -- had the power to stop this, but instead voted 'present' to ensure it passed.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-capitol-police-armed-with-2-billion</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>15 States Reach a Deal With Purdue Pharma, Advancing a $4.5 Billion Opioids Settlement</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The states, including Massachusetts and New York, agreed to drop opposition to the bankruptcy organization plan of the company, the maker of OxyContin.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/08/health/purdue-pharma-opioids-settlement.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How All My Politically Correct Bones Were Broken</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In my first 10 years of college teaching, from the mid-60s to mid-70s, I modeled myself on my best teachers—men and women who questioned my ideas vigorously. They let me know that I mattered to the…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/07/07/how-all-my-politically-correct-bones-were-broken/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pacific Northwest Heat Wave 'Virtually Impossible' Without Climate Change - Research</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The suffocating heat wave that killed hundreds of people across the Pacific Northwest last week would have been 'virtually impossible' without climate change, a study has found.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/heat-wave-pacific-northwest-could-soon-repeat-due-climate-change-research-2021-07-07/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rep. Ken Buck (R-CO) Speaks Out on Reining in Big Tech and Why Many House Members Refuse</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As House Republicans vocally denounce Big Tech in media appearances, many simultaneously use their power to impede legislative reform. Rep. Buck is acting.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/rep-ken-buck-r-co-speaks-out-on-reining</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An Ugly War Among Leftist YouTubers Shows Two Common, Toxic Pathologies Plaguing U.S. Politics</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Baselessly accusing people of being Russian agents and weaponizing accusations of sexual misconduct are reputation-destroying cancers at the heart of liberal discourse.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/an-ugly-war-among-leftist-youtubers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lifting the Mask</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Edward Snowden on privacy, on liberty, on Substack]]></description>
			<link>https://edwardsnowden.substack.com/p/lifting-the-mask</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Companies Hit by 'Colossal' Cyber-Attack</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A cyber-security firm says it believes the Russia-linked REvil ransomware gang is responsible.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57703836</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Case of 'Intellectual Capture?' On YouTube's Demonetization of Bret Weinstein</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[YouTube's use of government guidelines to regulate speech raises serious questions, both about the First Amendment and regulatory capture]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/a-case-of-intellectual-capture-on</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Whistleblowers Expose Corruption in EPA Chemical Safety Office</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[EPA managers removed information about the risks posed by dozens of chemicals, according to whistleblowers.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/07/02/epa-chemical-safety-corruption-whistleblowers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Now Know How Exxon Secretly Fights Crackdowns on Plastic Pollution</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In a sting operation by Greenpeace UK, a top Exxon official admits Exxon's producing PFAS products and lobbying against anti-plastic laws.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/we-now-know-how-exxon-secretly-fights-crackdowns-on-pla-1847220288</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Scientists Hired by Big Oil Who Predicted the Climate Crisis Long Ago</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Experts' discoveries lie at the heart of two dozen lawsuits that hope to hold the fossil-fuel industry accountable for devastating damage]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/02/scientists-climate-crisis-big-oil-climate-crimes</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Fightback Against Critical Race Theory</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Its creators thought America was on their side — they were wrong]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/07/the-fightback-against-critical-race-theory/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Russian Hackers Are Trying to Brute-Force Hundreds of Networks</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[While SolarWinds rightly drew attention earlier this year, Moscow's Fancy Bear group has been on a password-guessing spree this whole time.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/fancy-bear-russia-brute-force-hacking/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exxon Lobbyists Reveal Climate Delay Strategy in Secret Recordings</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A sting by Greenpeace UK exposes how the company talks a big climate game while ensuring nothing actually gets done.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/exxon-lobbyists-reveal-in-secret-recordings-how-they-ma-1847205392</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ivermectin for Prevention and Treatment of COVID-19</title>
			<source>American Journal of Therapeutics</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Moderate-certainty evidence finds that large reductions in COVID-19 deaths are possible using ivermectin. Using ivermectin early in the clinical course may reduce numbers progressing to severe disease. The apparent safety and low cost suggest that ivermectin is likely to have a significant impact on the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic globally.]]></description>
			<link>https://journals.lww.com/americantherapeutics/Abstract/9000/Ivermectin_for_Prevention_and_Treatment_of.98040.aspx</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Our Endless Dinner With Robin DiAngelo</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Suburban America's self-proclaimed racial oracle returns with a monumentally oblivious sequel to 'White Fragility']]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/our-endless-dinner-with-robin-diangelo</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Pesticide Companies Corrupted the EPA and Poisoned America</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Pesticide manufacturers that have long dodged regulation by the EPA now face billions in damages for causing cancer, brain damage, and Parkinson's disease.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/06/30/epa-pesticides-exposure-opp/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conspiracy: In Theory and Practice</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Would you like to know a secret?]]></description>
			<link>https://edwardsnowden.substack.com/p/conspiracy-pt1</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On Victimhood and Culture — A Reply to Aaron Hanna</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It was a pleasure to read Aaron Hanna's recent essay, 'The Limitations of Black Conservative Thought.' It is magnificently reasoned, informed, and fair. Shelby Steele and Thomas Sowell have rarely …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/30/on-victimhood-and-culture-a-reply-to-aaron-hanna/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Advertisers Are Selling Americans' Data to Hundreds of Shady Foreign Businesses</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new report shows advertisers don't seem to have qualms with selling intimate consumer data to foreign companies, including those based in Russia and China.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/advertisers-are-selling-americans-data-to-hundreds-of-s-1847189522</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Tech's Threat to Democracy</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Can the US government tolerate the existence of a rival within its territory?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/06/big-techs-threat-to-democracy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lakes Are Losing Oxygen — and Their Inhabitants Are in Danger</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hundreds of temperate lakes around the world are showing trends toward anoxia, becoming warmer, murkier, and less hospitable to cold-water species.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/lakes-are-losing-oxygen-and-their-inhabitants-are-in-danger/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antiracism Won't Save You</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Robin DiAngelo's new book is self-help for narcissistic white people]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/06/antiracism-wont-save-you/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Bias Narrative Versus the Development Narrative: Thinking About Persistent Racial Inequality in the United States</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Quillette invited author and Brown University professor of economics Glenn Loury to respond to Aaron Hanna's recent critique of black conservatives. He replied: I read Hanna's long piec…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/27/the-bias-narrative-versus-the-development-narrative-thinking-about-persistent-racial-inequality-in-the-united-states/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Lawless Bombing of Iraq and Syria Only Serves the Weapons Industry Funding Both Parties</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. citizens derive no benefit, but instead suffer great loss, from endless war in the Middle East. But their interests are irrelevant to decisions of bipartisan Washington.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/bidens-lawless-bombing-of-iraq-and</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazon's Woke Smokescreen</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The new inclusion policy put out by Amazon Studios offers entries on 'womxn' and 'acquired limb difference.' Meantime, the company's drivers urinate in bottles.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/amazons-woke-smokescreen</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dangerous Heat Is Literally Melting Infrastructure in the Pacific Northwest</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The heat-caused damage in the Pacific Northwest is a stark sign of how screwed our infrastructure is when it comes to climate change.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/dangerous-heat-wave-is-literally-melting-critical-infra-1847186624</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mexico Marijuana: Top Court Decriminalises Recreational Use of Cannabis</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Adults will be able to cultivate and consume the drug, but smoking in public remains banned.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-57645016</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>When a Free Society Becomes a Police State</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For 26 years, the pro-democracy tabloid Apple Daily was a thorn in Beijing's side. This week, the paper closed for good. What its death means for Hong Kong — and for us all.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/when-a-free-society-becomes-a-police</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bearing Witness to the End of Hong Kong's Free Press</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[My conversation with an intrepid Apple Daily reporter.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/bearing-witness-to-the-end-of-hong</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CRISPR Gene Editing Breakthrough Could Treat Many More Diseases</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers have discovered that you can inject CRISPR gene editing directly into the bloodstream, potentially leading to effective treatments for many diseases..]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/crispr-gene-editing-blood-injection-213815705.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>YouTube Takes Down Xinjiang Videos, Forcing Rights Group to Seek Alternative</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A human rights group that attracted millions of views on YouTube to testimonies from people who say their families have disappeared in China's Xinjiang region is moving its videos to little-known service Odysee after some were taken down by the Google-owned (GOOGL.O) streaming giant, two sources tol…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-youtube-takes-down-xinjiang-videos-forces-rights-group-seek-2021-06-25/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>VIDEO: A New Book by Leftist Ben Burgis Explores Why the Left's Political Culture Is So Alienating</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Central to 'Canceling Comedians While the World Burns' is the question of whether the western left wants to win. Watch my 50-minute discussion with the author.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/video-a-new-book-by-leftist-ben-burgis</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Johnson &amp; Johnson Pays $230m to Settle New York Opioids Case</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Pharmaceuticals giant 'helped fuel fire', attorney general says, while company says settlement is not an admission of wrongdoing]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/johnson-johnson-new-york-opioids-case</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Breach New Victims, Including a Microsoft Support Agent</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Discovery came as Microsoft was investigating new breaches by the same hacker group.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/06/solarwinds-hackers-breach-new-victims-including-a-microsoft-support-agent/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Report on Pentagon-Documented UFOs Leaves Sightings Unexplained</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A major U.S. government report on UFOs released on Friday said defense and intelligence analysts lack sufficient data to determine the nature of mysterious flying objects observed by military pilots including whether they are advanced earthly technologies, atmospherics or...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/usa-ufos/u-s-report-on-pentagon-documented-ufos-leaves-sightings-unexplained-idUSL2N2O70ZS</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Is Behind Gen. Mark Milley's Righteous Race Sermon? Look to the New Domestic War on Terror.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The overarching ideology of Pentagon officials is larger military budgets and ongoing permanent war posture. Their new war target, explicitly, is domestic 'white rage.']]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/what-is-behind-gen-mark-milleys-righteous</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Standing Up to the Gender Ideologues: A Quillette Editorial</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On June 23rd, Britain's Royal Academy of Arts put out a carefully worded five-paragraph media statement regarding German-born textile artist Jess de Wahls. 'We have apologised to Jess de Wahls for …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/24/standing-up-to-the-gender-ideologues-a-quillette-editorial/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ivermectin: Can a Drug Be 'Right-Wing'?</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A potential Covid-19 treatment has become hostage to a larger global fight between populists and anti-populists]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/ivermectin-can-a-drug-be-right-wing-ca7</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Blood Test That Finds 50 Types of Cancer Is Accurate Enough to Be Rolled Out</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Diagnostic tool being piloted by NHS England shows 'impressive results' in spotting tumours in early stages]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/25/blood-test-that-finds-50-types-of-cancer-is-accurate-enough-to-be-rolled-out</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>First COVID-19 Case Could Have Emerged in China in Oct 2019 - Study</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The virus that causes COVID-19 could have started spreading in China as early as October 2019, two months before the first case was identified in the central city of Wuhan, a new study showed on Friday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/first-covid-19-case-could-have-hit-china-oct-2019-study-2021-06-25/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Half of UK University Students Think Degree Is Poor Value for Money</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Survey sheds light on level of anger at higher education institutes' response to pandemic]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/24/half-of-uk-university-students-think-degree-is-poor-value-for-money</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hospitals Are Selling Treasure Troves of Medical Data — What Could Go Wrong?</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It could help with research, but also comes with risks.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547397/medical-records-health-data-hospitals-research</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Covid: Ivermectin to Be Studied as Possible Treatment in UK</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists begin to give the drug to people at home with symptoms to see if it can keep them out of hospital.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-57570377</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Most Dangerous Censorship</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Invisible but present, and far from the eyes of the public]]></description>
			<link>https://edwardsnowden.substack.com/p/on-censorship-pt-1</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The 'Gender Supremacist' Threat to the Progressive Alliance: Part One of a Three-Part Series</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There have always been conflicts within the LGBT+ community. But the recent capture of Western political and cultural institutions by a faction of radicalized transgender activists presents a more …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/22/the-gender-supremacist-threat-to-the-progressive-alliance-part-one-of-a-three-part-series/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Conversation With Daniel Elder, the Choral Music Composer Who Was Cancelled for Opposing Arson</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On May 30th, 2020, amid an anti-police-brutality protest in Nashville, TN, several white protesters allegedly attempted to burn down the city's Metro Courthouse. In response, choral music com…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/22/a-conversation-with-daniel-elder-the-choral-music-composer-who-was-cancelled-for-opposing-arson/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saudi Operatives Who Killed Khashoggi Received Paramilitary Training in U.S.</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The training, approved by the State Department, underscores the perils of military partnerships with repressive governments.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/22/us/politics/khashoggi-saudi-kill-team-us-training.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate-Driven Coastal Flooding in the US Likely to Get Worse Suddenly</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Within a few decades, many areas of the US may see a rapid change in frequency.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/06/climate-driven-coastal-flooding-in-the-us-likely-to-get-worse-suddenly/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Books Are Already Burning</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The question is only: How long will decent people stand by quietly and watch it happen?]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/the-books-are-already-burning</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Political Trolling Twice as Popular as Positivity, Study Suggests</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Political social-media posts are twice as likely to go viral if they are negative, a study suggests.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-57558028</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Pee or Flush Drugs Into Waterways — Does That Matter to Aquatic Life?</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Many of the drugs we flush could change aquatic animal behavior—theoretically.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/06/we-pee-or-flush-drugs-into-waterways-does-that-matter-to-aquatic-life/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Problem Isn't Remote Working – It's Clinging to Office-Based Practices</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Do we need to go to offices? Work 9 to 5? At this unique moment in history, employers can rethink everything, says researcher Alexia Cambon]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/remote-working-office-based-practices-offices-employers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Bret Weinstein</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Canceled on campus for speaking his mind, he's now going through a sequel at the hands of Silicon Valley]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-bret-weinstein</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Has 'Ivermectin' Become a Dirty Word?</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At the worst moment, Internet censorship has driven scientific debate itself underground]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/why-has-ivermectin-become-a-dirty-7bd</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Questions About the FBI's Role in 1/6 Are Mocked Because the FBI Shapes Liberal Corporate Media</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The FBI has been manufacturing and directing terror plots and criminal rings for decades. But now, reverence for security state agencies reigns.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/questions-about-the-fbis-role-in</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What if We're Wrong?</title>
			<source>Areo</source>
			<pubDate>May 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What if the Earth isn't the centre of everything? What if the ancestors of humans once looked like monkeys, or were single-celled organisms? What if the continents move? These questions…]]></description>
			<link>https://areomagazine.com/2021/05/19/what-if-were-wrong/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA: Earth Is Absorbing an 'Unprecedented' Amount of Heat</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Breaking: Earth. No, seriously. It's breaking, according to new research from NASA.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/nasa-earth-is-absorbing-an-unprecedented-amount-of-hea-1847120967</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Are There Dangerous Levels of Arsenic and Lead in American Baby Food?</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An investigation found that popular baby food products are tainted with dangerous levels of chemicals. Yet not enough is being done about it]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/17/why-are-there-dangerous-levels-of-arsenic-and-lead-in-american-baby-food</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Defense Budget Is a Big Win for Hypersonic Weapons Contractors</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The fiscal year 2022 proposal includes $3.8 billion for the ultrafast weapons, but some arms control experts question their effectiveness.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/06/17/hypersonic-weapons-contractors-biden-defense-budget/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Backlash Against Gender Ideology Is Starting in Universities</title>
			<source>The Economist</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Academics are speaking up against the stifling of debate | International]]></description>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/international/2021/06/05/a-backlash-against-gender-ideology-is-starting-in-universities</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Survey Shows People No Longer Believe Working Hard Will Lead to a Better Life</title>
			<source>Insider Mag</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The 2020 Edelman Trust Barometer – now in its 20th year – has found many people no longer believe working hard will give them a better life.]]></description>
			<link>https://insidermag.net/survey-shows-people-no-longer-believe-working-hard-will-lead-to-a-better-life/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Most Hospitals Aren't Complying With Price Transparency Rule</title>
			<source>Axios</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[They're particularly unlikely to disclose negotiated rates and cash prices.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.axios.com/hospitals-price-transparency-costs-regulations-noncompliance-ebf6bd21-5709-4298-b67a-74c8a90a1ec1.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Is the Society for American Archaeology Promoting Indigenous Creationism?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In April, one of us—Elizabeth Weiss—gave a talk, titled Has Creationism Crept Back into Archaeology?, at the 86th Annual Meeting of the Society for American Archaeology (SAA). The 87-year-old SAA i…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/13/why-is-the-society-for-american-archaeology-promoting-indigenous-creationism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Some Americans Are Breaking Out of Political Echo Chambers</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A growing number of people are seeking a wider diversity of news sources or opinions contrary to their own to combat information silos within social media.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-americans-breaking-political-echo-chambers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Enduring False Narrative About the PULSE Massacre Shows the Power of Media Propaganda</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Politicians and activists should stop ratifying the fiction that Omar Mateen was motivated by anti-LGBT hatred. It dishonors the victims and obscures the real motive.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-enduring-false-narrative-about</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Critical Entities Targeted in Suspected Chinese Cyber Spying</title>
			<source>Associated Press</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[RICHMOND, Va. (AP) — A cyberespionage campaign blamed on China was more sweeping than previously known, with suspected state-backed hackers exploiting a device meant to boost internet security to penetrate the computers of critical U.S.]]></description>
			<link>https://apnews.com/article/government-and-politics-hacking-technology-business-7350235e07d46ba5afc1238b553ea4b9</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Makes Quantum Computing So Hard to Explain?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Before we can even begin to talk about these computers' potential applications, we need to understand the fundamental physics behind them.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/what-makes-quantum-computing-so-hard-to-explain/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump DOJ Obtained Data on Schiff and Swalwell, Two Long-Time Champions of Domestic Spying</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The two California Democrats join the long list of politicians who enable spying on ordinary citizens, then angrily object when they themselves are targeted.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/trump-doj-obtained-data-on-schiff</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Heart Inflammation in Young Men Higher Than Expected After Pfizer, Moderna Vaccines - U.S. CDC</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A higher-than-expected number of young men have experienced heart inflammation after their second dose of the mRNA COVID-19 shots from Pfizer/BioNTech and Moderna, according to data from two vaccine safety monitoring systems, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) said on Thursday…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/cdc-heart-inflammation-cases-ages-16-24-higher-than-expected-after-mrna-covid-19-2021-06-10/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Woke Don't Want to Save the World</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Evil does not matter to a movement that only cares about itself]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/06/the-woke-dont-want-to-save-the-world/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Allies Believe U.S. 'No Longer a Good Model of Democracy,' Poll Shows</title>
			<source>Newsweek</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new survey spanning 16 nations and regions, most of them U.S. allies, has shown the country's global image rebounded after President Joe Biden succeeded former President Donald Trump, but not a single country believed the United States any longer constituted a good example for democracy.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newsweek.com/allies-believe-us-no-longer-good-model-democracy-poll-shows-1599048</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Are Activists Protecting Asians From Hate—or Protecting Their Narrative of White Supremacy From Criticism?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Asia Society, the global NGO dedicated to 'forging closer ties between Asia and the West through arts, education, policy and business,' recently shared a video in which activist Manjusha P. Kulkarn…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/08/are-activists-protecting-asians-from-hate-or-protecting-their-narrative-of-white-supremacy-from-criticism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yet Another Media Tale -- Trump Tear-Gassed Protesters for a Church Photo Op -- Collapses</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[That the White House violently cleared Lafayette Park at Trump's behest was treated as unquestioned truth by most corporate media. Today it was revealed as a falsehood.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/yet-another-media-tale-trump-tear</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Wholesale Prices Rise at Fastest Pace Since 2009, PPI Shows, as Inflation Pressures Keep Building</title>
			<source>MarketWatch</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. wholesale prices increased sharply again in April and signaled that more inflation is bubbling up in the U.S. economy, just a day after another...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/u-s-wholesale-prices-rise-at-fastest-pace-since-2009-ppi-shows-as-inflation-pressures-keep-building-11620909721</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beijing's Useful Idiots</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Science journals have encouraged and enforced a false Covid narrative]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/06/beijings-useful-idiots/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Secret IRS Files: Trove of Never-Before-Seen Records Reveal How the Wealthiest Avoid Income Tax</title>
			<source>ProPublica</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[ProPublica has obtained a vast cache of IRS information showing how billionaires like Jeff Bezos, Elon Musk and Warren Buffett pay little in income tax compared to their massive wealth — sometimes, even nothing.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/the-secret-irs-files-trove-of-never-before-seen-records-reveal-how-the-wealthiest-avoid-income-tax</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No, Critical Race Theory Isn't a New Civil Rights Movement. (Just the Opposite)</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Critical Race Theory has become a prominent subject in American political discourse. Several state legislatures have advanced measures aimed at banning it from public schools, on the basis that its…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/06/no-critical-race-theory-isnt-a-new-civil-rights-movement-just-the-opposite/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coastal Arctic Sea Ice Is Thinning Faster Than Previously Thought</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Old maps of snow depth on the ice had led researchers to underestimate melting]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/coastal-arctic-sea-ice-is-thinning-faster-than-previously-thought1/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Brain-Computer Interface Smashes Previous Record for Typing Speed</title>
			<source>IEEE Spectrum</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Imagining writing-by-hand is faster than imagining moving a cursor in new BCI system]]></description>
			<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/biomedical/devices/braincomputer-interface-smashes-previous-record-for-typing-speed</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why We Should Welcome the Lab Leak Hypothesis</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Plagued by fear, scientists have failed to protect us]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/06/why-we-should-welcome-the-lab-leak-theory/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Artist and the Censor</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Only proponents of the concept of art for art's sake always can be depended on to oppose the censorship of art. The most robust argument against censorship lies not in appeals to Enlightenment valu…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/05/the-artist-and-the-censor/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pentagon Undercounts Civilian Casualties in New Report, Experts Say</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The annual report vastly understates civilians killed by the U.S. military, and condolence payments are not offered even in confirmed cases.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/06/03/pentagon-civilian-casualties-report/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'The Psychopathic Problem of the White Mind'</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Listen now (51 min) | A psychiatrist lecturing at Yale's Child Study Center spoke about 'unloading a revolver into the head of any white person that got in my way.']]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/the-psychopathic-problem-of-the-white</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Winners and Losers: The Global Economy After COVID</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jun 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The COVID-19 pandemic has transformed the world economy in ways that will be debated by pundits and future historians for decades to come. Yet, as hard as it is to predict a disrupted future accura…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/06/04/winners-and-losers-the-global-economy-after-covid/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
