<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>B5idEEbwCE_sCnuwSIPik</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed Feb 17 2021 11:25:30 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>After Pork Giant Was Exposed for Cruel Killings, the FBI Pursued Its Critics</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The agency, seeking information on an animal rights group, attempted to recruit a former truck driver as an informant, the truck driver says.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/17/fbi-iowa-select-pigs-whistleblower/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Targets Rare Earth Export Curbs to Hobble US Defense Industry</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Beijing asks industry executives if proposed restrictions will harm western contractors.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/02/china-targets-rare-earth-export-curbs-to-hobble-us-defense-industry/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'New Car Smell' Is the Scent of Carcinogens, and Even Short Trips May Overexpose Us</title>
			<source>ScienceAlert</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The average American spends almost one hour each day commuting to work, a number that adds up quickly.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.sciencealert.com/a-20-minute-commute-puts-you-at-risk-of-unacceptably-high-levels-of-carcinogens</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What the New York Times' Hit Piece on Slate Star Codex Says About Media Gatekeeping</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['Silicon Valley's Safe Space' has misinformed readers.]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/02/15/what-the-new-york-times-hit-piece-on-slate-star-codex-says-about-media-gatekeeping/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fake Amazon Reviews 'Being Sold in Bulk' Online</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Which? investigation found 10 sites offering fake Amazon Marketplace reviews from as little as £5 each.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-56069472</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With a Star Science Reporter's Purging, Mob Culture at the New York Times Enters a Strange New Phase</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Speaking recently at a Quillette Free Thought Lives event, Columbia University professor John McWhorter expounded on his thesis that social justice comprises an ersatz religion, complete with rites…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/09/with-a-star-science-reporters-purging-mob-culture-at-the-new-york-times-enters-a-strange-new-phase/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Untold History of America's Zero-Day Market</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The lucrative business of dealing in code vulnerabilities is central to espionage and war planning, which is why brokers never spoke about it—until now.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/untold-history-americas-zero-day-market/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>White House Cites 'Deep Concerns' About WHO COVID Report, Demands Early Data From China</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The White House on Saturday called on China to make available data from the earliest days of the COVID-19 outbreak, saying it has 'deep concerns' about the way the findings of the World Health Organization's COVID-19 report were communicated.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-usa-idUSKBN2AD0FX</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Billions in Pandemic Aid Was Swindled by Con Artists and Crime Syndicates</title>
			<source>NBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A senior federal law enforcement source said the fraud is so complex and multilayered that it will take months to develop a full accounting.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/how-billions-pandemic-aid-was-swindled-con-artists-crime-syndicates-n1257766</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers, Mason Jars, and the Psychedelic Science of DIY Shrooms</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The history of home cultivation methods of Psilocybe is more connected to early internet culture than you'd think.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/hackers-mason-jars-psychedelic-science-diy-shrooms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>LA Cops Tried Using Instagram's Copyright Filter to Stop Someone From Filming Them</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over the last several weeks, police in Beverly Hills have been caught on video seemingly trying to weaponize Instagram's copyright detection algorithms to get a prominent LA activist banned from the platform.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/beverly-hills-police-instagram-copyright-232013882.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Making the Profane Sacred</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['By making a statute and by defining blasphemy, the church sought to prevent discussion—sought to prevent argument—sought to prevent a man giving his honest opinion. Certainly a tenet, a dogma, a d…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/11/making-the-profane-sacred/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Long Hack: How China Exploited a U.S. Tech Supplier</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For years, U.S. investigators found tampering in products made by Super Micro Computer Inc. The company says it was never told. Neither was the public.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2021-supermicro/#</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Refuses to Give WHO Raw Data on Early Covid-19 Cases</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[WHO investigators said Chinese authorities wouldn't give them personalized data that could help them determine how and when the coronavirus first began to spread in China.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/china-refuses-to-give-who-raw-data-on-early-covid-19-cases-11613150580</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unspeakable Truths About Racial Inequality in America</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This is the text of a lecture delivered by the author as part of the Benson Center Lecture Series at the University of Colorado, Boulder, on February 8th, 2021. I am a black American intellectual l…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/10/unspeakable-truths-about-racial-inequality-in-america/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MIT Researchers Created a System That Prints Functional Drones and Robots</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[LaserFactory cuts out a shape, then adds circuitry and components.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/mit-laserfactory-system-drones-robots-electronics-150215803.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mediocrity Is Now Mandatory</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From stimulus to school admissions, leaders act as if ease is the only worthy goal.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/mediocrity-is-now-mandatory-11612724198</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beating Back Cancel Culture: A Case Study From the Field of Artificial Intelligence</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's easy to decry cancel culture, but hard to turn it back. Thankfully, recent developments in my area of academic specialty—artificial intelligence (AI)—show that fighting cancel culture isn't im…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/27/beating-back-cancel-culture-a-case-study-from-the-field-of-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Journalistic Tattletale and Censorship Industry Suffers Several Well-Deserved Blows</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The NYT's Taylor Lorenz falsely accuses a tech investor of using a slur after spending months trying to infiltrate and monitor a new app that allows free conversation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-journalistic-tattletale-and-censorship</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Uighurs: 'Credible Case' China Carrying Out Genocide</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A legal opinion concludes the Chinese government has shown an intent to destroy the Uighur minority.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-55973215</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wuhan Residents Remember Coronavirus 'Whistleblower' Doctor a Year After His Death</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A year after his death from COVID-19, residents in the Chinese city of Wuhan say they remain grateful to the 'whistleblower' doctor who first sounded the alarm about the outbreak before it received official recognition.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/reutersComService_2_MOLT/idUSKBN2A60AK</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Plans Starlink Phone Service, Emergency Backup, and Low-Income Access</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX's latest petition to the FCC details some of its Starlink plans.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/02/spacex-plans-starlink-phone-service-emergency-backup-and-low-income-access/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Leading Baby Food Manufacturers Knowingly Sold Products With High Levels of Toxic Metals, a Congressional Investigation Found</title>
			<source>CNN</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Internal documents from major baby food manufacturers show they tested and used ingredients with high levels of arsenic, lead, cadmium and mercury in the baby food they sold to parents, according to a congressional investigation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/04/health/baby-food-heavy-metal-toxins-wellness/index.html?utm_term=link&amp;utm_medium=social&utm_content=2021-02-04T19%3A00%3A14</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'More Weight': An Academic's Guide to Surviving Campus Witch Hunts</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the fall of 2020, I became the target of a cancellation campaign after I'd suggested that the best policy for a university seeking to support underrepresented groups, while staying true to its m…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/02/05/more-weight-an-academics-guide-to-surviving-campus-witch-hunts/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>American Cities Are Way Underreporting Their Carbon Footprints</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A modeling system called Vulcan shows that on average, cities across the country pollute 18.3 percent more than they've estimated.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/american-cities-underreporting-their-carbon-footprints/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mysterious California Sea Lion Deaths Linked to Toxic Synthetic Chemicals</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists say animals with higher levels of DDT, PCBs and others in their blubber are more prone to cancer triggered by herpes]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/01/california-sea-lion-deaths-cancer-toxic-chemicals</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electric Cars Would Save America Huge Amounts of Energy</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Electrifying the vehicle fleet would save more energy than we get from the entire power grid today.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2021-opinion-renewables-will-power-future-of-us-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Did the BLM Protests Against the Police Lead to the 2020 Spike in Homicides?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Serious crime, particularly murder, soared while everyone was supposed to be locked indoors. Between 2019—by no means a famously peaceful year—and 2020, homicides alone surged by 42 percent during …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/27/did-the-blm-protests-against-the-police-lead-to-the-2020-spike-in-homicides/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apple CEO Sounds Warning of Algorithms Pushing Society Towards Catastrophe</title>
			<source>ZDNet</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Tim Cook says there will be consequences to having 'rampant disinformation and conspiracy theories juiced by algorithms'.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/apple-ceo-sounds-warning-of-algorithms-pushing-society-towards-catastrophe/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Intelligence Claims China Wants to Steal Your DNA</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[China has been accused of stealing a lot of things from America: intellectual property, 'jobs and wealth,' even our role as the world's biggest jerk. Now, US national security officials warn that America's greatest adversary wants to steal our genetic makeup.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/u-s-intelligence-claims-china-wants-to-steal-your-dna-1846156502</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Suck It, Wall Street</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In a blowout comedy for the ages, finance pirates take it up the clacker]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/suck-it-wall-street</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social Media Damages Teenagers' Mental Health, Report Says</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Heavy social media use had a negative impact on wellbeing, the study found.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55826238</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Live Streamers</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Silicon Valley is shutting down speech loopholes. The latest target: live content]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-live-streamers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Status Coup</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Silicon Valley is shutting down speech loopholes. The latest target: live content]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-status-coup</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Worrisome New Coronavirus Mutations Are Emerging. Why Now?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Across the globe, SARS-CoV-2 is evolving ways to evade the immune system and become more infectious. Blown pandemic response plans are to blame.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/worrisome-new-coronavirus-strains-are-emerging-why-now/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air Pollution Linked to Higher Risk of Irreversible Sight Loss</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Large UK study found small pollution rise associated with more cases of age-related macular degeneration]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/26/air-pollution-linked-to-higher-risk-of-irreversible-sight-loss</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reflecting the Authoritarian Climate, Washington Will Remain Militarized Until at Least March</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The idea of troops in U.S. streets for an extended period of time -- an extreme measure even when temporary -- has now become close to a sacred consensus.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/reflecting-the-authoritarian-climate</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth Has Lost 28 Trillion Tons of Ice Since the Mid-1990s</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 25, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Melt has accelerated over recent decades, contributing to sea level rise]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earth-has-lost-28-trillion-tons-of-ice-since-the-mid-1990s/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No Qualified Immunity for Cops Who Made Stuff Up to Justify Seizing a Man's Phone for Twelve Days</title>
			<source>Techdirt.</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Here's an interesting decision [PDF] by the Eighth Circuit Court of Appeals. On one hand, it says cops can possibly hassle people for filming them if they can find almost any reason at all to justify it. On the other hand, it says they definitely...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20210106/18521446009/no-qualified-immunity-cops-who-made-stuff-up-to-justify-seizing-mans-phone-twelve-days.shtml</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The War on Privacy</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 8, 2001</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Five years ago, official abuses of secrecy were the scandal. Today, the scandal is you]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-war-on-privacy</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Sets New Record for Most Satellites on a Single Launch With Latest Falcon 9 Mission</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has set a new all-time record for the most satellites launched and deployed on a single mission, with its Transporter-1 flight on Sunday. The launch was the first of SpaceX's dedicated rideshare missions, in which it splits up the payload capacity of its rocket among multiple customers…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spacex-sets-new-record-for-most-satellites-on-a-single-launch-with-latest-falcon-9-mission</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Glenn Greenwald: 'Journalists Are Authoritarians'</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[What went wrong at the outlet he co-founded, what's wrong with the ACLU, and what might go wrong in the Biden administration]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2021/01/23/journalists-are-authoritarians/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electric Vehicles Close to 'Tipping Point' of Mass Adoption</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sales increase 43% globally in 2020 as plunging battery costs mean the cars will soon be the cheapest vehicles to buy]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/22/electric-vehicles-close-to-tipping-point-of-mass-adoption</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Intelligence Analysts Use U.S. Smartphone Location Data Without Warrants, Memo Says</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The disclosure comes amid growing legislative scrutiny of how the government uses commercially available location records.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/22/us/politics/dia-surveillance-data.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Moronic Firing of Will Wilkinson Illustrates Why Fear and Bad Faith Mob Demands Reign Supreme</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the prevailing climate, the rational choice is to avoid social scorn and ostracization no matter how baseless the grievances one must appease.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-moronic-firing-of-will-wilkinson</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Echo Chamber Era</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Trust in media is down, but if journalists don't listen to critics anyway, why should they care?]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-echo-chamber-era</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Forever Chemicals Are Widespread in U.S. Drinking Water</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Experts hope that with the incoming Biden administration, the federal government will finally regulate a class of chemicals known as PFASs]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/forever-chemicals-are-widespread-in-u-s-drinking-water/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Vertical Farms Grow Veggies on Site at Restaurants and Grocery Stores</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 21, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last month we reported that a huge vertical farming operation near Copenhagen in Denmark recently completed its first harvest. That setup uses hydroponics, but the veggies grown in Vertical Field urban farming pods take root in real soil.]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/good-thinking/vertical-field-urban-farm-geoponics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Palantir's God's-Eye View of Afghanistan</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The company's software can sift through enormous amounts of data, and those metrics can be used to make life-or-death decisions.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/palantirs-gods-eye-view-of-afghanistan/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social Media Bans Are Really, Actually, Shockingly Common</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Booting Trump didn't set a precedent. From Yelp to Uber to Airbnb, platforms regularly ban users and content, but too often behind the scenes.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-social-media-bans-are-really-actually-shockingly-common/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Could Lab-Grown Plant Tissue Ease the Environmental Toll of Logging and Agriculture?</title>
			<source>MIT News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[MIT researchers have proposed a method for growing plant-based materials, like wood and fiber, in a lab. The technology is still in early development but might one day help reduce the environmental footprint of some types of agriculture.]]></description>
			<link>https://news.mit.edu/2021/lab-grown-plant-tissue-0120</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Ongoing Collapse of the World's Aquifers</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When humans over-exploit underground water supplies, the ground collapses like a huge empty water bottle. It's called subsidence, and it could affect 1.6 billion people by 2040.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-ongoing-collapse-of-the-worlds-aquifers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The SolarWinds Hackers Used Tactics Other Groups Will Copy</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The supply chain threat was just the beginning.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/solarwinds-hacker-methods-copycats/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New SolarWinds Malware Strain Is Discovered</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SolarWinds: it's the hack that keeps on growing. On Monday, researchers announced the discovery of yet another malware strain used by foreign hackers to infiltrate a wide milieu of American government agencies and companies.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/a-new-solarwinds-malware-strain-is-discovered-1846087775</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Domestic War on Terror Is Coming</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[No speculation is needed. Those who wield power are demanding it. The only question is how much opposition they will encounter.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-new-domestic-war-on-terror-is</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Behind a Secret Deal Between Google and Facebook</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 17, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook was going to compete with Google for some advertising sales but backed away from the plan after the companies cut a preferential deal, according to court documents.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/17/technology/google-facebook-ad-deal-antitrust.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2020 Was the One of the Hottest Years on Record</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officials from NASA and NOAA say the warming of both the planet's air and water are driving weather disasters.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/2020-was-the-one-of-the-hottest-years-on-record/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Left Stranded: US Military Sonar Linked to Whale Beachings in Pacific, Say Scientists</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Islands surrounded by US military study area, including Guam and Saipan, call for activity that harms the whales to stop]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/16/left-stranded-us-military-sonar-linked-to-whale-beachings-in-pacific-say-scientists</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beyond Platforms: Private Censorship, Parler, and the Stack</title>
			<source>EFF</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last week, following riots that saw supporters of President Trump breach and sack parts of the Capitol building, Facebook and Twitter made the decision to give the president the boot. That was notable enough, given that both companies had previously treated the president, like other political...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/01/beyond-platforms-private-censorship-parler-and-stack</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Billionaires Add $1tn to Net Worth During Pandemic as Their Workers Struggle</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Companies' attempts at hazard pay have been paltry and fleeting as employees are threatened for protesting working conditions]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/15/billionaires-net-worth-coronavirus-pandemic-jeff-bezos-elon-musk</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Everything We Know Now About Schools, Kids, and Covid-19</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers are finally getting good data on how severely SARS-CoV-2 affects children and how they transmit it. What does it mean for reopening classrooms?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/everything-we-know-now-about-schools-kids-and-covid-19/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Antifa Thugs Shame America</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Andy Ngo's family came to the US to escape Communist tyranny — now he's fleeing a political mob]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/01/the-antifa-thugs-shame-america/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cult Nation</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[National politics has robbed us of our selves.]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/cult-nation-935</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Law Enforcement Gets Around Your Smartphone's Encryption</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research has dug into the openings that iOS and Android security provide for anyone with the right tools.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/smartphone-encryption-law-enforcement-tools/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tech Companies Are Profiling Us From Before Birth</title>
			<source>The MIT Press Reader</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Children today are the very first generation of citizens to be datafied from before birth. The social and political consequences of this historical transformation have yet to be seen.]]></description>
			<link>https://thereader.mitpress.mit.edu/tech-companies-are-profiling-us-from-before-birth/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump's Twitter Ban Obscures the Real Problem: State-Backed Manipulation Is Rampant on Social Media</title>
			<source>The Conversation</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Social media censorship in the US fails to tackle the rising trend of 'disinformation-for-hire' cyber troops.]]></description>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/trumps-twitter-ban-obscures-the-real-problem-state-backed-manipulation-is-rampant-on-social-media-153136</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nasa's Curiosity Rover: 3,000 Days on Mars</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Three thousand days and counting: Nasa's Curiosity rover continues its extraordinary exploration of Mars.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-55562150</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Arctic Ocean Is Teeming With Microfibers From Clothes</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists find an average of 40 microplastic particles per cubic meter of the northern water. The likely source? The synthetic clothing in our washing machines.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-arctic-ocean-is-teeming-with-microfibers-from-clothes/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Silicon Valley, in a Show of Monopolistic Force, Destroyed Parler</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the last three months, tech giants have censored political speech and journalism to manipulate U.S. politics, while liberals, with virtual unanimity, have cheered.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/how-silicon-valley-in-a-show-of-monopolistic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Mafia Is Thriving in Lockdown</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Chaos has always been an opportunity for organised crime — as Britain could soon find out]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/01/the-mafia-is-thriving-in-lockdown/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Plan to Build a Global Network of Floating Power Stations</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A lot of thermal energy is trapped in the ocean. An ex-NASA researcher has figured out how it might generate unlimited clean power for aquatic robots.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-build-a-global-network-of-floating-power-stations/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Shared Tricks With Known Russian Cyberspies</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Security researchers have found links between the attackers and Turla, a sophisticated team suspected of operating out of Moscow's FSB intelligence agency.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/solarwinds-russia-hackers-turla-malware/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Need a New Media System</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you sell culture war all day, don't be surprised by the real-world consequences]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/we-need-a-new-media-system</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Social-Media Oligopolists Are the New Railroad Barons. It's Time for Washington to Treat Them Accordingly</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In 1964, an Ohio Ku Klux Klan leader named Clarence Brandenburg told a Cincinnati-based reporter that his hate group would soon be holding a rally in a rural area of Hamilton County. In the filmed por]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/01/11/social-media-oligopolists-are-the-new-railroad-barons-its-time-for-washington-to-treat-them-accordingly/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Would It Take to Run a City on 100 Percent Clean Energy?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 09, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Most claims of running on 'clean' electricity come with caveats, and many technologies required for round-the-clock renewable energy aren't quite ready yet.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-it-take-to-run-a-city-on-100-percent-clean-energy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Violence in the Capitol, Dangers in the Aftermath</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[From the Cold War to the War on Terror: the harms from authoritarian 'solutions' are often greater than the threats they are ostensibly designed to combat.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/violence-in-the-capitol-dangers-in-bbe</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wednesday's Other Story</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On the case of Julian Assange, and fearing empire more than Trump]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/wednesdays-other-story</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EFF's Response to Social Media Companies' Decisions to Block President Trump's Accounts</title>
			<source>Electronic Frontier Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Like most people in the United States and around the world, EFF is shocked and disgusted by Wednesday's violent attack on the U.S. Capitol. We support all those who are working to defend the Constitution and the rule of law, and we are grateful for the service of policymakers, staffers, and other...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/01/eff-response-social-media-companies-decision-block-president-trumps-accounts</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change Is Turning Cities Into Ovens</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 07, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new model estimates that by 2100, cities across the world could warm as much as 4.4 degrees Celsius. It's a deadly consequence of the heat-island effect.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-turning-cities-into-ovens/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sealed U.S. Court Records Exposed in SolarWinds Breach</title>
			<source>Krebs on Security</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ongoing breach affecting thousands of organizations that relied on backdoored products by network software firm SolarWinds may have jeopardized the privacy of countless sealed court documents on file with the U.S. federal court system, according to a memo released Wednesday by the Administrative…]]></description>
			<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/01/sealed-u-s-court-records-exposed-in-solarwinds-breach/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Security Failures Enabled Trump Mob to Storm U.S. Capitol</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[By Joseph Tanfani, John Shiffman, Brad Heath, Andrea Januta and Mark Hosenball]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-election-capitol-security-insight/how-security-failures-enabled-trump-mob-to-storm-u-s-capitol-idUSKBN29C0R5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SolarWinds Hackers Accessed More Than 3,000 DOJ Email Accounts</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In yet another dastardly twist in the ongoing SolarWinds debacle, the U.S. Department of Justice announced Wednesday that hackers had accessed the inboxes of over 3,000 DOJ employee Microsoft email accounts.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/solarwinds-hackers-accessed-more-than-3-000-doj-email-a-1846001981</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Intelligence Agencies Say Russia Was Likely Behind the SolarWinds Hack</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 06, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The FBI, NSA and CISA say it'll take a lot of effort to fix the problem.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/us-intelligence-agencies-fbi-nsa-cisa-solarwinds-hack-russia-111518166.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Last Year Reusable Rockets Entered the Mainstream, and There's No Going Back</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 06, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['If Rocket Lab ever builds a new vehicle, it will fundamentally be reusable.']]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/01/last-year-reusable-rockets-entered-the-mainstream-and-theres-no-going-back/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gravity Energy Storage Will Show Its Potential in 2021</title>
			<source>IEEE Spectrum</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Gravitricity and Energy Vault are pioneering a radical new alternative to batteries for grid storage]]></description>
			<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/energy/batteries-storage/gravity-energy-storage-will-show-its-potential-in-2021</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers Find a Faster, More Efficient Way to 3D Print</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two researchers at Penn State have created a new system for five-axis additive 3D-printing that reduces the amount and density of support materials needed for making printed objects.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/researchers-find-a-faster-more-efficient-way-to-3d-pri-1845992030</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Blocks Entry to WHO Team Studying Covid's Origins</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 05, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Officials say visas not yet approved for World Health Organization delegation due to visit Wuhan]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/05/china-blocks-entry-to-who-team-studying-covids-origins</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This Year, Autonomous Trucks Will Take to the Road With No One on Board</title>
			<source>IEEE Spectrum</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The startup TuSimple is deploying tractor-trailers that drive themselves from pickup to delivery]]></description>
			<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/transportation/self-driving/this-year-autonomous-trucks-will-take-to-the-road-with-no-one-on-board</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Lab-Leak Hypothesis</title>
			<source>New York Magazine</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For decades, scientists have been hot-wiring viruses in hopes of preventing a pandemic, not causing one. But what if …?]]></description>
			<link>https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/coronavirus-lab-escape-theory.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Wokest News Stories of 2020</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When editors in 2020 weren't being fired in bunches, they were taking aim at everything from Beethoven to mermaids to skyscrapers]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-wokest-news-stories-of-2020-d14</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Mark Crispin Miller</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 04, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The NYU Professor becomes the latest academic to fall afoul of idea police]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-mark-crispin-miller</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Kafkaesque Imprisonment of Julian Assange Exposes U.S. Myths About Freedom and Tyranny</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The real measure of how free is a society is not how its mainstream, well-behaved ruling class servants are treated, but the fate of its actual dissidents.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-kafkaesque-imprisonment-of-julian</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Woke Have No Vision of the Future</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 31, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Today's SJWs believe all that needs to be done to bring about a new world is to destroy the old one]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/the-woke-have-no-vision-of-the-future-2/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Approves Sale of $290m in Bombs to Saudi Arabia</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Arms deals with Middle East dictatorships are being rushed through by Trump, critics say, despite opposition over human rights records]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/30/us-approves-sale-of-290m-in-bombs-to-saudi-arabia</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Pardon of Blackwater Iraq Contractors Violates International Law - UN</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. President Donald Trump's pardon of four American men convicted of killing Iraqi civilians while working as contractors in 2007 violated U.S. obligations under international law, U.N. human rights experts said on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iraq-blackwater-un/trump-pardon-of-blackwater-iraq-contractors-violates-international-law-un-idUSKBN294108</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Coronavirus Variant Is in the U.S.—Now What?</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over the past 24 hours, health officials in Colorado have reported finding two suspected cases of covid-19 caused by a worrying new variant of the coronavirus.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/the-new-coronavirus-variant-is-in-the-u-s-now-what-1845967832</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nearly All Inmates in Alaska's Largest Prison Have Contracted Covid-19</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[About 1,115 prisoners of the the total 1,236 prisoners at the Goose Creek correctional center had tested positive]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/30/alaska-prison-inmates-contract-covid</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Liberals Rarely Defend Liberalism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Don't kid yourself, the woke crocodile is coming for you too]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/why-wont-liberals-defend-liberalism-2/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2020 Had Its Share of Memorable Hacks and Breaches. Here Are the Top 10</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The past 12 months teaches us that, yes, attacks do only get better.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/12/2020-had-its-share-of-merorable-hacks-and-breaches-here-are-the-top-10/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Your Digital Trails Wind Up in the Police's Hands</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Phone calls. Web searches. Location tracks. Smart speaker requests. They've become crucial tools for law enforcement, while users often are unaware.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/your-digital-trails-polices-hands/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
