<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>zYrCmpnsjvnKmpOh7ZpTf</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun May 16 2021 07:45:35 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>Divers Haul 200lb of Trash From Lake Tahoe in a Day</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scuba team launches six-month effort that has already turned up fishing rods, tires and cans]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/lake-tahoe-cleanup-trash-scuba-divers</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Scientists' [Finally] Want a Serious Investigation Into the Origins of the Coronavirus</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists in several countries are calling for a serious investigation into the beginnings of SARS-CoV-2, the novel coronavirus that gave rise to the covid-19 pandemic. In an open letter released Thursday, the group says that there are still too many unanswered questions about how the pandemic star…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/scientists-want-a-serious-investigation-into-the-origin-1846899382</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pentagon Is Tracking US Citizens Without a Warrant, Senator Says</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Pentagon may be using commercial data to track Americans without due legal process, according to a letter from Senator Ron Wyden..]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/the-pentagon-is-doing-warrantless-us-surveillance-ron-wyden-101201315.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Study Finds Alarming Levels of 'Forever Chemicals' in US Mothers' Breast Milk</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Toxic chemicals known as PFAS found in all 50 samples tested at levels nearly 2,000 times what is considered safe in drinking water]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/13/pfas-forever-chemicals-breast-milk-us-study</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chemical Giants Hid Dangers of 'Forever Chemicals' in Food Packaging</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The chemicals, called 6:2 FTOH, are now linked to a range of serious health issues, and Americans are still being exposed to them]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/chemical-giants-hid-dangers-pfas-forever-chemicals-food-packaging-dupont</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Solar Pushback: How US Power Firms Try to Make People Pay for Going Green</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In states such as Kansas, energy companies are seeking to impose financial charges on people who install rooftop solar arrays]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/13/solar-power-us-utility-companies-kansas</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC's Attack on Yang's Meaningless Israel Statement Shows Her Role: Protect Dem Leaders</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Real power over U.S. policy toward Israel and Gaza rests with Biden, Harris, Pelosi, Schumer, Blinken -- not Yang. But AOC's function is to shield them from leftist anger.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/aocs-attack-on-yangs-meaningless</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Neural Implant Lets Paralyzed Person Type by Imagining Writing</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A paralyzed individual hit 90 characters per minute, 99% accuracy.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/neural-implant-lets-paralyzed-person-type-by-imagining-writing/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Better Than Holograms: 3D-Animated Starships Can Be Viewed From Any Angle</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unlike holograms, the optical trap display produces images viewable from all angles.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/scientists-created-tiny-animated-starships-light-sabers-with-lasers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Millionaire CEOs Saw 29% Pay Raise While Workers' Pay Fell, Report Finds</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Workers saw 2% decrease as companies gave leaders bonuses and forgiving performance benchmarks amid pandemic]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/us-millionaire-ceos-saw-29-pay-raises-while-workers-had-decreases-report-says</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Will Science Survive Politics?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Whether something is politically convenient or not doesn't affect its truth]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/will-science-survive-politics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reporters Once Challenged the Spy State. Now, They're Agents of It</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[News companies are pioneering a new brand of vigilante reporting, partnering with the spy agencies they once oversaw]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/reporters-once-challenged-the-spy-a32</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air Pollution Linked to Increased Mental Health Outpatient Visits</title>
			<source>Yale School of Medicine</source>
			<pubDate>Jan 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[More pollution in the air could be linked to higher rates of mental health service utilization, researchers at the Yale School of Public Health found in a new]]></description>
			<link>https://medicine.yale.edu/news-article/air-pollution-linked-to-increased-mental-health-outpatient-visits/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tribalism Has Come to the West</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hostile and polarised, today's America reminds me of my Somalian clan]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/tribalism-has-come-to-the-west/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Pentagon Inches Toward Letting AI Control Weapons</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Drills involving swarms of drones raise questions about whether machines could outperform a human operator in complex scenarios.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/pentagon-inches-toward-letting-ai-control-weapons/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bombshell Dossier Indicates China Has Been 'Preparing' for Bio-Warfare</title>
			<source>Sky News Australia</source>
			<pubDate>May 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A recently uncovered bombshell dossier suggests Chinese scientists have been 'preparing' for a Third World War fought with 'biological and genetic weapons – including coronavirus,' according to Sky News host Alan Jones. 'The paper by Chinese scientists describes these biological weapons as the core…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.skynews.com.au/details/_6253473578001</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antony Blinken Continues to Lecture the World on Values His Administration Aggressively Violates</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How can you feign anger over others' attacks on a free press when you imprison Assange as punishment for his vital revelations about U.S. officials?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/antony-blinken-continues-to-lecture</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Portland Man Recovering From Beating After Armed Standoff Amid Protest</title>
			<source>New York Post</source>
			<pubDate>May 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Portland Police are trying to sort out exactly what happened that ended up sending Joseph Hall, 53, to the hospital.]]></description>
			<link>https://nypost.com/2021/05/08/portland-man-recovering-from-beating-after-standoff-amid-protest/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Publishing Is Now a Left-Wing Bubble</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A letter filled with hysterical analogies indicates an industry in crisis]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/05/publishing-is-now-a-leftist-bubble/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's Carbon Pollution Now Surpasses All Developed Countries Combined</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As China's coal-reliant economy has boomed, so, too, have its emissions.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/chinas-carbon-pollution-now-surpasses-all-developed-countries-combined/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biggest ISPs Paid for 8.5 Million Fake FCC Comments Opposing Net Neutrality</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[ISP-funded astroturfing used millions of real names and faked consent records.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/biggest-isps-paid-for-8-5-million-fake-fcc-comments-opposing-net-neutrality/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Natural Gas Is Now More Deadly Than Coal in 19 States</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>May 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unhealthy air pollution generally brings to mind coal-fired plants spewing black soot. But that image may quickly be outdated. A study published on Wednesday in found that natural gas air pollution caused more deaths in 19 states than burning coal.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/natural-gas-is-now-more-deadly-than-coal-in-19-states-1846831696</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Successfully Lands a Starship Test Flight</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 5, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Given that it's meant to be the basis for a lunar lander, landing it is good.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/spacex-successfully-lands-a-starship-test-flight/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Signal Said Facebook Shut Down Its Advertising Account After the Privacy-Focused Messaging App Tried to Buy Instagram Ads Showing How the Social Media Giant Collects Data</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[CEO Moxie Marlinspike tweeted an example that shows how occupation, location, dietary preferences, and fitness interests can be used to target ads.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-blocked-signal-ads-data-collecting-targeting-2021-5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Tactics Police Are Using to Prevent Bystander Video</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 30, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Kian Kelley-Chung was wearing a black T-shirt with the logo of his documentary and art collective on the day last summer when he found himself filming the Washington, DC, police during a protest. It was August 13, 2020, and Kelley-Chung had been recording Black Lives Matter demonstrations in the cit…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/04/30/1024325/police-video-filming-prevention-tactics/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Be It Resolved: The Mainstream Media Is Dying, and That's OK. Matt Taibbi Debates Ben Bradlee, Jr.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 4, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In Canada's 'Munk Debates' series, a civil discussion about the future of media]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/be-it-resolved-the-mainstream-media</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Corporate News Outlets Again 'Confirm' the Same False Story, While Many Refuse to Correct It</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Journalists with major outlets know they spread a false, retracted story about the FBI and Giuliani but refuse to remove it, because their real job is spreading disinformation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/corporate-news-outlets-again-confirm</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EPA to Eliminate Climate 'Super Pollutants' From Refrigerators, Air Conditioners</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>May 3, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hydrofluorocarbons saved the ozone layer, but they're killing the climate.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/05/biden-epa-proposes-rule-to-slash-use-of-climate-super-pollutants/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Havana Syndrome: NSA Officer's Case Hints at Microwave Attacks Since 90s</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>May 2, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When Mike Beck developed a rare form of Parkinson's US intelligence concluded he was the victim of a hi-tech weapon]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/02/havana-syndrome-nsa-officer-microwave-attacks-since-90s</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>When Will Activists (And the Media) Get Honest About Police Shootings?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>May 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Minutes before Derek Chauvin was convicted on all three counts of murder and manslaughter, Ma'Khia Bryant, a black teenage girl in Columbus, Ohio, was shot dead by police. Almost immediately, enrag…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/30/when-will-activists-and-the-media-get-honest-about-police-shootings/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Left Continues to Destroy Itself and Others With Evidence-Free Destruction of Reputations</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>May 1, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Equating accusations with proven fact is reckless and repressive. It is also standard behavior in liberal politics, whereby they ruin lives without a second thought.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-left-continues-to-destroy-itself</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Erased Decades of Historic Crimes in His Speech to Congress</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Biden's claim that the Capitol Riot was the 'worst attack on our democracy since the Civil War' is ahistorical garbage.]]></description>
			<link>https://outsidevoices.substack.com/p/biden-erased-decades-of-historic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Journal of Controversial Ideas Is Here</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The long-awaited first issue of Journal of Controversial Ideas (JCI), which allows academics of all disciplines to publish peer-reviewed research anonymously, has just been released. In an editoria…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/28/the-journal-of-controversial-ideas-is-here/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Court Rules That EPA's Delay 'Exposed a Generation of American Children' to Brain-Damaging Pesticide Chlorpyrifos</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 29, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ruling represents a stark repudiation of the Trump EPA's refusal to ban chlorpyrifos.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/29/chlorpyrifos-epa-brain-damage-children/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Satellites Show World's Glaciers Melting Faster Than Ever</title>
			<source>Associated Press</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Glaciers are melting faster, losing 31% more snow and ice per year than they did 15 years earlier, according to three-dimensional satellite measurements of all the world's mountain glaciers. Scientists blame human-caused climate change. Using 20 years of recently declassified satellite data, scienti…]]></description>
			<link>https://apnews.com/article/mountains-climate-climate-change-oceans-glaciers-64abe6a2ebb9793d8d695735128284ef</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Empire Politician: A Half-Century of Joe Biden's Stances on War, Militarism, and the CIA</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The new president's paper trail reveals a man who has often betrayed his own bedrock principles.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/28/empire-politician-a-half-century-of-joe-bidens-stances-on-war-militarism-and-the-cia/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Experian API Exposed Credit Scores of Most Americans</title>
			<source>Krebs on Security</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Big-three consumer credit bureau Experian just fixed a weakness with a partner website that let anyone look up the credit score of tens of millions of Americans just by supplying their name and mailing address, KrebsOnSecurity has learned. Experian says…]]></description>
			<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/04/experian-api-exposed-credit-scores-of-most-americans/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nestlé Threatened With Cease-and-Desist Over Alleged Illegal Water Use</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Company's claims hinge on how much water early-1900s rail cars carried.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/04/nestle-threatened-with-cease-and-desist-over-alleged-illegal-water-use/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High-Bandwidth Wireless BCI Demonstrated in Humans for First Time</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[BrainGate device complements Neuralink's successful test of wireless BCI in monkey.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/04/new-high-bandwidth-wireless-bci-helps-tetraplegics-use-tablet-computers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You Can't Cure Racism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 28, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Efforts to medicalise a social problem could be fatal]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/04/you-cant-cure-racism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN's New 'Reporter,' Natasha Bertrand, Is a Deranged Conspiracy Theorist and Scandal-Plagued CIA Propagandist</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the U.S. corporate media, the surest way to advance is to loyally spread lies and deceit from the U.S. security state. Bertrand is just the latest example.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/cnns-new-reporter-natasha-bertrand</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>25,000 Barrels of Suspected DDT Found Off the California Coast</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 27, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A known DDT dump site off the coast of Southern California is considerably larger than suspected, in a discovery that's sounding the alarm bells. Research by the Scripps Institution of Oceanography shows thousands of potentially toxic barrels on the seafloor.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/around-25-000-barrels-of-suspected-ddt-has-been-found-o-1846775004</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ACLU Again Cowardly Abstains From an Online Censorship Controversy: This Time Over BLM</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 26, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The once-principled group issues P.R.-scripted excuses or engages in obfuscation to avoid taking stances that would offend its liberal donor base.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/aclu-again-cowardly-abstains-from</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interview: Glenn Greenwald, on 'Securing Democracy,' Twitter, and the Media Business</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I tend to have a pretty polarizing effect on the discourse,' says the author, in a free-ranging talk about Bolsonaro's Brazil, his time at The Intercept, and critics who accuse him of being pro-Trump]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/interview-glenn-greenwald-on-securing-1bb</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grade Inflation Is Ruining Education</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['When people lose the connection between their actions and their consequences, they lose their hold on reality and the further this goes the more it looks like madness.' ~ Robert Greene A recent st…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/24/grade-inflation-is-ruining-education/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Slander Industry</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 24, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Who makes money from destroying reputations online?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/04/24/technology/online-slander-websites.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Crisis Has Shifted the Earth's Axis, Study Shows</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Massive melting of glaciers has tilted the planet's rotation, showing the impact of human activities]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/climate-crisis-has-shifted-the-earths-axis-study-shows</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pharmaceutical Industry Dispatches Army of Lobbyists to Block Generic Covid-19 Vaccines</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New lobbying disclosures show over 100 drug lobbyists working to defeat the IP waiver request at the WTO.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/23/covid-vaccine-ip-waiver-lobbying/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Heroic Congressional Fight to Save the Rich</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 23, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A handful of Democrats want to hold up a $2 trillion infrastructure bill to save a choice tax deduction for the wealthy, not that you'll hear it described that way]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-heroic-congressional-fight-to</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA Generates Oxygen on Mars, Setting Stage for Crewed Missions</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 22, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A device on the Perseverance rover produced roughly 5 grams of oxygen, a potentially huge leap for humanity and our aspirations on Mars.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/nasa-generates-oxygen-on-mars-setting-stage-for-crewed-1846739185</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Space Junk Is Our New Tragedy of the Commons</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unless countries overcome their differences and regulate the use of satellites, we’re all headed for trouble.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-04-17/space-junk-like-overfishing-and-pollution-is-a-global-tragedy-of-the-commons</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fukushima: Japan Announces It Will Dump Contaminated Water Into Sea</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Environmental groups and neighbours condemn plan to release more than 1m tonnes of contaminated water in two years' time]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/13/fukushima-japan-to-start-dumping-contaminated-water-pacific-ocean</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wall Street's Cooked Books Fueled the Financial Crisis in 2008. It's Happening Again.</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This time, the issue is not a bubble in the housing market, but apparent widespread inflation of the value of commercial businesses, on which loans are based.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/20/wall-street-cmbs-dollar-general-ladder-capital/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psychedelics Are Transforming the Way We Understand Depression and Its Treatment</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 20, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Psychiatry has long failed to explain depression. Our research into psilocybin suggests a new approach, says researcher Robin Carhart-Harris]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/apr/20/psychedelics-depression-treatment-psychiatry-psilocybin</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Media Lied Repeatedly About Officer Brian Sicknick's Death. and They Just Got Caught.</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Just as with the Russia Bounty debacle, they will never acknowledge what they did. Their audience wants to be lied to for partisan gain and emotional pleasure.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-media-lied-repeatedly-about-officer</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More J&amp;J Troubles: Vaccine Manufacturing Halted and More Possible Clot Cases</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[CDC advisory committee will meet Friday to decide the fate of the troubled vaccine.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/04/more-jj-troubles-vaccine-manufacturing-halted-and-more-possible-clot-cases/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Anarchists Captured Portland</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Left-wing rioters are burning the city to the ground — while the police do nothing]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/04/how-anarchists-captured-portland/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA's Ingenuity Mars Helicopter Succeeds in Historic First Flight</title>
			<source>NASA</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 19, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Monday, NASA's Ingenuity Mars Helicopter became the first aircraft in history to make a powered, controlled flight on another planet. The Ingenuity team at the agency's Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California confirmed the flight succeeded after receiving data from the helicopter via NASA's…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-s-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-succeeds-in-historic-first-flight</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Journalists, Learning They Spread a CIA Fraud About Russia, Instantly Embrace a New One</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The most significant Trump-era alliance is between corporate outlets and security state agencies, whose evidence-free claims they unquestioningly disseminate.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/journalists-learning-they-spread</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The U.S. Could Have Left Afghanistan Years Ago, Sparing Many Lives</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[America will depart without having accomplished its goals and with more Afghan suffering ahead.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/16/afghanistan-withdrawal-forever-war-biden/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chemical Industry Lobbyist in Trump EPA Suppressed Evidence of Cancer Risk</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 16, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The EPA inspector general found that Bill Wehrum, who ran the agency's office of Air and Radiation, buried data about cancer risks from ethylene oxide pollution.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/04/16/epa-cancer-ethylene-oxide-bill-wehrum/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Spy Agencies Say the Future Is Bleak</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Climate change, technology, disease and financial crises will pose big challenges for the world, an intelligence report concludes.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/opinion/global-trends-intelligence-report.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia Finds Google Misled Users Over Data Collection</title>
			<source>CNBC</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The ACCC said it is seeking declarations, pecuniary penalties, publication orders and compliance orders but did not specify any amount.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/16/australia-finds-google-misled-users-over-data-collection.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Nation's Corn Belt Has Lost a Third of Its Topsoil</title>
			<source>Smithsonian Magazine</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers used satellite imaging and surface soil color to find out how much of the nutrient-rich earth has eroded away]]></description>
			<link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/scientists-say-nations-corn-belt-has-lost-third-its-topsoil-180977485/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mice Fed Fast Food Get Noticeably Stupider, Scientists Warn</title>
			<source>Futurism</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Diet seems to have a bigger impact on neurological health than scientists thought.]]></description>
			<link>https://futurism.com/neoscope/americanized-diets-linked-neurocognitive-dysfunction-doctors</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Credit Card Companies Are Tracking Shoppers Like Never Before: Inside the Next Phase of Surveillance Capitalism</title>
			<source>Fast Company</source>
			<pubDate>May 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the battle between data brokers and privacy advocates, the latest front is the credit card.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90490923/credit-card-companies-are-tracking-shoppers-like-never-before-inside-the-next-phase-of-surveillance-capitalism</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Humans Have Destroyed 97% of Earth's Ecosystems</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Only 3% of land on Earth still qualifies as 'ecologically intact,' with undisturbed habitats and healthy populations of its original animal species, grim new research shows.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/humans-have-destroyed-97-of-earths-ecosystems-1846691917</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google Earth Is Now a 3D Time Machine</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 15, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Google puts 20 petabytes of historical satellite data into the Google Earth globe.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/04/google-earth-is-now-a-3d-time-machine/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anti-Colonialism's Bad History</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Prevailing academic theories of race relations hold that wealth and power differences between groups of people arose from social, economic, and legal systems created to benefit one group of people …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/13/anti-colonialisms-bad-history/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psilocybin: Magic Mushroom Compound 'Promising' for Depression</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A study of 59 people compared the drug with a conventional antidepressant.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-56745139</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Navy Acknowledges Weird Footage of Unidentified Objects Flying Around Its Ships Is Real</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 14, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Pentagon has officially verified that night-vision video circulating of unidentified, triangular aerial craft swarming around the Navy's Arleigh Burke-class destroyer USS Russell in 2019 is real, as first reported last week by Mystery Wire.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/navy-acknowledges-weird-footage-of-unidentified-objects-1846684702</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Can You Teach Children to Be Anti-Racist?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In 1935, Richard Clarke Cabot, a professor of clinical medicine and social ethics at Harvard University, began one of the first randomized controlled experiments in the field of social science. In …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/13/can-you-teach-children-to-be-anti-racist/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Refuse to Stand by While My Students Are Indoctrinated</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Children are afraid to challenge the repressive ideology that rules our school. That's why I am.]]></description>
			<link>https://bariweiss.substack.com/p/i-refuse-to-stand-by-while-my-students</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The War Against Money-Laundering Is Being Lost</title>
			<source>The Economist</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The global system for financial crime is hugely expensive and largely ineffective | Finance & economics]]></description>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2021/04/12/the-war-against-money-laundering-is-being-lost</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Pauses J&amp;J COVID-19 Vaccine Over Rare Blood Clots</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. federal health agencies on Tuesday recommended pausing the use of Johnson & Johnson's COVID-19 vaccine for at least a few days after six women under 50 given the shot developed rare blood clots, dealing a fresh setback to efforts to tackle the pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-johnson-johnson-va/u-s-pauses-jj-covid-19-vaccine-over-rare-blood-clots-idUKKBN2C01BC</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big Corporations Now Deploying Woke Ideology the Way Intelligence Agencies Do: As a Disguise</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[By draping itself in the finery of political activism, the corporatist class consolidates political power, corrupts democracy and distracts from its real functions.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/big-corporations-now-deploying-woke</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Covid Dissidents Taking on China</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Beijing's science stooges are being unmasked by an international team of online sleuths]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/04/the-covid-dissidents-taking-on-china/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Global Business of Professional Trolling</title>
			<source>Axios</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Troll farms are a booming business in the developing world.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.axios.com/trolls-misinformation-facebook-twitter-iran-dd1a13b4-de1f-48cd-91a6-cac66202344b.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Data Brokers Are a Threat to Democracy</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Unless the federal government steps up, the unchecked middlemen of surveillance capitalism will continue to harm our civil rights and national security.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-data-brokers-are-a-threat-to-democracy/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Plastic Is Falling From the Sky. But Where's It Coming From?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At any given time, 1,100 tons of microplastic are floating over the western US. New modeling shows the surprising sources of the nefarious pollutant.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/plastic-is-falling-from-the-sky/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX's Falcon Heavy Rocket to Deliver an Astrobotic Lander and NASA Water-Hunting Rover to the Moon in 2023</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX is set to send a payload to the Moon in 2023, using its larger (and infrequently used) Falcon Heavy launch vehicle. The mission will fly a lander built by space startup Astrobotic, which itself will be carrying NASA's VIPER, or Volatiles Investigating Polar Exploration Rover (this is t…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/spacexs-falcon-heavy-rocket-to-deliver-an-astrobotic-lander-and-nasa-water-hunting-rover-to-the-moon-in-2023</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>100 Million More IoT Devices Are Exposed—and They Won't Be the Last</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 13, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Name:Wreck flaws in TCP/IP are the latest in a series of vulnerabilities with global implications.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/namewreck-iot-vulnerabilities-tcpip-millions-devices/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Mexico Becomes Latest State to Legalize Marijuana, a Rebuttal to America's 'Failed War on Drugs'</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Gov. Michelle Lujan-Grisham signed legislation on Monday that legalizes recreational cannabis and erases many past criminal convictions.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/new-mexico-becomes-16th-state-to-legalize-marijuana-for-adults-2021-4</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interview: Noam Chomsky</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 12, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On Biden vs. Trump, his new book, and why manufacturing consent 'is much easier now.']]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/interview-noam-chomsky-1a2</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Black Lives Matter, So Refund the Police</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[During the summer of 2020, following the deaths of George Floyd and Breonna Taylor, it was easier to count how many cities didn't have Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests than to count the ones that …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/12/black-lives-matter-so-refund-the-police/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Will Decolonizing the Curriculum Help the Poor and Dispossessed?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On February 8th, 2021, the Students of Color Liberation Front at the University of Michigan made a series of anti-racist demands, including a call to 'Decolonize the University of Michigan's pedago…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/10/how-will-decolonizing-the-curriculum-help-the-poor-and-dispossessed/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ecological Impacts of Solar Geoengineering Are Highly Uncertain</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 11, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research describes the unknowns in our knowledge of solar geoengineering.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/04/unknowns-linger-for-idea-of-scattering-sunlight-to-cool-the-earth/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Georgetown's Cultural Revolution</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 10, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sandra Sellers, an adjunct professor at Georgetown University's Law Center, was forced to resign because she was caught on video saying to her colleague and co-teacher David Batson: 'I hate t…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2021/04/09/georgetowns-cultural-revolution/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook Had Years to Fix the Flaw That Leaked 500M Users' Data</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Software makers can't catch every bug every time, but Facebook had ample warning about the privacy problems with its 'contact import' feature.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-data-leak-contact-import-flaws/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>More Than Half of Older Millennials With Student Debt Say Their Loans Weren't Worth It</title>
			<source>CNBC</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Even as the oldest millennials turn 40 this year and approach middle age, student debt continues to follow them.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/08/older-millennials-with-student-debt-say-their-loans-werent-worth-it.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Wireless Brain-Computer Interface Has Been Successfully Tested on Humans for the First Time</title>
			<source>TheNextWeb</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists say the Braingate device is the first high-bandwidth wireless brain-computer interface (BCI) to be demonstrated on humans.]]></description>
			<link>https://thenextweb.com/news/wireless-bci-brain-computer-interface-tested-on-humans-first-time-braingate</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Two Faces of Joe Biden</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The press is building an image of a 'radical' progressive hero, while reality looks a lot like the same corporate Democrat]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/the-two-faces-of-joe-biden-cec</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Gadgets Could Unlock the Potential of Lucid Dreaming</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Recent experiments show we can learn in our dreams. What else could we do with the right technology?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/how-gadgets-could-unlock-the-magic-potential-of-lucid-dreaming-150039868.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Neuralink's Brain-Computer Interface Demo Shows a Monkey Playing Pong</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 9, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Neuralink is building brain-computer interfaces, like the one that allows this monkey to control a game of Pong with its thoughts.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/monkey-mindpong-link-003709524.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We're Entombing the Earth in an Impenetrable Shell of Dead Satellites</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 8, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A recent study suggests that there is now nowhere on Earth free from the light pollution produced by overhead debris and satellites. Researchers expect that problem to only get worse as mega-constellations of internet-beaming mini-satellites, like SpaceX's Starlink program, take off.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/were-entombing-the-earth-in-an-impenetrable-shell-of-dead-satellites-163002560.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Japan Says Sorry, but It Has to Dump This Radioactive Water Into the Ocean</title>
			<source>Futurism</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['What to do with the [treated] water is a task that the government can no longer put off without setting a policy.']]></description>
			<link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/japan-sorry-dump-radioactive-water-ocean</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook Does Not Plan to Notify Half-Billion Users Affected by Data Leak</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook Inc did not notify the more than 530 million users whose details were obtained through the misuse of a feature before 2019 and recently made public in a database, and does not currently have plans to do so, a company spokesman said on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-data-leak-idUSKBN2BU2ZY</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nobody Will Win the Culture Wars</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 7, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Today's 'cancel culture' debates are designed to fail]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2021/04/nobody-will-win-the-culture-wars/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: The U.S. Right to Know Foundation</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Apr 6, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A nonprofit that investigates Genetically Modified Organisms and the origins of Covid-19 is the latest to see its traffic plunge after a search engine update]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-the-us-right-to</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Scientists Who Say the Lab-Leak Hypothesis for SARS-CoV-2 Shouldn't Be Ruled Out</title>
			<source>MIT Technology Review</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 18, 2021</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For many scientists, challenging the idea that SARS-CoV-2 has natural origins is seen as career suicide. But some say the idea it came from the Wuhan lab should still be discussed.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/03/18/1021030/coronavirus-leak-wuhan-lab-scientists-conspiracy/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
