<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>eSDgQJl5K8OPGFekfOXc7</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri Dec 11 2020 11:30:21 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Accessed Covid Vaccine Data Through the EU Regulator</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The European Medicines Agency has released limited details about the cyberattack.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/hackers-accessed-covid-vaccine-data-through-the-eu-regulator/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CISA and FBI Warn of Rise in Ransomware Attacks Targeting K-12 Schools</title>
			<source>ZDNet</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The percentage of ransomware attacks against K-12 schools increased at the beginning of the 2020 school year]]></description>
			<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/cisa-and-fbi-warn-of-rise-in-ransomware-attacks-targeting-k-12-schools/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hollywood Deployed Lobbyists to Win Exemptions to Strict California Lockdown</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The entertainment industry has been given extensive leeway during the pandemic, even as California now faces a stay-at-home order.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/11/hollywood-covid-filming-california-lockdown/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hackers Steal Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 Vaccine Data in Europe, Companies Say</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[U.S. drugmaker Pfizer and its German partner BioNTech said on Wednesday that documents related to development of their COVID-19 vaccine had been 'unlawfully accessed' in a cyberattack on Europe's medicines regulator.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-ema-cyber/hackers-steal-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-data-in-europe-companies-say-idUSKBN28J2Q7</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hunter Biden Tax Probe Examining Chinese Business Dealings</title>
			<source>Associated Press</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON (AP) — The Justice Department is investigating the finances of President-elect Joe Biden's son, including scrutinizing some of his Chinese business dealings and other transactions ]]></description>
			<link>https://apnews.com/article/hunter-biden-federal-tax-investigation-87c200c919aa61396b5d43077bc5b0ff</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Hunter Biden Criminal Probe Bolsters a Chinese Scholar's Claim About Beijing's Influence With the Biden Administration</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Professor Di Dongsheng says China's close ties to Wall Street and its dealings with Hunter both enable it to exert more power now than it could under Trump.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-hunter-biden-criminal-probe-bolsters</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With News of Hunter Biden's Criminal Probe, Recall the Media Outlets That Peddled the 'Russian Disinformation' Lie</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The now-validated facts about Hunter are precisely those the U.S. media -- in tandem with Silicon Valley and the intelligence community -- suppressed based on lies.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/with-news-of-hunter-bidens-criminal</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>One Small Step for Free Speech</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This week's Cambridge victory will do little to stop the march through the institutions]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/one-small-step-for-free-speech/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Diplomats' Brain Injuries May Be From Covert Microwave Attack, Experts Say</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Data from Russian experiments on pulsed RF energy offers best explanation.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/12/covert-microwave-weapon-most-plausible-cause-of-cuba-health-attacks/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Abigail Shrier</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Where is the line between boycott-based activism and corporate censorship?]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-abigail-shrier</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pandemic Villains: Robinhood</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Have a pair of gangly Stanford grads built the perfect mousetrap?]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/pandemic-villains-robinhood</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Progress Toward a Safer Psychedelic Drug to Treat Depression and Addiction</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A synthetic version of the psychedelic drug ibogaine appears to relieve depression and addiction without producing hallucinations or other dangerous side effects — at least in rodents.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/12/09/944572325/progress-toward-a-safer-psychedelic-drug-to-treat-depression-and-addiction</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Old Arctic Is Gone</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists have spent the past 15 years pulling together data about the Arctic into a report card. What's become clear in the 15 iterations of the report is nothing will be the same for centuries to come and the shifts are happening faster than anticipated.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/the-old-arctic-is-gone-1845834100</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Printable, Flexible Battery Offers 10 Times the Density of Lithium-Ion</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists investigating an experimental battery chemistry have wound up with a flexible device they say offers up to 10 times the energy density of current lithium-ion solutions, making it an ideal fit for a number of applications. The technique also allows for easier manufacturing of flexible…]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/energy/printable-high-density-batteries-silver-oxide/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Large Study of Americans Shows the Broad Health Problems Covid-19 Can Cause</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research out Tuesday looks to pin down the many health problems that can arise from a bout of covid-19. The long list includes more common ailments like pneumonia, kidney failure, and widespread inflammation, as well as rarer complications like serious heart inflammation, collapsed lungs, and se…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/large-study-of-americans-shows-the-broad-health-problem-1845832915</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Choice for Pentagon Chief Further Erodes a Key U.S. Norm: Civilian Control</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Gen. Lloyd Austin, on the Raytheon Board, is yet another high-level Biden nominee enmeshed in D.C.'s corporatist 'revolving door' of legalized influence-peddling.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/bidens-choice-for-pentagon-chief</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exclusive: U.S. Air Pollution Monitoring Network Falling Into Disrepair - GAO Report</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. air pollution monitoring network has fallen into disrepair after years of budget cuts and neglect, leaving tens of millions of Americans vulnerable to undetected bad air quality from events like wildfires to industrial pollution, according to a report by the investigative...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/usa-pollution-airmonitors-gao-idUSKBN28H1V5</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>California's Hellish 2018 Wildfires Cost the US Economy $148.5 Billion</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Two years later, we're still adding unfortunate superlatives to the 2018 California wildfire season. The latest is a new study that reveals the hidden toll of what—until this year—was the state's most destructive fire season.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/californias-hellish-2018-wildfires-cost-the-u-s-econom-1845824226</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exxon Holds Back on Technology That Could Slow Climate Change</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Carbon capture can make money for oil giants, and scientists say we need it. Is the industry willing to invest enough?]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-12-07/exxon-s-xom-carbon-capture-project-stalled-by-covid-19</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coca-Cola, Pepsi and Nestlé Named Top Plastic Polluters for Third Year in a Row</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Companies accused of 'zero progress' on reducing plastic waste, with Coca-Cola ranked No 1 for most littered products]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/dec/07/coca-cola-pepsi-and-nestle-named-top-plastic-polluters-for-third-year-in-a-row</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Quantum Device Performs 2.6 Billion Years of Computation in 4 Minutes</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Photons explore quantum maze faster than possible for any classical computer.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/12/un-computable-quantum-maze-computed-by-quantum-maze-computer/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Gets $886 Million From FCC to Subsidize Starlink in 35 States</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Charter also wins big; FCC fund will bring service to 5.2M homes and businesses.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>With Guns Drawn, Police Raid Home and Seize Computers of COVID-19 Data Whistleblower</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Florida fired her, and now it's raiding her home]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22160181/rebekah-jones-raid-seizure-search-warrant-covid-19-whistleblower-florida</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Health Care Is Coming to Grips With Its Pollution Problem</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Greenhouse gas emissions are on the rise.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22159555/health-care-pollution-climate-change</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The NSA Warns That Russia Is Attacking Remote Work Platforms</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A vulnerability in VMWare has prompted a warning that companies—and government agencies—need to patch as soon as possible.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/nsa-warns-russia-attacking-vmware-remote-work-platforms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Black and White in the Classroom</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[My palms were sweating, my heart was racing, and I avoided eye contact with everyone in that room, praying hard that my teacher would not call on me. And then, 'Lola, what are your thoughts?' was said out loud. I had many thoughts and ideas I knew needed to be spoken, stories I could share to change…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/07/black-and-white-in-the-classroom/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rehabilitation for Vice Bloggers</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This is a new center for bloggers to get back into the normal world (comedy sketch)]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7CxM1anfPE</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Should the US Be Afforded the 'Power of Assassination'?</title>
			<source>Al Jazeera</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The US government's argument it has the right to assassinate anyone, anywhere heralds its descent into despotism.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2020/12/6/why-should-america-be-afforded-the-power-of/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Enlightenment Literature as Foreign Aid</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['If God were to humiliate a human being,' wrote Imam Ali bin abi Talib in the sixth century, 'He would deny him knowledge.' If the woeful state of knowledge in lands beset by authoritarian regimes is any indication, a great number of human beings in our world have been lavishly humiliated, albeit by…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/04/enlightenment-literature-as-foreign-aid/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>After the Deep State Sabotaged His Presidential Bid, Bernie Sanders Mocks Those Who Believe It Exists</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Also ridiculing 'rigged elections' and 'fake news' -- two other weapons used on him -- the Vermont Senator's relationship to the Democratic Party descends from loyal support to abject subservience.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/after-the-deep-state-sabotaged-his</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Havana Syndrome' Likely Caused by Directed Microwaves - US Report</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The US report is the latest attempt to explain a mystery illness that affected diplomats in Cuba.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-55203844</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Used Patriot Act to Gather Logs of Website Visitors</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A disclosure sheds new light on a high-profile national security law as lawmakers prepare to revive a debate over it in the Biden administration.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/03/us/politics/section-215-patriot-act.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Is Massively Expanding Its Weather-Modification Program, Saying It Will Be Able to Cover Half the Country In artificial Rain and Snow by 2025</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Beijing said Tuesday that China's 'cloud seeding' project will soon cover 2.1 million of China's 3.7 million square miles.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/china-expanding-weather-modification-program-artificial-rain-snow-2025-2020-12</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Overcome Stress by Visualizing It as a Greedy, Hook-Nosed Race of Creatures</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Aug 8, 2010</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On Today Now!, author Christine Eckard teaches Jim and Tracy to imagine economic problems as oily, curly-haired 'Grabblers.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q4PC8Luqiws</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Who Will Biden Bomb First?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The President-elect's 'global leadership' is a return to neoconservatism]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/american-exceptionalism-is-back/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Student Loan Horror Stories: Borrowed: $79,000. Paid: $190,000. Now Owes? $236,000</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At 59, Chris pleaded for a renegotiation. 'My life expectancy is 15 more years. At this rate, you're not going to get very much...′ Their response was, 'So?'']]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/student-loan-horror-stories-borrowed</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Congress Stalls on Stimulus Checks for Families While Corporations Continue to Reap Millions From CARES Act</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The IRS is still issuing retroactive tax refunds to companies, many of which are thriving amid the coronavirus pandemic.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/04/covid-irs-corporation-tax-refunds/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Light-Based Quantum Computer Exceeds Fastest Classical Supercomputers</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The setup of lasers and mirrors effectively &ldquo;solved&rdquo; a problem far too complicated for even the largest traditional computer system]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/light-based-quantum-computer-exceeds-fastest-classical-supercomputers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'This Is Not Science Fiction,' Say Scientists Pushing for 'Neuro-Rights'</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientific advances from deep brain stimulation to wearable scanners are making manipulation of the human mind increasingly possible, creating a need for laws and protections to regulate use of the new tools, top neurologists said on Thursday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-global-tech-rights/this-is-not-science-fiction-say-scientists-pushing-for-neuro-rights-idUSKBN28D3HK</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Every Mayor, Governor Accused of Breaking COVID Restrictions — and Why</title>
			<source>Newsweek</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Austin Mayor Steve Adler joins a long list of leading politicians to have allegedly broken their own rules. Here's the rundown.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.newsweek.com/every-mayor-governor-caught-breaking-covid-restrictions-1552033</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Resisting the Mourner's Veto</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Controversy recently erupted at Penguin Random House when it was announced that the company would be publishing Canadian clinical psychologist Jordan Peterson's forthcoming book. Peterson rose to prominence in 2016 when he posted a series of videos on YouTube denouncing a Canadian law that, he claim…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/03/resisting-the-mourners-veto/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China Is National Security Threat No. 1</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Resisting Beijing's attempt to reshape and dominate the world is the challenge of our generation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/china-is-national-security-threat-no-1-11607019599</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feds Claim the Patriot Act Allowed Them to Log Visitors to Websites</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Letters produced by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence reportedly show that the U.S. government has interpreted Section 215 of the Patriot Act as giving it the power to monitor who visits certain websites and when, with minimal oversight.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/feds-claim-the-patriot-act-allowed-them-to-log-visitors-1845803993</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nation-State Backed Hackers Going After COVID Vaccine Supply Chain</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sophisticated operation is well-researched and well-placed, aimed at EU.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/12/covid-vaccine-supply-chain-targeted-by-hackers-say-security-experts/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Doctors Release 'Most Worrying Outlook' on Climate Change and Health</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The doctors are here to give the Earth its annual checkup, and they say it's running a fever which is making people sick. They issued their findings showing all the ways climate change is affecting our health in the annual Lancet Countdown on Wednesday.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/doctors-release-their-most-worrying-outlook-on-how-cl-1845794219</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Journey of Electronic Bottles and the Ocean Plastic Crisis</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers loaded containers with trackers and released them in the Ganges and the Bay of Bengal, giving new insight into how plastic pollution travels.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-incredible-journey-of-the-electronic-plastic-bottle/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Toxic PFAS Chemicals Discovered in Hundreds of Products</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Climbing ropes, guitar strings, and hand sanitizer are among the newly reported uses for the toxic 'forever' chemicals.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/12/02/pfas-chemicals-products/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Army Tested 'Germ Warfare' on the NYC Subway by Smashing Lightbulbs Full of Bacteria</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 14, 2015</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It was one of many dangerous government experiments on US citizens in violation of the Nuremberg Code.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/biological-agents-were-tested-on-the-new-york-city-subway-2015-11</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'One of the Largest Human Experiments in History' Was Conducted on Unsuspecting Residents of San Francisco</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 8, 2015</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[For 20 years, the military secretly tested biological agents on the American public.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/the-military-tested-bacterial-weapons-in-san-francisco-2015-7</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Heretical Impulse: Zamyatin and Orwell</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[I In a 1931 letter to Joseph Stalin, Russian novelist Yevgeny Zamyatin adopted a respectful tone by way of introduction: 'My name is probably known to you.' The author of We, the dystopian science fiction novel that influenced Aldous Huxley's Brave New World and George Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/01/the-heretical-impulse-zamyatin-and-orwell/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Race and Social Panic at Haverford: A Case Study in Educational Dysfunction</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['You have continued to stand as an individual that seems to turn a blind eye to the stuff that's going on, as a black woman that is in the [college] administration,' said the first-year Haverford College student. 'I came to this institution'—and here she pauses for a moment, apparently fighting back…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/12/01/race-and-social-panic-at-haverford-a-case-study-in-educational-dysfunction/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Elon Musk Says SpaceX Will Attempt Uncrewed Mars Flight in Two Years, Human Landing in Four to Six</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX founder and CEO Elon Musk was given an award from media giant Axel Springer on Tuesday, and he sat down to provide a wide-ranging interview that covered topics including space, Tesla, AI and even underpopulation. Musk addressed SpaceX's Mars ambitions first, providing current timelines…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/elon-musk-says-spacex-will-attempt-uncrewed-mars-flight-in-two-years-human-landing-in-four-to-six/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DeepMind's Superhuman Intelligence</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The solving of a 50-year scientific problem takes computers a step closer to 'true creativity']]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/12/how-deepmind-is-transforming-the-future/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aftermarket Truck Mods Pollute as Much as 9 Million Extra Pickups</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The EPA estimates 550,000 medium pickup trucks have disabled emissions controls.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/12/truck-emissions-mods-pollute-more-than-dieselgate-epa-says/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Tis the Season: Congress Looks to Sneak in Unconstitutional Copyright Reform Bill Into 'Must Pass' Spending Bill</title>
			<source>Techdirt</source>
			<pubDate>Dec 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you have to sneak your transformational copyright bill into a 'must pass' government spending bill, it seems fairly evident that you know the bill is bad. Earlier we talked about how the White House is trying to slip a Section 230 repeal...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20201201/10514145802/tis-season-congress-looks-to-sneak-unconstitutional-copyright-reform-bill-into-must-pass-spending-bill.shtml</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Public Defender Tales: Innocent, But Fined</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The state of Iowa collects millions of dollars in fines from people whose charges were dismissed. There's also a Catch-22: financially, you're better off guilty]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/public-defender-tales-innocent-but</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Appointee Neera Tanden Spread the Conspiracy That Russian Hackers Changed Hillary's 2016 Votes to Trump</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How can Democrats and allied media outlets credibly oppose unhinged conspiracy theories and attacks on U.S. election legitimacy while empowering its worst purveyors?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/biden-appointee-neera-tanden-spread</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New Study Sheds Light on Why Women Tend to Have Greater Animosity Towards Political Opponents</title>
			<source>PsyPost</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New research suggests there is a gender gap in affective polarization: Women in the United States tend to be more hostile than men towards their political ...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.psypost.org/2020/11/new-study-sheds-light-on-why-women-tend-to-have-greater-animosity-towards-political-opponents-58680</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Dangerous Logic of Anti-Racism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If racism is about prejudice and power, where does that leave high-achieving minorities?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/the-dangerous-logic-of-anti-racism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Assassination of a Top Iranian Nuclear Scientist, Briefly Explained</title>
			<source>Vox</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Iran has blamed Israel for the attack, and pledged retaliation.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vox.com/2020/11/28/21723778/assassination-iran-nuclear-scientist-mohsen-fakhrizadeh</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Guns, Drugs and Viral Content: Welcome to Cartel TikTok</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Mexico is set to shatter another murder record, but that grim reality is nowhere to be seen on the TikTok videos that go viral by showcasing drug cartel culture.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/28/world/americas/mexico-drugs-cartel-tiktok.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Politics in Academia: A Case Study</title>
			<source>Psychology Today</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This is the story of our effort to publish a paper that threatens academia.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/darwins-subterranean-world/202011/politics-in-academia-case-study</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Most Americans Object to Government Tracking of Their Activities Through Cellphones</title>
			<source>The Wall Street Journal</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new survey found widespread concern among Americans about government tracking of their whereabouts through their digital devices, with an overwhelming majority saying that a warrant should be required to obtain such data.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/most-americans-object-to-government-tracking-of-their-activities-through-cellphones-11606305601</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Long-Forgotten CIA Document From WikiLeaks Sheds Critical Light on Today's U.S. Politics and Wars</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Agency knew that their best asset for selling their wars was Barack Obama -- the same reason so many in the security state were eager to get rid of Donald Trump.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/a-long-forgotten-cia-document-from</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jordan Peterson v the Crybullies</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The reaction to the 12 Rules for Life sequel shows an infantile intolerance]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/jordan-peterson-v-the-crybullies/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>As Cities Curb Surveillance, Baltimore Police Took to the Air</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In a program that overcame three court challenges this year, planes with high-tech cameras circled the city up to 40 hours a week.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/cities-curb-surveillance-baltimore-police-took-air/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Microsoft's New 'Productivity Score' Gamifies Workplace Surveillance</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The company's newest feature is facing heavy criticism for allowing bosses to track how their employees use Microsoft's suite of tools, such as how frequently they send emails, collaborate in shared documents, or have their camera on during virtual meetings.]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/microsofts-creepy-new-productivity-score-gamifies-workp-1845763063</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Ethics of Rebooting the Dead</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The notion of resurrecting people as digital entities is becoming less hypothetical. But just because something can be done, doesn't always mean it should.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/ethics-reviving-dead-with-tech/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How the Criminal Justice System Fails People With Mental Illness</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['I found your baby,' Michelle Durden recalls the police officer saying after her son went missing. 'He's alive. And he's in jail.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/26/mental-illness-prison-jail-police/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contaminants in New Jersey Soil and Water Are Toxic, Documents Reveal</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Solvay had previously withheld information about the PFAS chemicals on the grounds that it was 'confidential business information.']]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/25/solvay-new-jersey-pfas-documents/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Illegal Tampering by Diesel Pickup Owners Is Worsening Pollution, E.P.A. Says</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An E.P.A. investigation has found that the owners of more than half a million diesel pickup trucks have installed devices to defeat emissions controls and boost pollution.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/25/climate/diesel-trucks-air-pollution.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interview With Edward Snowden on Silicon Valley Censorship, Biden, and Lurking Press Freedom Dangers</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How did we travel so far from the original vision of the internet as the one place humans could communicate and organize free of state and corporate control?]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/video-interview-with-edward-snowden</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Demanding Silicon Valley Suppress 'Hyper-Partisan Sites' in Favor of 'Mainstream News' (The NYT) Is a Fraud</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The corporate news organizations masquerading as reliable and non-partisan are, in fact, as hyper-partisan as any sites on the internet, and spread as much misinformation.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/demanding-silicon-valley-suppress</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Andre Damon</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Increased content moderation has been sold as a tool to control the far right, but the World Socialist Web Site was among the first to sound the alarm]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-andre-damon</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why I Had to Leave the Guardian</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[If you were bullied by 338 colleagues, what would you do?]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/11/why-i-had-to-leave-the-guardian/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How America Came Apart</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A people with no shared history will find it very hard to keep a lid on disorder and violence]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/09/can-america-hold-apart/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Cultural Appropriation' Is American Cultural Imperialism</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The US culture wars are intruding in places they don't belong]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2020/09/cultural-appropriation-is-american-cultural-imperialism/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Has Trans Activism Gone Too Far?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It's time we were allowed a properly nuanced discussion on gender issues]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/11/has-trans-activism-gone-too-far/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Will Maths Succumb to the Woke Wave?</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 4, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Students are being imprisoned in the lies of our age]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/10/will-maths-succumb-to-the-woke-wave/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antifa's Attack on the Truth</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Jul 5, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Hostile actors are conspiring to create false narratives]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/07/antifas-attack-on-the-truth/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Titania Is Perfect for Our Times</title>
			<source>UnHerd</source>
			<pubDate>Mar 8, 2019</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The avenging SJW angel, Titania McGrath, has disrupted a tired genre]]></description>
			<link>https://unherd.com/2019/03/why-titania-is-perfect-for-our-times/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Is Scientific Illiteracy So Acceptable?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the mid-1980s, when I taught a Physics for Poets class at Yale University, I was dumbstruck when I gave the students a quiz problem to estimate the total amount of water flushed in all the toilets in the US in one 24-hour period and I started to grade the quiz. In order to estimate this, you have…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/23/why-is-scientific-illiteracy-so-acceptable/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Retracting a Controversial Paper Won't Help Female Scientists</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Imagine yourself as a newly hired female assistant professor and the delight you feel when you learn that your article, examining over 222 million academic papers, has just been accepted at one of the top science journals. Now imagine your response when you discover that a fellow female academic is …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/23/retracting-a-controversial-paper-wont-help-female-scientists/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This Squishy 3D-Printed Human Heart Feels Like the Real Thing</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A clever technique allows scientists to scan a heart and reconstruct it in a soup of gelatin. It's like making jello, only way more useful for surgeons.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/3d-printed-human-heart-feels-like-the-real-thing/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Psilocybin &amp; Migraine: First of Its Kind Trial Reports Promising Results</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A first-of-its-kind exploratory study, led by researchers from Yale School of Medicine, has found a single dose of the psychedelic psilocybin can reduce migraine frequency by 50 percent for a least two weeks. The preliminary trial was small, with follow-up work necessary to validate the results,…]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/psilocybin-migraine-psychedelic-clinical-trial-promising-results/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Fragility of Modern Education in the Time of COVID-19</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Modern education is arguably the most massive feat of social engineering ever attempted by humanity and one of the most important, when effective. Academic competencies at the end of schooling can have life-long influences on employability, wages, and the ability to advance in one's career.1,2,3,4 T…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/22/the-fragility-of-modern-education-in-the-time-of-covid/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kin, Tribes, and the Dark Side of Identity</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA['We should poison their water holes!' This was the first thing my father said when I called him after planes hit the World Trade Center where I worked. My dad was a 1960s cultural liberal and pacifist, who had opposed every war our country had fought. The moment he felt that my life was in danger, h…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/22/kin-tribes-and-the-dark-side-of-identity/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Does Racism Explain Black Disadvantage?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A foundational tenet of the Black Lives Matter and similar racial justice movements is that gaps between blacks and whites on many socio-economic measures are produced primarily by racism. Racial inequalities in educational attainment, financial success, social status, crime, and health are thereby …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/15/does-racism-explain-black-disadvantage/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Joe Biden's Silence on Ending the Drone Wars</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 22, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[With scant comments about U.S. assassination programs, there are indications that Biden would keep the drone wars around.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/11/22/biden-drones-endless-wars/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What if Instead of Calling People Out, We Called Them In?</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Prof. Loretta J. Ross is combating cancel culture with a popular class at Smith College.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/19/style/loretta-ross-smith-college-cancel-culture.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police in Mississippi to Pilot a Program to Live-Stream Amazon Ring Cameras</title>
			<source>Mozilla Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The police surveillance center in Jackson, Mississippi, will be conducting a 45-day pilot program to live stream the security cameras, including Amazon Ring cameras, of participating residents.]]></description>
			<link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/blog/police-mississippi-pilot-program-live-stream-amazon-ring-cameras/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Robots Invade the Construction Site</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Boosted by advances in sensors and artificial intelligence, a new generation of machines is automating a tech-averse industry.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/robots-invade-construction-site/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This 2-Acre Vertical Farm Out-Produces 720 Acre 'Flat Farms'</title>
			<source>Forbes</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[95% less water. 99% less land. 400X more yield.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/20/this-2-acre-vertical-farm-out-produces-750-acre-flat-farms/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deep Frozen Arctic Microbes Are Waking Up</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thawing permafrost is releasing microorganisms, with consequences that are still largely unknown]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/deep-frozen-arctic-microbes-are-waking-up/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Extremely Aggressive' Internet Censorship Spreads in the World's Democracies</title>
			<source>University of Michigan News</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The largest collection of public internet censorship data ever compiled shows that even citizens of the world's freest countries are not safe from internet censorship. A University of Michigan team used Censored Planet, an automated censorship tracking...]]></description>
			<link>https://news.umich.edu/extremely-aggressive-internet-censorship-spreads-in-the-worlds-democracies/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Victimhood or Development?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On October 20th, Brown University professor of economics Glenn Loury and Columbia University professor of linguistics John McWhorter were joined on Loury's Bloggingheads podcast The Glenn Show by Shel]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/11/19/victimhood-or-development/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the Censored: Ford Fischer</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The videographer is this week's entrant in a growing club of the digitally deleted]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/meet-the-censored-ford-fischer</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's Time for America to Reckon With the Staggering Death Toll of the Post-9/11 Wars</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least half a million people have been killed in the post-9/11 wars in Afghanistan, Iraq, and Pakistan, a new study by Brown University researchers finds.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/11/19/civilian-casualties-us-war-on-terror/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The New Ruling Coalition: Opposition to Afghanistan Withdrawal Shows Its Key Factions</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An unholy union of the National Security State and the neocon-backed and corporate-funded Democratic Party are about to assume power: with media-supported internet censorship a key weapon.]]></description>
			<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/the-new-ruling-coalition-opposition</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pandemic Villains: Allianz Global Investors</title>
			<source>Substack</source>
			<pubDate>Nov 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[How one of the world's biggest finance companies misread Covid-19 and cost pensioners billions]]></description>
			<link>https://taibbi.substack.com/p/pandemic-villains-allianz-global</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
