<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss>
	<channel>
		<title>cata-list</title>
		<link>https://cata-list.github.io</link>
		<id>PPyrkUXEcUaA59ERSgU9s</id>
		<description>Useful lists of some of the best info, media, tools, and quotes for those who seek to understand and improve this world.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed Oct 14 2020 11:02:10 GMT-0700 (Pacific Daylight Time)</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<item>
			<title>What Would Happen if All the Antarctic Ice Melted?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[It … let's just say it would not be good. Here, let's do the math.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-happen-antarctic-ice-melted/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Great Barrier Reef Has Lost Half of Its Corals Since 1995</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Every type of coral has declined since 1995 because of climate change, an Australian study finds.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-australia-54533971</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Engineering a Battery Fast Enough to Make Recharging Like Refueling</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The structure of black phosphorus naturally makes channels to let lithium in.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/10/engineering-a-battery-fast-enough-to-make-recharging-like-refueling/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Real and Imminent' Extinction Risk to Whales</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A letter signed by hundreds of scientists calls for global action to protect whales, dolphins and porpoises.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-54485407</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>For Some Adjunct Professors, It's Speak Your Mind Versus Keep Your Job</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The issue of academic freedom is particularly tenuous for the growing number of college teachers who hold positions that are neither tenured nor on the tenure track. Various titles are used to desc…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/10/08/for-some-adjunct-professors-its-speak-your-mind-versus-keep-your-job/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Computers Aboard Airliners Vulnerable to Hacking, Watchdog Says</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Airliners carry a variety of computer systems that could become vulnerable to hackers and U.S. regulators haven't imposed adequate counter measures, a government watchdog report concluded.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-09/computers-aboard-airliners-vulnerable-to-hacking-watchdog-says</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'World's Fastest Electrodes' Triple the Density of Lithium Batteries</title>
			<source>New Atlas</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[French company Nawa technologies says it's already in production on a new electrode design that can radically boost the performance of existing and future battery chemistries, delivering up to 3x the energy density, 10x the power, vastly faster charging and battery lifespans up to five times as…]]></description>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/energy/nawa-vertically-aligned-carbon-nanotube-electrode/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Recycling Was a Lie — a Big Lie — to Sell More Plastic, Industry Experts Say</title>
			<source>CBC</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Less than 10 per cent of the plastics we've used have been recycled. A new documentary reveals why]]></description>
			<link>https://www.cbc.ca/documentaries/the-passionate-eye/recycling-was-a-lie-a-big-lie-to-sell-more-plastic-industry-experts-say-1.5735618</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Unprecedented and Illegal Campaign to Eliminate Julian Assange</title>
			<source>The Intercept</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Assange would never receive a fair trial in the U.S., but he's not receiving one in Britain either.]]></description>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2020/10/06/julian-assange-trial-extradition/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Orders From the Top: The EU's Timetable for Dismantling End-to-End Encryption</title>
			<source>Electronic Frontier Foundation</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The last few months have seen a steady stream of proposals, encouraged by the advocacy of the FBI and Department of Justice, to provide 'lawful access' to end-to-end encrypted services in the United States. Now lobbying has moved from the U.S., where Congress has been largely paralyzed by the...]]></description>
			<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/10/orders-top-eus-timetable-dismantling-end-end-encryption</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The IRS Is Being Investigated for Using Location Data Without a Warrant</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 6, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The IRS used smartphone location data from a contractor to try to track Americans without a warrant.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/qj479d/irs-investigation-location-data-no-warrant-venntel</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exxon's Plan for Surging Carbon Emissions Revealed in Leaked Documents</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Internal projections from one of world’s largest oil producers show an increase in its enormous contribution to global warming.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-05/exxon-carbon-emissions-and-climate-leaked-plans-reveal-rising-co2-output</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>State Sanctioned Secrecy: NSA's Criminality Shield</title>
			<source>The Hill</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Americans should not have to rely on whistleblowers to reveal our government is targeting us for unconstitutional surveillance behind a shield of secrecy. Nor should executive branch bureaucrats be able to conceal their misconduct behind false claims that exposing their ineptitude or criminality wou…]]></description>
			<link>https://thehill.com/blogs/congress-blog/politics/516064-state-sanctioned-secrecy-nsas-criminality-shield</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Humanity Destroyed Itself</title>
			<source>YouTube</source>
			<pubDate>Feb 5, 2017</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The real reason we may destroy ourselves isn't really to do with politics or economics or even warfare. It has to do with our minds.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yk3QsGzAjKI</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>California Fires Set Bleak Record as 4m Acres Destroyed</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Four million figure double the previous record for most land burned as officials warn that season is 'far from over and fire potential remains high']]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/oct/05/california-fires-4m-acres-wildfires-burn</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Greenland Melting Fastest Any Time in Last 12,000 Years</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Researchers determined that Greenland is on track to lose more ice this century than during any of the previous 120 centuries. Christopher Intagliata reports.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/greenland-melting-fastest-any-time-in-last-12-000-years/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Weaponizing Words: Language and Oppression</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An article in Tablet magazine last month by Paul Berman, 'Lynching and Liberalism,' paints the gloomy history of coercion from the Stalinist excesses of many radicals in the 1930s down to the blowback against the recent Harper's 'Letter on Justice and Open Debate.' In discussing the 'New Left' and '…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/10/02/weaponizing-words-language-and-oppression/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Russian State Hackers Appear to Have Breached a Federal Agency</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Evidence suggests Russia's state-backed Fancy Bear group was behind a hack targeting a US federal agency.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/russia-fancy-bear-reportedly-hacked-us-agency-213304085.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Misguided Campaign Against Journalistic Objectivity</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Locked down in a northern Ontario cottage over the summer, I found myself listening to CBC Radio's Sunday Edition, an eclectic three-hour weekly morning show hosted, until his recent retirement, by veteran journalist and broadcaster Michael Enright. On this particular Sunday in July, guest host Anth…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/10/01/the-misguided-campaign-against-journalistic-objectivity/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Likely Had the Virus During the Debate, According to Medical Experts</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A massive contact tracing effort is under way to determine when Trump and aides were contagious, raising startling questions about the debate.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-likely-had-the-virus-during-the-debate-medical-experts-2020-10</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New 'Forever Chemicals' Contaminating the Environment, Regulators Say</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Oct 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Efforts in the US to oversee one PFAS compound from chemical company Solvay illustrate the challenges officials face]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/oct/01/new-forever-chemicals-contaminating-environment-regulators-say</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The West's Infernos Are Melting Our Sense of How Fire Works</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[42,000-foot plumes of ash. 143-mph firenadoes. 1,500-degree heat. These wildfires are a new kind of hell on earth, and scientists are racing to learn its rules.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/west-coast-california-wildfire-infernos/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Psilocybin Can Save the Environment</title>
			<source>Nautilus</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Last week, biologist and writer Merlin Sheldrake introduced Nautilus readers to Paul Stamets, a mycologist who preaches that mushrooms...]]></description>
			<link>http://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/how-psilocybin-can-save-the-environment</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Radicalized Antiracism on Campus—as Seen From the Computer Lab</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The campus battle over what I've previously called the equity agenda has recently shifted almost completely from a focus on gender to a focus on race. This has been accompanied by a series of surreal spectacles at the University of Washington in Seattle, where I teach. In the aftermath of the George…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/29/radicalized-antiracism-on-campus-as-seen-from-the-computer-lab/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Intelligence Sources Discussed Poisoning Julian Assange, Court Told</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 30, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Extradition hearing told spying operation at Ecuador embassy included plot to take baby's nappy]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2020/sep/30/us-intelligence-sources-discussed-poisoning-julian-assange-court-told</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Compact Nuclear Fusion Reactor Is 'Very Likely to Work,' Studies Suggest</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A series of research papers renews hope that the long-elusive goal of mimicking the way the sun produces energy might be achievable.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/29/climate/nuclear-fusion-reactor.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>90 Percent of Coronavirus Patients Experience Side Effects After Recovery, Study Finds</title>
			<source>The Hill</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An online survey of 965 recovered COVID-19 patients found 9 in 10 reported experiencing symptoms such as fatigue, loss of taste and smell and psychological issues.]]></description>
			<link>https://thehill.com/changing-america/well-being/longevity/518751-90-percent-of-coronavirus-patients-experience-side</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists Find Evidence of Multiple Underground Lakes on Mars</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 29, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Scientists believe they've found more evidence confirming the presence of a large reservoir of liquid water under the surface of Mars first discovered back in 2018. In fact, they believe they've found three more subsurface saltwater lakes surrounding that main one — a huge discovery, seeing as thos…]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/scientists-underground-lakes-mars-092555621.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Inside the JPMorgan Trading Desk the U.S. Called a Crime Ring</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The U.S. says the precious metals desk at JPMorgan was a racketeering operation. Now the bank is poised to pay a record penalty for spoofing. Here's a look behind eight years of alleged conspiracy.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-28/inside-the-jpm-precious-metals-desk-called-a-crime-ring-by-prosecutors</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Election Threats That Keep US Intelligence Up at Night</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Government officials have increasingly sounded alarms on the risks of foreign interference and disinformation campaigns leading up to—and after—November 3.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/election-threats-fbi-cisa-disinformation-hack-leak/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The FDA Approved Prescription Opioids Without Critical Safety Data, Study Says</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 28, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The Food and Drug Administration has been lax in how it's approved prescription opioid treatments dating back to the late 1990s, according to a new study out Monday. The study found that the FDA has routinely approved new opioid drugs or new formulations of existing drugs on the basis of limited evi…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/the-fda-approved-prescription-opioids-without-critical-1845207485</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Metal Wires of Carbon Complete Toolbox for Carbon-Based Computers</title>
			<source>Berkeley News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Transistors based on carbon rather than silicon could potentially boost computers' speed and cut their power consumption more than a thousandfold — think of a mobile phone that holds its charge for…]]></description>
			<link>https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/09/24/metal-wires-of-carbon-complete-toolbox-for-carbon-based-computers/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JPMorgan Is Set to Pay $1 Billion in Record Spoofing Penalty</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase and Co. is poised to pay close to $1 billion to resolve market manipulation investigations by U.S. authorities into its trading of metals futures and Treasury securities, according to three people with knowledge of the matter.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-23/jpmorgan-is-set-to-pay-1-billion-in-record-spoofing-penalty</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists May Have Found a Material for Building on Mars</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 27, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Using simple chemistry, the organic polymer chitin can be transformed into a viable substance for creating tools and habitats on the Red Planet.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-may-have-found-a-material-for-building-on-mars/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Bias That Divides Us</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 26, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As we sit here over six months after the initial lockdown provoked by COVID-19, the United States has moved out of a brief period of national unity into distressingly predictable and bitter partisan division. The return to this state of affairs has been fuelled by a cognitive trait that divides us a…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/26/the-bias-that-divides-us/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deception and Complicity—the Strange Case of Jessica Krug</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[On September 9th, Jessica Krug, 38, abruptly resigned from her job as associate professor of African history at George Washington University (GWU). Apparently fearing imminent exposure, she had confessed in a post on Medium that she had passed herself off for more than a decade as being of black-Afr…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/25/deception-and-complicity-the-strange-case-of-jessica-krug/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia Says World Needs to Know Origins of COVID-19</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 25, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The world's nations must do all they can to understand the origins of COVID-19, Australia's Prime Minister Scott Morrison said on Saturday, comments that could worsen tensions with China.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-australia-china/australia-says-world-needs-to-know-origins-of-covid-19-idUSKCN26H00T</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Crows Possess Higher Intelligence Long Thought Primarily Human</title>
			<source>STAT</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A second study looked in unprecedented detail at the brains of pigeons and barn owls, finding hints to the basis of their intelligence.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.statnews.com/2020/09/24/crows-possess-higher-intelligence-long-thought-primarily-human/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Extremely Brilliant' X-Ray Beams Are About to Revolutionize How We See Into Matter</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A new way of producing powerful X-ray beams—the brightest on Earth—is now making it possible to create 3D images of matter at astounding resolutions. This 'Extremely Brilliant Source' officially opened last month at the European Synchrotron Radiation Facility in France, and scientists are already us…]]></description>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/extremely-brilliant-x-ray-beams-are-about-to-revoluti-1845055303</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Dangerous 'Forever Chemicals' Are Allowed in US Drinking Water</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The federal government has still not set limits for PFAS compounds, and some allege that could be because it is a polluter of them itself]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/sep/24/pfas-dangerous-forever-chemicals-drinking-water</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DHS Admits Facial Recognition Photos Were Hacked, Released on Dark Web</title>
			<source>Vice</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 24, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Traveler's faces, license plates, and care information were hacked from a subcontractor called Perceptics and released on the dark web.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/m7jzbb/dhs-admits-facial-recognition-photos-were-hacked-released-on-dark-web</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook's Former Director of Monetization Says Facebook Intentionally Made Its Product as Addictive as Cigarettes — And Now He Fears It Could Cause 'Civil War'</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 23, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Former director Tim Kendall said Facebook 'took a page from Big Tobacco's playbook, working to make our offering addictive at the outset.']]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/former-facebook-exec-addictive-as-cigarettes-tim-kendall-2020-9</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Typical Full-Time Salary in America Would Be $102,000 if Wages Had Kept Up With Growth — but the Economy Has Failed 90% of Workers</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A Rand report finds the median salary could have been $102,000, instead of $50,000, for a full-time worker if wages and GDP grew at the same rate.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/median-us-worker-salaries-could-have-been-102000-without-inequality-2020-9</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Secret Documents Show How Criminals Use Famous Banks to Finance Terror and Death</title>
			<source>BuzzFeed News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thousands of secret 'suspicious activity reports' offer a never-before-seen picture of corruption and complicity — and how the government lets it flourish.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jasonleopold/fincen-files-financial-scandal-criminal-networks</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Postal Service Files a Patent for Voting System Combining Mail and a Blockchain</title>
			<source>Forbes</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[USPTO (United States Patent and Trademark Office) published a patent application filed by the USPS. A reading of the patent itself. Opposition to technology in election systems, from election 'experts'. Why this year is different.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/vipinbharathan/2020/09/20/us-postal-service-files-a-patent-for--voting-system-combining-mail-and-a-blockchain/#7fedc0e73336</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Companies Can Track Your Phone's Movements to Target Ads</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 20, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A startup gathers data on when you pick up your phone or go out on a run.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/09/companies-can-track-your-phones-movements-to-target-ads/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What's Causing the Mass Bird Die-Off in the Southwest?</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thousands of migrating birds have died, perhaps starved by drier conditions related to climate change or by having to fly inland to avoid wildfire smoke.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/whats-causing-the-mass-bird-die-off-in-the-southwest/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Down the 1619 Project's Memory Hole</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The history of the American Revolution isn't the only thing the New York Times is revising through its 1619 Project. The 'paper of record' has also taken to quietly altering the published text of the project itself after one of its claims came under intense criticism. When the 1619 Project went to p…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/19/down-the-1619-projects-memory-hole/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What's in Wildfire Smoke, and How Dangerous Is It?</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Blazes on the West Coast are spewing a haze clear across the country.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/09/whats-in-wildfire-smoke-and-how-dangerous-is-it/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Then They Came for Beethoven</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[This week, Vox published an article titled 'How Beethoven's 5th Symphony put the classism in classical music.' 'Since its 1808 premiere, audiences have interpreted [its opening progression] as a metaphor for Beethoven's personal resilience in the face of his oncoming deafness,' write Nate Sloan and …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/19/then-they-came-for-beethoven/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How the Nonbinary Trend Hurts Those With Real Gender Dysphoria</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 19, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Within the conversation about transgender rights has emerged a debate about whether nonbinary people should be considered transgender. Over time, concerns about nonbinary rights have begun to dominate this discussion in online spaces and within the community. For those in support of nonbinary rights…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/19/how-the-nonbinary-trend-hurts-those-with-real-gender-dysphoria/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Dishonest and Misogynistic Hate Campaign Against J.K. Rowling</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 18, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When J. K. Rowling first outed herself as a gender-critical feminist, my first thought was: If Rowling can be cancelled, anyone can be cancelled. Not only is she one of the best known and best loved authors in the world (the writer of children's books, for goodness sake), she also has a personal his…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/18/the-dishonest-and-misogynistic-hate-campaign-against-j-k-rowling/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wealth of US Billionaires Rises by Nearly a Third During Pandemic</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Report includes Jeff Bezos, whose personal fortune has risen by 65% since 18 March]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/sep/17/wealth-of-us-billionaires-rises-by-nearly-a-third-during-pandemic</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook Accused of Watching Instagram Users Through Cameras</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Facebook Inc. is again being sued for allegedly spying on Instagram users, this time through the unauthorized use of their mobile phone cameras.The lawsuit springs from media reports in July that the photo-sharing app appeared to be accessing iPhone cameras even when they weren’t actively being used.Facebook denied the reports and blamed a bug, which it said it was correcting, for triggering what it described as false notifications that Instagram was accessing iPhone cameras.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-18/facebook-accused-of-watching-instagram-users-through-cameras</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gas Companies Are Abandoning Their Wells, Leaving Them to Leak Methane Forever</title>
			<source>Bloomberg</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Just one orphaned site in California could have emitted more than 30 tons of methane. There are millions more like it.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-09-17/abandoned-gas-wells-are-left-to-spew-methane-for-eternity</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Humans Wiped Out Two-Thirds of the World's Wildlife in 50 Years</title>
			<source>Smithsonian Magazine</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Threats to global biodiversity are also threats to humans, experts warn]]></description>
			<link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/humans-wiped-out-two-thirds-worlds-wildlife-50-years-180975824/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Black Lives Matter and the Mechanics of Conformity</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 17, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The death of George Floyd in May, circulated in a bystander's excruciating video clip, reignited furious and sometimes violent protests demanding reforms to address police brutality against ethnic minorities. According to the Center for Police Equity's 2016 report 'The Science of Justice,' black Ame…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/17/black-lives-matter-and-the-mechanics-of-conformity/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Birds 'Falling Out of the Sky' in Mass Die-Off in South-Western US</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Wildfires and climate crisis cited as possible causes for the deaths of thousands of migrating species heading south for the winter]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/16/birds-falling-out-of-the-sky-in-mass-die-off-in-south-western-us-aoe</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lessons of the Pinker Affair: The Problem With the Academy Is False Beliefs, Not Intolerance</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 16, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Earlier this summer, over 600 signatories signed an open letter to the Linguistic Society of America (LSA), denouncing Steven Pinker for 'speaking over genuine grievances and downplaying injustices, frequently by misrepresenting facts, and at the exact moments when Black and Brown people are mobiliz…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/16/lessons-of-the-pinker-affair-the-problem-with-the-academy-is-false-beliefs-not-intolerance/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'I Have Blood on My Hands': A Whistleblower Says Facebook Ignored Global Political Manipulation</title>
			<source>BuzzFeed News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 15, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A 6,600-word internal memo from a fired Facebook data scientist details how the social network knew about specific examples of global political manipulation — and failed to act.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/craigsilverman/facebook-ignore-political-manipulation-whistleblower-memo</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists Found Phosphine on Venus—a Possible Hint of Life</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 14, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A simple molecule floating in Venus's atmosphere is now humans' best bet for finding companionship in the galaxy.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/dr-phosphine-and-the-possibility-of-life-on-venus/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Arctic We Know Is Disappearing</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 14, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There have been some pretty freaky things happening in the Arctic this year, with historic levels of ice melt, absurdly high temperatures, and wildfires in an area that's meant to be the definition of cold. New research by scientists at the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) shows that …]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/the-arctic-we-know-is-disappearing-1845049072</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Antarctic Glaciers Are Growing Unstable Above and Below Water</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 14, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[New studies show fractures on surface ice and warm seawater melting the ice from underneath. That's a harbinger of a coming collapse—and sea level rise.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/antarctic-glaciers-are-growing-unstable-above-and-below-water/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Disposable Masks 'Causing Enormous Plastic Waste'</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The government is urged to do more to get people to wear reusable, washable face coverings.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-politics-54057799</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Health Officials Worldwide Are Receiving Death Threats Because of Their Work to Educate the Public and Stop the Spread of COVID-19</title>
			<source>Business Insider</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At least 24 local and state public health officials in the US have quit or retired since the beginning of the pandemic in January.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/health-officials-worldwide-receive-death-threats-for-covid-19-response-2020-9</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anti-Racist Structuralists and Non-Racist Culturalists</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 13, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[As the long hot summer of 2020 draws to a close, many Americans may feel as though they are living through an unraveling: an uncontrolled pandemic, collapsing faith in public institutions, apocalyptic rhetoric, violence and looting, and—if the rhetoricians of Black Lives Matter are to be believed—a …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/13/anti-racist-structuralists-and-non-racist-culturalists/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Online Voting Is Harder Than Online Banking</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A common argument for online voting doesn't actually make sense.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/09/why-online-voting-is-harder-than-online-banking/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Secret Recording Reveals Oil Executives' Private Views on Climate Change</title>
			<source>The New York Times</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 12, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[At a meeting last year, industry leaders contradicted public claims that emissions of climate-warming methane are under control]]></description>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/12/climate/methane-natural-gas-flaring.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Budget Deficit Tops $3 Trillion With One Month Left in Fiscal 2020</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The coronavirus pandemic has pushed the U.S. federal budget deficit above $3 trillion for the first 11 months of fiscal 2020, more than doubling the previous full-year record, the U.S. Treasury said on Friday.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-economy-budget/us-fiscal-year-budget-deficit-tops-3-trillion-idUSKBN2622OR</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>US Wildfires: At Least 20 Dead as California Governor Signs Bill Addressing Incarcerated Firefighters – as It Happened</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 11, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[California fires have burned 3.1m acres this year as Oregon blazes displace hundreds of thousands – follow the latest updates live]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2020/sep/11/fires-oregon-california-washington-wildfires-live-news-updates-today</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Big Oil Misled the Public Into Believing Plastic Would Be Recycled</title>
			<source>NPR</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An NPR and PBS Frontline investigation reveals how the oil and gas industry used the promise of recycling to sell more plastic, even when they knew it would never work on a large scale.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.npr.org/2020/09/11/897692090/how-big-oil-misled-the-public-into-believing-plastic-would-be-recycled</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>As Waters Warm, These Species Are Stuck Going the Wrong Way</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Earlier spring warmth puts young in stronger southward currents.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/09/some-ocean-species-are-moving-the-wrong-direction-as-waters-warm/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Russia, China and Iran Target US Elections With Cyberattacks</title>
			<source>Engadget</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Russia is once again trying to interfere with a US presidential election. So are China and Iran.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-warns-russia-china-iran-targeting-2020-election-191501661.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wildlife in 'Catastrophic Decline', Report Warns</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 10, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Conservation group WWF says global wildlife populations have shrunk by two-thirds since 1970.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-54091048</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Natural World Being Destroyed at Rate 'Never Seen Before', WWF Warns</title>
			<source>The Independent</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[We are working with conservation charity Space for Giants to protect wildlife at risk from poachers due to the conservation funding crisis caused by Covid-19. Help is desperately needed to support wildlife rangers, local communities and law enforcement personnel to prevent wildlife crime]]></description>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/climate-crisis-wwf-report-wildlife-biodiversity-david-attenborough-b420979.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Police Violence and the Rush to Judgment</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[In the days and weeks following George Floyd's death in May, activists flooded the streets with placards and slogans to denounce racism and police violence. But the zeal with which they mobilized support for their cause frequently clouded complex issues and events that demanded greater scrutiny than…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/08/police-violence-and-the-rush-to-judgment/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Former NSA Chief Keith Alexander Has Joined Amazon's Board of Directors</title>
			<source>The Verge</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A surveillance-friendly choice.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429635/amazon-keith-alexander-board-of-directors-nsa-cyber-command</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hydrogen, Carbon Capture Key to Net-Zero U.S. Electricity: Study</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[The United States can generate affordable electricity without producing carbon dioxide emissions by 2035 by deploying hydrogen or carbon capture technology, according to a report released on Wednesday by a climate policy think tank.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-climate-power/hydrogen-carbon-capture-key-to-net-zero-u-s-electricity-study-idUSKBN2602M0</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Illegal Devices That Bypass Vehicle Emissions Controls Spread Across US</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 9, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Thousands of tons of pollution spew into the air in the US from devices that proliferate online and in body shops]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/sep/09/auto-car-emissions-defeat-devices-delete-kits</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australian Scientists Say Logging, Mining and Climate Advice Is Being Suppressed</title>
			<source>The Guardian</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 8, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[A third of government and industry-employed ecologists and conservation scientists had work unduly modified, study finds]]></description>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/09/australian-scientists-say-logging-mining-and-climate-advice-is-being-suppressed</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The China Syndrome Part IV: Did China Fudge Its Data?</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 7, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Note: This is the concluding part of a four-part series of essays looking in detail at China's role in the COVID-19 pandemic. Part One looked at the circumstances surrounding the initial outbreak; Part Two looked at the discovery of human-to-human transmission and the immediate response; Part Three …]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/06/the-china-syndrome-part-iv-did-china-fudge-its-data/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'You're Not Allowed to Film': The Fight to Control Who Reports From Portland</title>
			<source>Reason</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 5, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Both sides are getting their information through purposely bottlenecked media reports, and the results are predictably distorted and dangerous.]]></description>
			<link>https://reason.com/2020/09/04/youre-not-allowed-to-film-the-fight-for-control-over-who-reports-from-portland/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unlimited Information Is Transforming Society</title>
			<source>Scientific American</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Technology is blurring the lines between consumers and producers, amateurs and professionals, and laypeople and experts. We're just starting to understand the implications]]></description>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/unlimited-information-is-transforming-society/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Portland's Grim Reality: 100 Days of Protests, Many Violent</title>
			<source>Associated Press</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) — Once hailed as one of the most livable U.S. cities, Portland, Oregon, is grappling with an uncertain future as it reaches a stunning benchmark: 100 consecutive nights of...]]></description>
			<link>https://apnews.com/b57315d97dd2146c4a89b4636faa7b70</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Neuralink Is Impressive Tech, Wrapped in Musk Hype</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Cool research tool? Definitely. A way to remotely control a computer or a prosthetic? Sure. But reading minds and storing memories? Not so fast.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/neuralink-is-impressive-tech-wrapped-in-musk-hype/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Drip Irrigation</title>
			<source>MIT GEAR Lab</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 4, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Our group is addressing this problem from multiple angles]]></description>
			<link>https://www.gear.mit.edu/drip-irrigation</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Human Embryo Gene Editing Gets a Road Map — Not a Green Light</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[After the 2018 'Crispr baby' scandal, a global commission assessed the technology and set strict criteria for moving it toward clinical trials.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/human-embryo-gene-editing-gets-a-road-map-not-a-green-light/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NSA Spying Exposed by Snowden Was Illegal and Not Very Useful, Court Says</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[NSA's illegal mass surveillance did not help thwart terror plot, court says.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/09/nsa-spying-exposed-by-snowden-was-illegal-and-not-very-useful-court-says/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>SpaceX Confirms Starlink Internet Private Beta Underway, Showing Low Latency and Speeds Over 100Mbps – TechCrunch</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has confirmed some details of its Starlink internet service beta test, via SpaceX engineer Kate Tice on today's launch webcast for its most recent Starlink satellite mission. Tice said that SpaceX's service has demonstrated latency low enough to allow it to play the 'fastes…]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/spacex-confirms-starlink-internet-private-beta-underway-showing-low-latency-and-speeds-over-100mbps/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Experts Are Overwhelmingly Skeptical of Online Voting</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[An online voting CEO tried—and failed—to convince me it was a good idea.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/09/why-experts-are-overwhelmingly-skeptical-of-online-voting/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Arctic Wildfires Have Never Released This Much Carbon Dioxide</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 3, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Sure, we're all aghast at the Siberian tundra exploding because it's too damn hot. But there's a much bigger catastrophe that's played out this summer in the overheated region. Arctic fires have unleashed an unprecedented amount of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/arctic-wildfires-have-never-released-this-much-carbon-d-1844940863</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Glacial Meltwater Lakes Have Grown by Half Since the 1990s</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Satellite images track remarkable growth with local consequences.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/09/glacial-meltwater-lakes-have-grown-by-half-since-the-1990s/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Your Beloved Blue Jeans Are Polluting the Ocean — Big Time</title>
			<source>Wired</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[When you wash denim, tiny fibers shed and flow into the environment. Scientists just found that Arctic waters are now loaded with little bits of jeans.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/your-blue-jeans-are-polluting-the-ocean/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Alexei Navalny: Russia Opposition Leader Poisoned With Novichok - Germany</title>
			<source>BBC News</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Germany says Alexei Navalny was attacked with a type of nerve agent used against an ex-spy in the UK.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-54002880</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Half of Americans Fear a Health-Related Bankruptcy</title>
			<source>Axios</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Health care costs were an issue even when the economy was good.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.axios.com/health-bankruptcy-fears-poll-ce3c4905-53c6-4f43-ba4f-fde22f4ef849.html</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Court: Mass Surveillance Program Exposed by Snowden Was Illegal</title>
			<source>Reuters</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Seven years after former National Security Agency contractor Edward Snowden blew the whistle on the mass surveillance of Americans' telephone records, an appeals court has found the program was unlawful - and that the U.S. intelligence leaders who publicly defended it were not telling the truth.]]></description>
			<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-nsa-spying/u-s-court-mass-surveillance-program-exposed-by-snowden-was-illegal-idUSKBN25T3CK</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CBP Does Not Make It Clear Americans Can Opt Out of Airport Face Scanning, Watchdog Says – TechCrunch</title>
			<source>TechCrunch</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Airport notices did not adequately inform Americans of their rights to opt-out of face scanning.]]></description>
			<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/customs-border-protection-airport-border-face-data/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Asphalt Could Be Making Summer Air Pollution Worse</title>
			<source>Gizmodo</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 2, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[There's a lot of asphalt in the U.S.—approximately 18 billion tons, according to the National Asphalt Pavement Association. Unfortunately, it turns out all that asphalt is the source of harmful air pollution, especially in the summer heat.]]></description>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/asphalt-could-be-making-summer-air-pollution-worse-1844930148</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Shortsighted' and 'Self-Defeating': US Rejects Global COVID-19 Vaccine Effort</title>
			<source>Ars Technica</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Over 170 countries are involved in the plan, which is like a vaccine insurance plan.]]></description>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/09/trump-admin-shuns-global-covid-19-vaccine-program-citing-beef-with-who/</link>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The China Syndrome Part III: Wet Markets and BioLabs</title>
			<source>Quillette</source>
			<pubDate>Sep 1, 2020</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[Note: This is the third part of a four-part series of essays looking in detail at China's role in the COVID-19 pandemic. Part One looked at the circumstances surrounding the initial outbreak; Part Two looked at the discovery of human-to-human transmission and the immediate response; this part invest…]]></description>
			<link>https://quillette.com/2020/09/02/the-china-syndrome-part-iii-wet-markets-and-biolabs/</link>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
